<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06183747B2.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as second publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06183747</doc-number>
        <kind>B2</kind>
        <date>20010206</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6183747</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B2</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference family-id="23376299" extended-family-id="1232154">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>09350342</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19990714</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>1999US-09350342</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>1278221</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>35034299</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19990714</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>1999US-09350342</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010206</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>A01N  65/00        20060101A I20051110RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>A</section>
        <class>01</class>
        <subclass>N</subclass>
        <main-group>65</main-group>
        <subgroup>00</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051110</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="2">
        <text>A61K  36/42        20060101A I20080531RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>A</section>
        <class>61</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>36</main-group>
        <subgroup>42</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20080531</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>424758000</text>
        <class>424</class>
        <subclass>758000</subclass>
      </main-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="1">
        <text>514859000</text>
        <class>514</class>
        <subclass>859000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>A61K-036/42</classification-symbol>
        <section>A</section>
        <class>61</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>36</main-group>
        <subgroup>42</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130823</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
      <patent-classification sequence="2">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>A61K-009/0014</classification-symbol>
        <section>A</section>
        <class>61</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>9</main-group>
        <subgroup>0014</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130823</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
      <patent-classification sequence="3">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>Y10S-514/859</classification-symbol>
        <section>Y</section>
        <class>10</class>
        <subclass>S</subclass>
        <main-group>514</main-group>
        <subgroup>859</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>A</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130518</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>0</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>0</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6183747</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Use of plant Momordica charactia extracts for treatment of acne acid</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="1">
          <text>WUNDERLICH JENS-CHRISTIAN, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5578307</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5578307</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="2">
          <text>NAKANO MASATOSHI</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5929047</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5929047</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="3">
          <text>HOSPITAL OF TCM ANREN COUNTY</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>CN</country>
            <doc-number>1205202</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>CN1205202</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="4">
          <text>FUJISAWA PHARMACEUTICAL CO</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>JP</country>
            <doc-number>H0640882</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>JP06040882</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="5">
          <text>MITSUI NORIN KK, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>WO</country>
            <doc-number>9704791</doc-number>
            <kind>A1</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>WO9704791</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <nplcit num="1">
          <text>Singh et al. Toxicol. Lett. Vo. 94 (1), pp. 37-46, Jan. 1998.</text>
        </nplcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>REN KAIJUN</name>
          </addressbook>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Ren, Kaijun</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Sugar Land, TX, 77478, US</address-1>
              <city>Sugar Land</city>
              <state>TX</state>
              <postcode>77478</postcode>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
      <agents>
        <agent sequence="1" rep-type="agent">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>Thomason, Moser &amp; Patterson, L.L.P.</orgname>
          </addressbook>
        </agent>
      </agents>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>Tate, Christopher</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>LAPSED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      Novel herbal extracts provide potent efficacy in the treatment of acne and furuncle.
      <br/>
      The formulated extracts of Momordica charantia L. are from either the whole plant or parts of the plant.
      <br/>
      The extracts have been formulated into aqueous solution, pads, and/or lotion.
      <br/>
      These formulations have been provided to treat acne and furuncle 2 to 3 times a day.
      <br/>
      It has demonstrated the ability to manage various grades of acne, from mild, moderate to severe, which include comedos, papules, pustules and nodules.
      <br/>
      Significant improvement is visible within five days.
      <br/>
      There are no observed either long-term or short-term side reactions.
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <heading>BACKGROUND--FIELD OF INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="1">This invention relates to the use of the extract from the whole plant or a part of the plant, Momordica charantia L., as a novel potent agent for the treatments of acne and furuncle.</p>
    <heading>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="2">
      Acne vulgaris, also called acne, pimple, or break out, is the most common disease of the pilosebaceous unit of the skin.
      <br/>
      It generally appears in the second decade of life.
      <br/>
      It effects nearly 80 percent of persons at some time between the ages of 11 and 30 years.
      <br/>
      Estimation of 30 percent of teenagers has acne of sufficient severity to required medical treatment.
      <br/>
      Acne is most commonly distributed on the face and lesser degree on the back and chest.
      <br/>
      It can persist for years and result in disfigurement and permanent scarring of the skin. 20% of adults are plagued with low-grade persistent acne.
      <br/>
      There is a huge market demand in the search for a potent anti-acne agent.
      <br/>
      In the last couple of decades in research, there is still a deficit in the potent efficacy and low toxicity of medicines to treat acne.
    </p>
    <p num="3">
      Acne is the result of the hypercornification of sebaceous follicles that are found over most of the body surface, but are largest and most numerous on the face, chest, and upper back.
      <br/>
      In normal conditions, the cornified layer of the follicle remains thin.
      <br/>
      When the persistent cohesion between cells retards desquamation, it causes the thickening of the ductal epithelium to narrow the ductal lumen.
      <br/>
      The process of ductal hypercornification causes the formation of a micromedo that may evolve into either a comedo or an inflammatory lesion.
    </p>
    <p num="4">
      Androgen is one of most important factors to cause an increased production of sebum.
      <br/>
      From the age of pubertal period and up, the adrenal glands mature and secrete an increased amount of androgen to increase the activity of sebaceous glands and produce more sebum.
      <br/>
      Males produce 10 times as much androgen as females, so it is not surprising that more males develop severe cases of acne
    </p>
    <p num="5">A resident anaerobic organism, Propionibacterium acnes, proliferates in the environment created by the mixture of the excessive sebum and follicular cells and produces chemotatic factors and inflammatory mediators that may lead to inflammation.</p>
    <p num="6">Acne may also be exacerbated by several chemicals (drugs), such as iodides, bromides, glucocorticoids, and lithium, as well as the application of oil-containing compounds.</p>
    <p num="7">
      In occupational cases, acne prone workers placed in environments in which there is contact with oils frequently have poral occlusion problems.
      <br/>
      Hot humid environments may also cause sufficient hydration and swelling of the skin to predispose to acne.
    </p>
    <p num="8">
      Furuncle is also a very common skin disease.
      <br/>
      It is the focal suppurative inflammation of hair follicles.
      <br/>
      Furuncle may occur in the hair follicles anywhere on the body, but they are most common on the face, neck, back, armpit, buttocks, and thighs.
      <br/>
      Almost everyone has had some experience with furuncles.
      <br/>
      The painful swelling of the skin is caused by a deep bacterial infection of the skin.
      <br/>
      It can occur singly or in multiples.
      <br/>
      Furuncle can be very painful if it occurs in the areas like ear canal or nose.
      <br/>
      Furuncles should be treated by a health care provider if it occurs by the nose.
      <br/>
      The condition that furuncles develop as they close and/or expand and join together is called carbunculosis.
    </p>
    <p num="9">
      With a couple dozen of acne medications out on the market, it is difficult for consumers to find a good product that really works for them because there are only a few that can actually treat acne.
      <br/>
      Most products contain basically the same ingredients: retinoide and its derivatives, benzyl peroxide, salicylic acid, sulfur, antibiotics, etc.
      <br/>
      Most are only effective for a short period of time and possesses many side reactions.
    </p>
    <p num="10">
      Most of the over counter medications contain salicylic acid, sulfur, benzyl peroxide, amino acids, etc.
      <br/>
      Most can only treat a minor aspect of acne.
      <br/>
      These topical creams, lotions, ointments and cleansers can only attack the end results of acne, but not the causes.
      <br/>
      They can not prevent future outbreaks.
    </p>
    <p num="11">
      The prescribed topical cream and other formulations, like retin-A and its derivatives and antibiotics (benzamycin), may be able to treat a part of the acne problem, but the side reactions which they cause to make the benefits behind the problems.
      <br/>
      They strip off layers of skin, dry and irritate skin, and make skin more susceptibility to sun burns.
    </p>
    <p num="12">
      The other current treatment is systemic treatment, such as antibiotics.
      <br/>
      It is about two thirds acne reacting under these treatments.
      <br/>
      This is a long term treatment.
      <br/>
      Other than their many side reactions, antibiotics also destroy the balance of the body bacterial system, which will create additional problems.
    </p>
    <p num="13">
      Currently, the common treatment of furuncle includes warm, wet compresses of the furuncle several times a day.
      <br/>
      Antibiotic soaps, topical antibiotics (applied to a localized area of the skin) are of little benefit once the furuncle has formed.
      <br/>
      Systemic antibiotics may also help to control the infection.
    </p>
    <p num="14">
      Based on the factor of the acne medication market, side reactions are the most common problems encountered with the current acne medications.
      <br/>
      Some medications possess potent treatment, but the patients have to stop using the drug due to the adverse effects that made their skin worse than before.
    </p>
    <heading>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="15">
      The basic pathology of acne includes two majority factors, inflammation (bacterial) and hypercornification of sebaceous follicles.
      <br/>
      A good therapeutic should at least have the ability to solve these two questions.
      <br/>
      The conventional methods of the acne treatment, which may be classified into clinical, cosmetic and self treatment, these have not provided total acne control, and low side reaction, and could be a painful process.
      <br/>
      Therefore, an objective of providing a relatively safe and effective medicine is still in command.
    </p>
    <p num="16">
      The present invention relates a novel potent therapeutics for acne and furuncle.
      <br/>
      In the present invention, the composition has demonstrated to manage the different grade of acne, from mild, moderate to severe.
      <br/>
      It includes the treatment of the symptoms of severe acne, like comedo, papules, pustules and nodules.
      <br/>
      It does not show any kind of side reactions.
    </p>
    <p num="17">
      Many herbs have a long history of being used in the treatment of bacteria, virus and fungus.
      <br/>
      The fruit, bitter melon, of the plant, Momordica charantia L., has been used as a diet for a long period of time in different countries.
      <br/>
      It has also been used as an antibiotic, antioxidant, antidiabetic, and hypotensive and so on.
      <br/>
      In the present invention, the extracts of fruit, leaf, vine, and root have been investigated by HPLC and UV.
      <br/>
      They contain similar integrations.
      <br/>
      The extract of the leaf indicates more components than others and has shown more potent efficacy in the control of acne and furuncle.
    </p>
    <p num="18">
      The practice use of the extraction is formulated with the addition of organic and inorganic acids, such as  ALPHA -hydroxy acid, fumaric acid, HCI and so on, to make the pH of the solution from 4-5.
      <br/>
      This process may add some benefits to the treatment:
    </p>
    <p num="19">
      1.
      <br/>
      Precipitate tannic acid and other components that may block the pilosebaceous layer of the skin.
    </p>
    <p num="20">2. Lower pH levels may soften the pilosebaceous tube to increase the elimination of sebum and keratinous debris.</p>
    <p num="21">3. Lighter color of the extract.</p>
    <p num="22">4. A lower pH environment is to prevent growth of bacteria The preparations of the extract have been in different formulations: water solution, pads and lotion.</p>
    <p num="23">Therefore, the present invention is related to the novel discovery of acne and furuncle treatment which is characterized by using extracts of Momordica charantia L., the extraction procedure, and the formulations.</p>
    <p num="24">One of the objectives of the present invention is to provide new uses of the herbal medicine that can treat acne and furuncle.</p>
    <p num="25">Another objection of the present is to provide a process for preparing the herbal medicine to treat acne and furuncle.</p>
    <p num="26">Another objection of the present invention is to provide the formulations to be better and convenient to treatment of acne and furuncle.</p>
    <p num="27">Further and other objections of the present invention maybe illustrated from the following description of the present invention in detail.</p>
    <heading>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="28">
      According to the present invention, a process of preparing herbal medicine comprises of treating with fresh material, dried raw material, different parts of the plant, and the different formulations.
      <br/>
      The typical processes are listed in the following pages.
    </p>
    <p num="29">
      200 g fresh plant was collected and washed.
      <br/>
      The washed plant was left so the surface water could dry.
      <br/>
      It was then grounded to almost pulp-like texture and squeezed (pressed) through a gauze to obtain as much liquid as possible.
      <br/>
      All of the liquid was collected and then centrifuged at high speed, which was not less than 3500 rpm.
      <br/>
      The upper clean liquid was collected.
      <br/>
      The solution was about 120 ml and the its pH was between 6 to 6.5.
    </p>
    <p num="30">
      The formulation of the extracts were performed with organic and inorganic acids.
      <br/>
      The typical sample used was glycolic acid.
      <br/>
      The acid was dissolved in water and the pH was adjusted to about pH 3.8 with saturated sodium hydroxide solution.
      <br/>
      The final concentration of glycolic acid was 50%.
      <br/>
      Under room temperature and stirring, the glycolic acid solution was dropwisely added to the centrifuged clean solution until the final concentration of glycolic acid in the extract was 5% or the pH of the extraction was above 4.
      <br/>
      There was a lot of precipitate and the formulated solution was allowed to stand overnight.
      <br/>
      The formulated solution was centrifuged to remove the precipitate.
      <br/>
      The concentration of the solution can be increased by lyophilization or evaporation under vacuum.
    </p>
    <p num="31">Dried raw materials are easier storage and solves the seasonal problem of obtaining natural products. 100 g of the fresh plant was dried naturally to form 15.3 g dry powder of the plant. 100 g of fresh root resulted in 12.1 g of dry root.</p>
    <p num="32">
      In a 450 ml beaker, 160 ml of water were added to 20 g of the dry powder raw material.
      <br/>
      The mixture was boiled for 20 min.
      <br/>
      The solution was filtrated and the residue was squeezed to near dry while the mixture still is warm.
      <br/>
      Combination of the solutions was about 110 ml.
      <br/>
      If the volume is greater than 110 ml, evaporates parts of the water to reach that volume.
      <br/>
      This volume is similar to that of the fresh material.
      <br/>
      The pH of the solution was around 8.
      <br/>
      The HPLC and UV results were almost identical between the fresh and dry materials.
      <br/>
      The HPLC conditions are as follows:
    </p>
    <p num="33">
      Column: C18, 300  Angstrom , 5 MU , 4.6 mm * 2500 mm
      <br/>
      Solvent A: 100% water
      <br/>
      Solvent B: 5% water in acetonitrile
      <br/>
      Gradient: 0-30% of B in 30 min.
    </p>
    <p num="34">Flow rate: 1 ml per min.</p>
    <p num="35">Detector: UV 214 nm</p>
    <p num="36">
      The formulated extract from the dried plant was the same procedure as in the fresh material.
      <br/>
      The amount of acidity did not have a significant difference.
      <br/>
      The HPLC and UV demonstrated the similarity in both.
    </p>
    <p num="37">
      The extracts have a natural herb smell.
      <br/>
      It is uncomfortable for some people.
      <br/>
      To remove the smell, added 3 g of active carbon to 100 ml of the formulated solution and stirred at room temperature for 5 min.
      <br/>
      The active carbon was filtrated to obtain a clean solution.
      <br/>
      This solution did not have the strong smell but a slightly comfortable, sweet smell.
      <br/>
      The UV spectra shown that the absorbency after 460 nm had disappeared.
      <br/>
      If the de-smell time had lasted to 1 hour, the solution had de-colored and had turned to a light yellow tone.
      <br/>
      The UV spectra shown that the absorbency after 340 nm has disappeared.
    </p>
    <p num="38">
      In the present invention, the best part or the whole plant is necessary to serve the treatments that had been investigated.
      <br/>
      Each part of the plant, leaf, melon, root, and vine, had been studied by HPLC and UV spectra.
      <br/>
      All of them were fresh part of the plant and were grounded.
      <br/>
      The liquid was squeezed out from the grounded material through gauze.
      <br/>
      The liquids were centrifuged and the upper solutions have been served as the samples for HPLC and UV spectra.
      <br/>
      In the results of HPLC, leaf, root and melon most likely contained the same components.
      <br/>
      Based on the strength of absorbency, the vine extraction contained less quantity of the components than that of the before mentioned three.
      <br/>
      In the results of UV spectra, the melon had no strong absorbency after 340 nm.
      <br/>
      The root had no strong absorbency after 380 nm.
      <br/>
      The vine had no strong absorbency after 426 nm.
      <br/>
      The leaf had the highest absorbency in the group.
      <br/>
      It had no strong absorbency after 470 nm.
      <br/>
      Therefore, all of the plant could be used as raw material for the treatment of acne and furuncle.
      <br/>
      The order of the best part for the treatments is: leaf, root, melon, and vine.
    </p>
    <p num="39">
      In the present invention, the different formulations have also been described.
      <br/>
      The acidified solution could be directly used for acne and furuncle treatment.
      <br/>
      The concentration can be increased for different level of the diseases.
      <br/>
      Generally speaking, the more severe form of acne and furuncle, the higher the concentration used.
      <br/>
      The normal concentration levels range from 1 to 2 times the original concentration.
    </p>
    <p num="40">
      For convenience, pads had been made by addition of the solution to the 21/8 inch cotton pads.
      <br/>
      This formulation was much more convenient for people to use, specifically for young adults.
      <br/>
      To confirm that the pads release a solution which containing same quality and quantity of material in the original aqueous solution, the solution in the pads were to be squeezed out and compared with original aqueous solution by HPLC and UV spectra.
      <br/>
      Both results indicated that the both solutions contained exactly same components in both quality and quantity.
    </p>
    <p num="41">
      In the present invention, the other formulation of the extract was lotion preparation.
      <br/>
      The formulated extract could be added to normal skin care cream or lotion.
      <br/>
      To maintain the same concentration of the solution in the lotion, the extract needed to be concentrated.
      <br/>
      It can be performed under normal boiling evaporation procedure.
      <br/>
      To avoid possible over heating, which may destroy some components, the best procedures are either lyophilization or evaporation under vacuum.
      <br/>
      The final volume of the solution depends on the concentration of the lotion.
      <br/>
      The final solution should be a clean solution with no precipitate.
      <br/>
      This is important in making homogenous lotion and achieving the expected treatment.
    </p>
    <p num="42">The Treatment and Results</p>
    <p num="43">
      For a normal acne and furuncle case (mild or moderate level), it may be used twice a day, morning and evening.
      <br/>
      A thin layer is applied on the problem areas after the face is washed and dried.
      <br/>
      For more severe cases, one may increase the application times.
      <br/>
      Significant improvement will result in 3-5 days after the treatment.
      <br/>
      Some results are summarized in the following tables.
    </p>
    <p num="44">
      -- TABLE 1
      <br/>
      -- The Treatment of Acne
      <br/>
      --                                                               Comparison
      <br/>
      -- Number    Age     History Number in Each Level        Efficacy with Others
      <br/>
      -- Involved  (Year)  (Year)  Comedo  Papulopustule Nudule  (%)     Medications
      <br/>
      -- 6         17-36   4-20    6       6             1       100     Best
    </p>
    <p num="45">
      -- TABLE 2
      <br/>
      -- The Treatment of Furuncle
      <br/>
      -- Number    Age     History Treatment Size of
      <br/>
      -- Involved  (year)  (day)   (day)     Furuncle (cm) Results
      <br/>
      -- 5         16-47   2-100   &lt;3     0.5-1.5       Disappear
    </p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>What is claimed is:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1.</claim-text>
      <claim-text>A process for treating skin having acne or furuncle comprising applying a composition containing an effective amount of an acidfied pressed liquid or water extract of Momordica charactia L. over an area of skin having acne or furuncle.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="2">
      <claim-text>2. The process of claim 1, wherein the pH of the external is from 4-5.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="3">
      <claim-text>3. The process of claim 1, wherein the extract is obtained from one or more parts of the Momordica charactia L. plant.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="4">
      <claim-text>4. The process of claim 1, wherein the composition is formulated in a form selected from an aqueous solution, pads containing the aqueous solution, a cream, and a lotion.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="5">
      <claim-text>5. The process of claim 1 wherein the composition is reapplied over the area of skin periodically.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="6">
      <claim-text>6. The process of claim 1 further comprising washing the area of skin before applying the composition.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>