<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06181206B2.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as second publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06181206</doc-number>
        <kind>B2</kind>
        <date>20010130</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6181206</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B2</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference is-representative="YES" family-id="11423476" extended-family-id="18682189">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>09338400</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19990622</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>1999US-09338400</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>19192764</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>IT</country>
        <doc-number>VA980013</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19980623</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>1998IT-VA00013</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010130</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>H03G   1/00        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>H</section>
        <class>03</class>
        <subclass>G</subclass>
        <main-group>1</main-group>
        <subgroup>00</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>330278000</text>
        <class>330</class>
        <subclass>278000</subclass>
      </main-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="1">
        <text>330288000</text>
        <class>330</class>
        <subclass>288000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <classifications-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="1">
        <text>H03G-001/00B8</text>
        <section>H</section>
        <class>03</class>
        <subclass>G</subclass>
        <main-group>001</main-group>
        <subgroup>00B8</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
    </classifications-ecla>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>H03G-001/0088</classification-symbol>
        <section>H</section>
        <class>03</class>
        <subclass>G</subclass>
        <main-group>1</main-group>
        <subgroup>0088</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>29</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6181206</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Low noise RF amplifier with programmable gain</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="1">
          <text>DEBROUX JEAN-FRANCOIS</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5530404</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5530404</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="2">
          <text>PERKINS GEOFFREY W</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5767662</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5767662</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="3">
          <text>HU XIAOYUN, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5977828</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5977828</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant data-format="original" app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>STMicroelectronics S.r.l.</orgname>
            <address>
              <address-1>Agrate Brianza, IT</address-1>
              <city>Agrate Brianza</city>
              <country>IT</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>IT</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
        <applicant data-format="questel" app-type="applicant" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>STMICROELECTRONICS</orgname>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>IT</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Palmisano, Giuseppe</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Catania, IT</address-1>
              <city>Catania</city>
              <country>IT</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>IT</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Pennisi, Salvatore</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Giarre, IT</address-1>
              <city>Giarre</city>
              <country>IT</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>IT</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
      <agents>
        <agent sequence="1" rep-type="agent">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Galanthay, Theodore E.</name>
          </addressbook>
        </agent>
        <agent sequence="2" rep-type="agent">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>Allen, Dyer, Doppelt, Milbrath &amp; Gilchrist, P.A.</orgname>
          </addressbook>
        </agent>
      </agents>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>Mottola, Steven J.</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>GRANTED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      By selecting a particular configuration of an input stage of a low noise RF amplifier, an optimal combination of linearity and input matching is achieved upon selecting a certain gain factor from a set of fixed step values.
      <br/>
      Each input stage configuration defines an input matching network specifically suitable to operate at a certain RF frequency.
      <br/>
      An RF signal input inductor is selectively associated to an input coupling capacitor, and a second degeneration inductor of a gain transistor of the input stage having a different gain value.
      <br/>
      The selection of a certain configuration is made through at least one switch through which a bias current generator is switched to the programmably selected input stage.
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <heading>FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="1">The present invention relates to the field of electronics, and, more particularly to an amplifier.</p>
    <heading>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="2">
      Low noise amplifiers (LNA) for multi-standard RF applications must operate in different frequency ranges, particularly with input signal dynamics that may be 90 dB or more.
      <br/>
      To avoid a rather costly approach of using several distinct amplifiers, with each amplifier having a selection switch external to the chip, it is necessary to overcome a number of problems deriving from the different operating frequencies, as well as from the extremely variable input signal dynamics.
    </p>
    <p num="3">
      To ensure an acceptable voltage standing wave ratio (VSWR), an amplifier requires a specific input matching adapting network.
      <br/>
      Such a network may normally be designed for a relatively narrow band, and optimized for a certain operating frequency.
      <br/>
      Different requirements apply to output matching because there are not relevant noise contributions that may originate from the output matching network.
      <br/>
      The matching is often achieved using resistive elements, and thereby with broadband characteristics.
    </p>
    <p num="4">
      Beside the above mentioned problem, the different gain and linearity specifications of each application dictate different design approaches for each amplifier.
      <br/>
      This often makes it impossible to not only share the same matching network, but even use the same active circuit.
    </p>
    <p num="5">
      When the gain and linearity requirements are linked to broad input dynamics, a typical approach is to make a variable gain amplifier.
      <br/>
      Though gain variation may address, to some extent, the linearity problems relative to the output section by attenuating the output signals, it does not resolve the linearity problems of the input section.
      <br/>
      The linearity problems of the input section are inherent to the nonlinear voltage-current characteristic of metal oxide semiconductor (MOS) transistors, as well as bipolar junction transistors (BJT).
    </p>
    <p num="6">
      Because the low-noise specification requirements must be met, a gain that is programmable in discrete steps, e.g., two or three steps, is usually preferred.
      <br/>
      Continuously programming over a broader dynamic range is usually applied to a variable gain amplifier (VGA) downstream of the mixer stage.
      <br/>
      An LNA circuit normally used to ensure the input matching and programmability of the gain is illustrated by the diagram of FIG. 1.
    </p>
    <p num="7">
      The current generator IPTAT and the current mirror Q1 -Q2 establish the operating current in Q2 to ensure stability in the gain when the temperature changes.
      <br/>
      A portion of the current signal, generated by Q2, reaches the resistive load RL via Q3.
      <br/>
      The portion of the current that flows in Q4 is dispersed in the supply rail.
      <br/>
      Resistors RA and RB have the function of reducing the noise contribution originating from the bias network, and permits a simpler application of the signal through the coupling capacitor C.
    </p>
    <p num="8">
      The current signal on the load resistor depends on the voltage on the control terminal VC.
      <br/>
      If VC is much lower than VB (VB &gt;VC +4VT), all the signal current of Q2 goes to Q3 and is converted to a voltage on the resistor RL producing the maximum gain.
      <br/>
      In the opposite case, if the VC voltage is greater than VB (VC &gt;VB +4VT), the entire current flows in Q4 and the gain is zero.
      <br/>
      By properly setting VC it is possible to obtain any gain value.
    </p>
    <p num="9">
      As mentioned above, to reduce the noise figure, the gain cannot be lowered below a minimum value.
      <br/>
      This requires an accurate control of the VC voltage.
      <br/>
      The practical aspect of a sufficiently accurate control is not easy because of the exponential voltage-current relation in the Q3 -Q4 pair.
    </p>
    <p num="10">
      The inductors LE and LB in the circuit of FIG. 1 perform the impedance matching for the real part and the imaginary part of the input impedance, Zin, respectively.
      <br/>
      By hypothesizing that  (Equation image '1' not included in text)
    </p>
    <p num="11">
      the condition for the matching of the input impedance, Zin (jw)=Rs, implies the selection of LE and LB values that satisfy the following equations:
      <br/>
      OMEGA T * LE +rb (congruent to) Rs  (1)
      <br/>
      OMEGA 2 * (LB +LE)C PI  (congruent to) 1  (2)
    </p>
    <p num="12">
      The linearity of the voltage-to-current transformation through Q2 is improved by the presence of LE, which causes an emitter degeneration.
      <br/>
      Therefore, to improve the linearity in the presence of an ample input signal, LE is incremented.
      <br/>
      However, this is a detriment for matching of the real part of Zin.
      <br/>
      An imperfect input impedance match for linearity is acceptable for signals having a sufficient magnitude.
    </p>
    <heading>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="13">An object of the present invention is to provide a low noise amplifier (LNA) for RF applications having a programmable selection of the operating frequency while ensuring an optimal combination of linearity and input matching characteristics, and having a selectable gain in a step mode for each selected configuration.</p>
    <p num="14">
      According to the present invention, the programmable LNA includes a selectable one of a number of selectable layouts of the amplifier's input stage, each defining an input matching circuit operating at a given RF frequency.
      <br/>
      A unique RF signal input inductor is selectively associated to an input coupling capacitor and to a second emitter or source degeneration inductor of a gain transistor of the input stage having a different value.
      <br/>
      The selection of a predetermined layout is operated with a plurality of switches through which a dedicated current generator is switchable on the programmably selected input stage.
      <br/>
      A bias current conducts through the selected input stage.
    </p>
    <p num="15">An input stage configured as a function of the operating frequency and of an optimizing combination of the input matching and linearity parameters is coupled to a respective output current buffer in which several transistors are driven by bias voltages whose value determines the selection of one of several predefined gain values.</p>
    <heading>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
    <p num="16">
      FIG. 1 shows a common circuit of a low noise RF amplifier with an input matching circuit and gain control stage, according to the prior art.
      <br/>
      FIGS. 2a, 2b respectively show a functional scheme of a configurable low noise RF amplifier with bipolar transistors and with field effect transistors, according to the present invention.
      <br/>
      FIG. 3 shows a detail circuit of an output block of the scheme illustrated in FIG. 2.
    </p>
    <heading>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
    <p num="17">
      The following is a description of a low noise amplifier (LNA) whose gain and operating frequency are programmable in discrete steps.
      <br/>
      The circuit may be used for a variety of applications or for a certain application, which, as in the GSM case, requires accurate linearity in addition to low noise characteristics.
    </p>
    <p num="18">
      By way of example, the circuit is formed with bipolar junction technology although the circuit of the present invention may be easily adapted to CMOS or BiCMOS technology.
      <br/>
      FIG. 2a illustrates an embodiment of the amplifier circuit of the invention using bipolar junction transistors (BJT).
      <br/>
      As previously stated, the circuit may also be formed with CMOS field effect transistors (FETS) as illustrated in FIG. 2b. The same references are used in both FIGS. 2a and 2b.
    </p>
    <p num="19">
      The circuit is generalized for a multi-standard application with N different operating frequencies.
      <br/>
      The transistors Q21 -Q2N are the gain elements of the selectively configurable input stages of the amplifier defined by the configuration switches Si.
      <br/>
      The selected transistor Q2i is activated by a current mirror effect of the corresponding transistor Q1i of each pair of selected transistors.
    </p>
    <p num="20">
      The resistors RAi and RBi have the same function of limiting the noise originating from the bias network of the common circuit shown in FIG. 1.
      <br/>
      The blocks Ai are output current buffers whose gain may assume two different values depending on the value of the control voltage VC.
      <br/>
      The resistor RL and the inductors LEi have the same function as in the circuit of FIG. 1.
    </p>
    <p num="21">
      In particular, in the case of a low frequency input RF signal having high gain, wherein the linearity only depends on the output dynamics, the inductors LEi may be equal and sized according to equation (1).
      <br/>
      This is not the case for the LB conductor and the capacitors Ci, because the match of the imaginary part depends on the specific operating frequency  OMEGA .
    </p>
    <p num="22">
      Assuming the circuit is used for a multi-standard application, for example, which requires a programmable match at different operating RF frequencies, the capacitors Ci become part of the matching network.
      <br/>
      By assuming the activation of the i branch, equation (2) transforms to:  (Equation image '2' not included in text)
    </p>
    <p num="23">
      Once the values LEi and LB are established, it is possible to select Ci to obtain the match of the imaginary part at the desired frequency.
      <br/>
      The value of LB should be established with reference to the lower operating frequency, which requires the highest value of LB.
      <br/>
      Therefore, it is possible to adapt the circuit to operate at different operating frequencies by adequately sizing the capacitors Ci and by using a unique RF signal input inductor LB.
    </p>
    <p num="24">
      The configurable circuit of the amplifier of the invention allows for simultaneously satisfying the requirement of operating at different frequencies, i.e., different standards, and with different signal levels having wide dynamics.
      <br/>
      With respect to the input part of the circuit, it is possible for a certain operating frequency to associate several branches with different inductances LEi to be dynamically selected by the switches Si, depending on the amplitude level of the input signal.
      <br/>
      For example, three branches may be associated for the GSM and additional three branches for the DCS.
    </p>
    <p num="25">
      A further functionality of the circuit is given by the particular implementation of the output current buffer of the various selectable input stages, represented by the Ai blocks.
      <br/>
      As shown in FIG. 3, each output current buffer is formed by K+1 transistors and by K resistors.
      <br/>
      The resistors REi are introduced to more adequately match the Q4i transistors.
    </p>
    <p num="26">
      It is possible to set the maximum gain if VB &gt;VC 4VT, or any other gain value if VC is much greater than VB (VC &gt;VB 4VT).
      <br/>
      In the latter case, the gain value would depend on the number of branches of transistors Q41 -Q4K that have been connected to the output node.
      <br/>
      In the illustrated example of FIG. 3, only the branch of Q41 is connected to the output node.
    </p>
    <p num="27">
      Each block Ai defines two prefixed gain values.
      <br/>
      For example, the maximum gain and any other reduced gain value.
      <br/>
      Therefore, the blocks Ai permit association of two different gains to the circuit selected by the switches Si, carrying out an efficient programming function of the gain through accurate steps as required by many RF applications.
    </p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>What is claimed is:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1.</claim-text>
      <claim-text>A low noise amplifier (LNA) comprising:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>a current generator providing a bias current; a plurality of input stages connected to said current generator, each input stage comprising a first transistor and a second transistor connected to said first transistor forming a current mirror; an input matching network connected in common to said plurality of input stages, said input matching network comprising a first inductor and a plurality of capacitors, each capacitor connected in common to said first inductor and to a respective input stage defining an operating frequency of the respective input stage; a plurality of output current buffers each having a selectable gain and being connected to a respective input stage;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and a plurality of switches for selecting a respective output current buffer to receive the bias current to thereby select a gain.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="2">
      <claim-text>2. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 1, wherein said first and second transistors each comprises a bipolar junction transistor;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and wherein said second transistor is connected in a common-emitter configuration.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="3">
      <claim-text>3. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 1, wherein said first transistor is connected to said current generator for providing the bias current to said second transistor when said respective switch is selected.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="4">
      <claim-text>4. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 1, wherein said first and second transistors each comprises a metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="5">
      <claim-text>5. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 1, wherein each input stage comprises a pair of noise limiting resistors connected in series between said first and second transistors.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="6">
      <claim-text>6. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 1, wherein each input stage comprises an inductor connected between said first and second transistors.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="7">
      <claim-text>7. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 1, wherein the bias current comprises a first and a second bias current;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and wherein each output current buffer comprises: a third transistor forming an output node of the LNA and receiving the first bias current;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and a plurality of fourth transistors connected together and receiving the second bias current, at least one of said fourth transistors being connected to said third transistor and others of said plurality of fourth transistors being connected to a voltage supply node of the LNA.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="8">
      <claim-text>8. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 7, further comprising a plurality of degeneration resistors, each resistor connected between one of said plurality of fourth transistors and a respective input stage.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="9">
      <claim-text>9. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 7, wherein said third and fourth transistors each comprises a bipolar junction transistor;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and wherein said plurality of fourth transistors are connected in a common-emitter configuration;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and wherein a collector of said at least one fourth transistor is connected to a collector of said third transistor.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="10">
      <claim-text>10. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 7, wherein said third and said plurality of fourth transistors each comprises a metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="11">
      <claim-text>11. A low noise amplifier (LNA) comprising: a current generator providing a bias current; a plurality of input stages connected to said current generator, each input stage comprising a first transistor and a second transistor connected to said first transistor forming a current mirror, and an inductor being connected between said first and second transistors; an input matching network connected in common to said plurality of input stages, said input matching network comprising a first inductor and a plurality of capacitors, each capacitor connected in common to said first inductor and to a respective input stage defining an operating frequency of the respective input stage; a plurality of output current buffers each having a selectable gain and being connected to a respective input stage;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and a plurality of switches for selecting a respective output current buffer to receive the bias current to thereby select a gain.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="12">
      <claim-text>12. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 11, wherein said first and second transistors each comprises a bipolar junction transistor;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and wherein said second transistor is connected in a common-emmitter configuration.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="13">
      <claim-text>13. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 11, wherein said first transistor is connected to said current generator for providing the bias current to said second transistor when said respective switch is selected.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="14">
      <claim-text>14. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 11, wherein said first and second transistors each comprises a metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="15">
      <claim-text>15. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 11, wherein each input stage comprises a pair of noise limiting resistors connected in series between said first and second transistors.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="16">
      <claim-text>16. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 11, wherein the bias current comprises a first and a second bias current;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and wherein each output current buffer comprises: a third transistor forming an output node of the LNA and receiving the first bias current;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and a plurality of fourth transistors connected together and receiving the second bias current, at least one of said fourth transistors being connected to said third transistor and others of said plurality of fourth transistors being connected to a voltage supply node of the LNA.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="17">
      <claim-text>17. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 16, further comprising a plurality of degeneration resistors, each resistor connected between one of said plurality of fourth transistors and a respective input stage.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="18">
      <claim-text>18. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 16, wherein said third and fourth transistors each comprises a bipolar junction transistor;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and wherein said plurality of fourth transistors are connected in a common-emitter configuration;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and wherein a collector of said at least one fourth transistor is connected to a collector of said third transistor.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="19">
      <claim-text>19. A low noise amplifier (LNA) according to claim 16, wherein said third and said plurality of fourth transistors each comprises a metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="20">
      <claim-text>20. A method for making a low noise amplifier (LNA) having a selectable gain, the method comprising the steps of: providing a bias current using a current generator; connecting a plurality of input stages to the current generator, each input stage comprising a first transistor and a second transistor connected to the first transistor forming a current mirror; defining an operating frequency of each input stage using an input matching network, the input matching network being connected in common to the plurality of input stages, the input matching network comprising a first inductor and a plurality of capacitors, each capacitor connected in common to the first inductor and to a respective input stage for defining the operating frequency of the respective input stage; connecting an output current buffer to a respective input stage, each output current buffer having a selectable gain;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and connecting a plurality of switches for selecting a respective output current buffer to receive the bias current to thereby select a gain.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="21">
      <claim-text>21. A method according to claim 20, wherein the first and second transistors each comprises a bipolar junction transistor;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and wherein the step of connecting a plurality of input stages comprises connecting the second transistor in a common-emitter configuration.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="22">
      <claim-text>22. A method according to claim 20, wherein the first transistor is connected to the current generator for providing the bias current to the second transistor when the respective switch is selected.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="23">
      <claim-text>23. A method according to claim 20, wherein the first and second transistors each comprises a metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="24">
      <claim-text>24. A method according to claim 20, further comprising the step of connecting a pair of noise limiting resistors in series between the first and second transistors for each input stage.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="25">
      <claim-text>25. A method according to claim 20, further comprising the step of connecting an inductor between the first and second transistors for each input stage.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="26">
      <claim-text>26. A method according to claim 20, wherein the bias current comprises a first and a second bias current;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and wherein the step of connecting an output current buffer to a respective input stage comprises: using a third transistor for forming an output node of the LNA and for receiving the first bias current;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and connecting together a plurality of fourth transistors for receiving the second bias current, at least one of the fourth transistors being connected to the third transistor and others of the plurality of fourth transistors being connected to a voltage supply node of the LNA.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="27">
      <claim-text>27. A method according to claim 26, further comprising the step of connecting a respective degeneration resistor between one of the plurality of fourth transistors and a respective input stage.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="28">
      <claim-text>28. A method according to claim 26, wherein the third and fourth transistors each comprises a bipolar junction transistor;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and wherein the step of connecting together the plurality of fourth transistors comprises connecting the plurality of fourth transistors in a common-emitter configuration, and connecting a collector of the at least one fourth transistor to a collector of the third transistor.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="29">
      <claim-text>29. A method according to claim 26, wherein the third and the plurality of fourth transistors each comprises a metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>