<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06182515B2.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as second publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06182515</doc-number>
        <kind>B2</kind>
        <date>20010206</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6182515</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B2</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference family-id="22314783" extended-family-id="755332">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>09107091</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19980629</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>1998US-09107091</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>775225</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>10709198</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19980629</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>1998US-09107091</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010206</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>G01M  13/02        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>01</class>
        <subclass>M</subclass>
        <main-group>13</main-group>
        <subgroup>02</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>073862080</text>
        <class>073</class>
        <subclass>862080</subclass>
      </main-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="1">
        <text>192037000</text>
        <class>192</class>
        <subclass>037000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <classifications-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="1">
        <text>G01M-013/02H</text>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>01</class>
        <subclass>M</subclass>
        <main-group>013</main-group>
        <subgroup>02H</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
    </classifications-ecla>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>G01M-013/025</classification-symbol>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>01</class>
        <subclass>M</subclass>
        <main-group>13</main-group>
        <subgroup>025</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>15</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>17</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6182515</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Coupler arrangement for isolation arrangement for system under test</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="1">
          <text>CALISTRAT MICHAEL M</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>4004433</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US4004433</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="2">
          <text>ROSENDAHL PETER, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>4407401</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US4407401</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="3">
          <text>MAURER RUPRECHT</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>4721492</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US4721492</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="4">
          <text>METCALF JEFFREY D, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>4730788</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US4730788</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="5">
          <text>OMURA HIROYOSHI</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5339145</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5339145</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="6">
          <text>HERNANDEZ WALTER C, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>4931949</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US4931949</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="7">
          <text>KLOTZ GMBH SPEZIALGERAETE</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>DE</country>
            <doc-number>3905983</doc-number>
            <kind>A1</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>DE3905983</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="8">
          <text>MONITORING TECH CORP</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>EP</country>
            <doc-number>0442020</doc-number>
            <kind>A1</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>EP-442020</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="9">
          <text>ALLPAC INT BV</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>EP</country>
            <doc-number>0576056</doc-number>
            <kind>A1</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>EP-576056</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <nplcit num="1">
          <text>Patent Abstracts of Japan, vol. 015, No. 249 (M-1128), Jun. 25, 1991 (1991-06-25) &amp; JP 03 079815 A (Shin Nippon Tool KK), Apr. 4, 1991 (1991-04-04).</text>
        </nplcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant data-format="original" app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>Veri-Tek Inc.</orgname>
            <address>
              <address-1>Farmington Hills, MI, US</address-1>
              <city>Farmington Hills</city>
              <state>MI</state>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
        <applicant data-format="questel" app-type="applicant" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>VERI TEK</orgname>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Juranitch, James C.</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Walled Lake, MI, US</address-1>
              <city>Walled Lake</city>
              <state>MI</state>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Olschefski, Robert D.</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Farmington, MI, US</address-1>
              <city>Farmington</city>
              <state>MI</state>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
      <agents>
        <agent sequence="1" rep-type="agent">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>Rohm &amp; Monsanto, P.L.C.</orgname>
          </addressbook>
        </agent>
      </agents>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>Noori, Max</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>LAPSED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      A drive coupling arrangement for transmitting torque from a drive arrangement to a gear assembly under test is provided with a first coupler portion attached to the gear assembly under test.
      <br/>
      The coupler has a polygonal cross-sectional configuration and has a plurality of substantially planar surfaces that extend parallel to the predetermined length of axis, in the form of an assembly nut of the gear assembly under test at a rotatory terminal thereof.
      <br/>
      A second coupler portion is coupled to the drive arrangement and has an internal cross-sectional configuration that accommodates the polygonal cross-sectional configuration of the first coupler portion.
      <br/>
      The second coupler portion has a plurality of engagement portions that communicate exclusively with a predetermined number of the substantially planar surfaces of the first coupler portion, and is axially translatable along the first coupler portion for a portion of its length of axis.
      <br/>
      The first and second coupler portions exert a torque against one another via the substantially planar surfaces of the first coupler portion and the engagement portions of the second coupler portion, over a predetermined range of the portion of the predetermined length of axis.
      <br/>
      A resilient biasing element urges the second coupler portion axially toward the first coupler portion.
      <br/>
      The resilient biasing element urges the second coupler portion axially upward toward the first coupler portion.
      <br/>
      An isolation support supports the energy transfer system so as to be translatable in at least one plane of freedom.
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <heading>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="1">
      1.
      <br/>
      Field of the Invention
    </p>
    <p num="2">This invention relates generally to systems for testing electrical and mechanical energy transfer systems that exhibit vibratory and other responses to electrical or mechanical input energy, and more particularly, to an arrangement that isolates a mechanical or electrical system under test and produces signals and data corresponding to a plurality of operating characteristics of the system under test in response to the input energy.</p>
    <p num="3">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
    <p num="4">
      Noise testing of gears to date has been attempted by methods that rigidly mount the gear or axle assemblies in one or more planes.
      <br/>
      Some other previous attempts chose to have one of the rigidly mounted planes resonate at a frequency sympathetic to gear noise.
      <br/>
      None of these methods, or any other rigidly mounted test system has been successful.
      <br/>
      This is due to the lack of repeatability of the previous systems, largely as a result of interacting resonances, and external background noise that is transferred through the rigid mounting system.
      <br/>
      This is especially true in a production test environment.
    </p>
    <p num="5">
      These deficiencies in the prior art are most evident in the axle industry.
      <br/>
      At this time, the only widely accepted way of measuring gear noise is to acquire an assembled axle and install it in a test car.
      <br/>
      A specially trained individual then drives the car over its typical operating range while carefully listening for axle gear noise.
      <br/>
      The individual rates the quality of axle gear noise on a scale that is typically 0 to 10.
      <br/>
      Ten is usually a perfect axle, i.e. one that has no gear noise.
      <br/>
      This method is made difficult by:
    </p>
    <p num="6">1 The lack of available trained noise rating individuals</p>
    <p num="7">2 The cost of test cars.</p>
    <p num="8">3 The lack of quality roads or test tracks on which to perform a repeatable and accurate test.</p>
    <p num="9">4 The time required for each test.</p>
    <p num="10">5 The subjectivity that humans bring into the rating system</p>
    <p num="11">
      Typically less than a dozen axles can be tested by a major manufacturer in one shift due to all of the above complications.
      <br/>
      This low number is not statistically valid when it is considered that most manufacturers make thousands of axles each day.
      <br/>
      Even with all of the above problems, human testers in cars are the only widely accepted method of axle testing in the industry due to the lack of a better more reliable testing method.
      <br/>
      This lack of a scientific basis for rating axles and gear systems is made worse when the reader considers that modern cars are extremely quiet, and are evolving to become more quiet.
      <br/>
      This market direction increases the pressure on axle and other gear manufacturers to make their products quieter.
      <br/>
      There is a need for a system that offers gear and axle manufacturers a repeatable reliable, accurate and practical way of measuring gear noise in production or laboratory environments.
    </p>
    <p num="12">It is, therefore, an object of this invention to provide a system for testing an energy transfer system, such as a vehicle axle, quickly and inexpensively, and achieving repeatable results.</p>
    <heading>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="13">
      The foregoing and other objects are achieved by this invention which provides, in a first apparatus aspect thereof, a drive coupling arrangement for transmitting substantially exclusively torque from a drive arrangement to a gear assembly under test.
      <br/>
      In accordance with the invention, the drive coupling arrangement is provided with a first coupler portion attached to the gear assembly under test.
      <br/>
      The coupler has a polygonal cross-sectional configuration that extends continuously over a predetermined length of axis.
      <br/>
      The polygonal cross-sectional configuration has a plurality of substantially planar surfaces that extend parallel to the predetermined length of axis.
      <br/>
      In addition, there is provided a second coupler portion with an internal cross-sectional configuration that accommodates the polygonal cross-sectional configuration of the first coupler portion.
      <br/>
      The second coupler portion has a plurality of engagement portions that communicate exclusively with a predetermined number of the substantially planar surfaces of the first coupler portion.
      <br/>
      The second coupler is axially translatable along the first coupler portion for a portion of its predetermined length of axis.
      <br/>
      In this manner, the first and second coupler portions exert a torque against one another via the substantially planar surfaces of the first coupler portion and the engagement portions of the second coupler portion, over a predetermined range of the portion of the predetermined length of axis.
    </p>
    <p num="14">
      In one embodiment of the invention, the first coupler portion is in the form of an assembly nut of the gear assembly under test at a rotatory terminal thereof The polygonal cross-sectional configuration corresponds to a hexagon and has six substantially planar surfaces.
      <br/>
      The second coupler portion has three engagement portions that engage three respective substantially planar surfaces of the first coupler portion.
      <br/>
      The second coupler portion is coupled to the drive arrangement.
    </p>
    <p num="15">
      A resilient biasing element urges the second coupler portion axially toward the first coupler portion.
      <br/>
      The predetermined length of axis is substantially vertically arranged, the first coupler portion being disposed axially superior to the second coupler portion.
      <br/>
      The resilient biasing element urging the second coupler portion axially upward toward the first coupler portion.
    </p>
    <p num="16">
      In accordance with a further apparatus aspect of the invention, there is provided an arrangement for isolating an energy transfer system while it is subjected to a test process for noise, the energy transfer system being of the type having an energy input and at least one energy output.
      <br/>
      In accordance with the invention, the arrangement is provided with a base for supporting the arrangement and the energy transfer system.
      <br/>
      An isolation support supports the energy transfer system whereby the energy transfer system is translatable in at least one plane of freedom with respect to the base.
      <br/>
      Additionally, an engagement arrangement is provided for securing the energy transfer system to the isolation support, the engagement arrangement having a first position with respect to the base wherein the energy transfer system is installable on, and removable from, the isolation support, and a second position wherein the energy transfer system is secured to the isolation support.
      <br/>
      A first coupler portion is attached to the gear system, the coupler portion having a polygonal cross-sectional configuration that extends continuously over a predetermined length of axis.
      <br/>
      The polygonal cross-sectional configuration has a plurality of substantially planar surfaces that extend parallel to the predetermined length of axis.
      <br/>
      There is additionally provided a second coupler portion having an internal cross-sectional configuration that accommodates the polygonal cross-sectional configuration of the first coupler portion.
      <br/>
      The second coupler portion has a plurality of engagement portions that communicate exclusively with a predetermined number of the substantially planar surfaces of the first coupler portion, and are axially translatable along the first coupler portion for a portion of the predetermined length of axis.
      <br/>
      Thus, the first and second coupler portions exert a torque against one another via the substantially planar surfaces of the first coupler portion and the engagement portions of the second coupler portion
    </p>
    <p num="17">
      In one embodiment, there is further provided an energy supply coupled to the energy transfer system for supplying energy thereto when the engagement arrangement is in the second position.
      <br/>
      The energy transfer system is, in one embodiment of the arrangement of the present invention, a mechanical energy transfer system, and in such an embodiment, the energy supply, which is a part of the arrangement of the invention, is in the form of a source of rotatory mechanical energy.
      <br/>
      A rotatory coupler couples the source of rotatory mechanical energy to the energy transfer system.
      <br/>
      The first coupler portion, in this embodiment of the invention, is an hexagonal assembly nut.
      <br/>
      The second coupler portion is resiliently urged toward the first coupler portion by operation of a resilient spring.
    </p>
    <p num="18">
      In a highly advantageous embodiment of the invention, the mechanical energy transfer system test has forward and reverse directions of operation, and drive and coast modes of operation for each of the forward and reverse directions of operation.
      <br/>
      The mechanical energy transfer system contains at least a pair of meshed elements, at least one of the pair of meshed elements being a gear having a plurality of gear teeth thereon, the gear teeth each having first and second gear tooth surfaces for communicating with the other element of the pair of meshed elements.
      <br/>
      A mechanical energy transfer communication between the pair of meshed elements is effected primarily via the respective first gear tooth surfaces during forward-drive and reverse-coast modes of operation, and primarily via the respective second gear tooth surfaces during forward-coast and reverse-drive modes of operation.
      <br/>
      With such a system under test, the arrangement of the present invention is provided with a first acoustic sensor arranged at a first location in the vicinity of the mechanical energy transfer system for producing a first signal that is responsive substantially to a qualitative condition of the first gear tooth surfaces.
      <br/>
      A second acoustic sensor is arranged at a second location in the vicinity of the mechanical energy transfer system, and produces a second signal that is responsive substantially to a qualitative condition of the second gear tooth surfaces.
      <br/>
      The first and second locations are distal from each other on opposite sides of the pair of meshed elements.
    </p>
    <p num="19">
      In a further embodiment of the invention, the rotatory coupler is provided with a resilient coupler arrangement that transmits rotatory motion thereacross over a predetermined range of rotatory motion transmission angles.
      <br/>
      The resilient coupler arrangement is provided with first and second coupler portions, the first and second coupler portions being rigidly coupled rotationally to each other.
      <br/>
      Additionally, they are axially resiliently coupled to each other, whereby the first and second coupler portions are synchronously rotatable over the predetermined range of rotatory motion transmission angles.
    </p>
    <p num="20">
      In yet a further embodiment of the invention, the resilient coupler arrangement is provided with first and second coupler portions, the first and second coupler portions being rigidly coupled rotationally to each other, and radially resiliently coupled to each other.
      <br/>
      Thus, the first and second coupler portions are synchronously rotatable over a predetermined range of axial displacement.
    </p>
    <p num="21">
      A torque sensor advantageously is interposed, in a highly advantageous embodiment, between the source of rotatory mechanical energy and the energy transfer system.
      <br/>
      The torque sensor produces a signal that is responsive to a torque applied by the source of rotatory mechanical energy to the energy transfer system.
      <br/>
      The torque sensor is provided with a torque-transmitting element that has a predetermined deformation characteristic.
      <br/>
      Thus, the torque-transmitting element becomes deformed in response to the torque that is applied by the source of rotatory mechanical energy to the energy transfer system.
      <br/>
      In this embodiment of the invention, the torque sensor further is provided with a strain sensor that is coupled to the torque-transmitting element for producing a strain signal responsive to the predetermined deformation characteristic of the torque-transmitting element.
      <br/>
      The strain signal, therefore, is proportional to the torque.
    </p>
    <p num="22">
      It is very advantageous to determine the residual torque required to initiate motion of the system under test.
      <br/>
      The torque sensor is therefore arranged to produce a static torque signal that is responsive to the magnitude of the torque required to initiate rotatory motion in the mechanical energy transfer system.
      <br/>
      In addition, it is advantageous that the torque sensor be arranged to produce a dynamic torque signal that is responsive to the magnitude of torque required to maintain rotatory motion in the mechanical energy transfer system.
    </p>
    <p num="23">
      In accordance with a further apparatus aspect of the invention. there is provided an arrangement for isolating a mechanical drive system for a vehicle while it is subjected to a testing process, the drive system being of the type having a rotatory input and at least one rotatory output.
      <br/>
      In accordance with the invention, the arrangement is provided with a base for supporting the arrangement and the mechanical drive system.
      <br/>
      An isolation support supports the mechanical drive system whereby the mechanical drive system is translatable in at least one plane of freedom with respect to the base.
      <br/>
      An engagement arrangement secures the mechanical drive system to the isolation support, the engagement arrangement having a first position with respect to the base wherein the mechanical drive system is installable on, and removable from, the isolation support, and a second position wherein the mechanical drive system is secured to the isolation support.
      <br/>
      An engagement driver is coupled to the base and to the engagement arrangement for urging the engagement arrangement between the first and second positions.
      <br/>
      The engagement arrangement is coupled to the engagement driver when the engagement arrangement is in the first position, and isolated from the engagement driver when the engagement arrangement is in the second position.
      <br/>
      In addition, a rotatory drive applies a rotatory drive force to the mechanical drive system, and a drive coupler transmits a torque from the rotatory drive to the rotatory input of the mechanical drive system.
      <br/>
      The drive coupler is itself provided with a first coupler portion attached to the mechanical drive system, the coupler having a polygonal cross-sectional configuration that extends continuously over a predetermined length of axis.
      <br/>
      The polygonal cross-sectional configuration has a plurality of substantially planar surfaces that extend parallel to the predetermined length of axis.
      <br/>
      Additionally, the drive coupler is provided with a second coupler portion having an internal cross-sectional configuration that accommodates the polygonal cross-sectional configuration of said first coupler portion.
      <br/>
      The second coupler portion has a plurality of engagement portions that communicate exclusively with a predetermined number of the substantially planar surfaces of said first coupler portion, and are axially translatable along the first coupler portion for a portion of the predetermined length of axis.
      <br/>
      Thus, the first and second coupler portions exert a torque against one another via the substantially planar surfaces of said first coupler portion and the engagement portions of the second coupler portion, over a predetermined range of the portion of the predetermined length of axis.
    </p>
    <p num="24">
      In a mechanical embodiment of the invention. there are additionally provided a rotatory load for applying a rotatory load to the mechanical drive system, and a load coupler for coupling the rotatory load to the rotatory input of the mechanical drive system.
      <br/>
      The mechanical drive system is in the form of a drive-transmitting component for a motor vehicle.
      <br/>
      In such an embodiment, the rotatory load applies a controllable rotatory load thereto to simulate a plurality of vehicle operating conditions.
      <br/>
      These include, for example, gear drive and coast conditions, as well as a gear float condition.
    </p>
    <p num="25">
      In accordance with a method aspect of the invention, there is provided a method of testing a gear assembly of the type having an input and an output.
      <br/>
      The method includes the steps of:
    </p>
    <p num="26">
      installing the gear assembly on a mounting arrangement that resiliently permits motion of
      <br/>
      installing the gear assembly on a mounting arrangement that resiliently permits motion of the gear assembly in all directions, the gear assembly having an hexagonal assembly nut installed at a rotatory input thereof;
      <br/>
      urging a coupler having three engagement surfaces resiliently and continuously toward the hexagonal nut, whereby the three engagement surfaces communicate with three corresponding surfaces of the hexagonal assembly nut;
      <br/>
      applying a torque at the coupler, whereby the gear assembly is rotatably operated;
      <br/>
      applying a load at the output of the gear assembly; and
      <br/>
      sensing a predetermined operating characteristic of the gear assembly.
    </p>
    <p num="27">
      In one embodiment of this method aspect of the invention, the step of sensing is provided with the step of detecting acoustic energy issued by the gear assembly.
      <br/>
      Also, the step of detecting acoustic energy issued by the gear assembly is provided with the step of placing a microphone n the vicinity of the gear assembly.
    </p>
    <p num="28">
      In accordance with a further embodiment of this method aspect of the invention, the drive and coast modes of operation are cyclical over a period that is shorter than a cycle period of the input of the gear assembly.
      <br/>
      Conversely, the period can be longer than a cycle period of the input of the gear assembly.
      <br/>
      This will depend, to an extent, upon the operating ratios within the system under test.
      <br/>
      In situations where the system under test is an electrical system, harmonics and signal distortions may affect the apparent cycle period in relation to the cycle period of the input energy.
    </p>
    <p num="29">
      In an advantageous embodiment, the first and second sensors are disposed at respective locations that are distal from each other, with the gear assembly interposed therebetween.
      <br/>
      This enables distinguishing between operating modalities of the system under test, as well as facilitating analysis of operating characteristics of the system under test that have directional components.
    </p>
    <heading>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING</heading>
    <p num="30">
      Comprehension of the invention is facilitated by reading the following detailed description, in conjunction with the annexed drawing, in which:
      <br/>
      FIG. 1 is a front plan representation of an arrangement for isolating a system under test, constructed in accordance with the principles of the invention;
      <br/>
      FIG. 2 is a side plan view of the embodiment of FIG. 1;
      <br/>
      FIG. 3 is an exploded plan representation of the embodiment of FIG. 1 showing certain drive components;
      <br/>
      FIG. 4 is a top plan view of the embodiment of FIG. 1;
      <br/>
      FIG. 5 is a partially phantom front plan view of a drive arrangement that supplied rotatory mechanical energy to an isolate mechanical energy transfer system under test;
      <br/>
      FIG. 6 is side plan view of the drive system of FIG. 5;
      <br/>
      FIG. 7 is a side plan representation of the drive system as shown in FIG. 6, enlarged to show greater detail;
      <br/>
      FIG. 8 is a side plan view of a coupler that couples the drive system to the mechanical system under test;
      <br/>
      FIG. 9 is a top plan view of the coupler of FIG. 8 showing therein three engagement surfaces for coupling with the flanks of an hexagonal nut (not shown in this figure) at the rotatory input of the mechanical system under test;
      <br/>
      FIG. 10 is a plan representation of a clamping arrangement constructed in accordance with the principles of the invention, the clamping arrangement being shown in two positions;
      <br/>
      FIG. 11 is a compact drive arrangement constructed in accordance with the invention for coupling the rotatory output of a mechanical energy transfer system under test to a rotatory load;
      <br/>
      FIG. 12 is a partially cross-sectional side plan view of the compact drive arrangement of FIG. 11 further showing a resilient coupling element;
      <br/>
      FIG. 13 is a partially phantom enlarged representation of the resilient coupling element shown in FIG. 12;
      <br/>
      FIG. 14 is an isometric representation of an arrangement for isolating a system under test, constructed in accordance with the principles of the invention, the system under test being an electrical energy transfer device;
      <br/>
      FIG. 15 is a process diagram of a typical process for conducting an energy analysis;
      <br/>
      FIG. 16 is a process diagram of a process for conducting an energy analysis in accordance with the principles of the present invention; and
      <br/>
      FIG. 17 is a process diagram of a process for conducting an energy analysis in accordance with the principles of the present invention for determining bumps and nicks in a mechanical energy transfer system.
    </p>
    <heading>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
    <p num="31">
      FIG. 1 is a front plan representation of an arrangement for isolating a system under test, constructed in accordance with the principles of the invention.
      <br/>
      As shown in this figure, an isolating arrangement 10 is arranged to support in relative isolation a mechanical drive system in the form of a differential 11.
      <br/>
      Differential 11 is of the type that is conventionally employed in a motor vehicle (not shown) and is intended to be tested for a variety of operating conditions, using isolating arrangement 10.
      <br/>
      The differential is of the type having a rotatory input 13 that receives rotatory mechanical energy from a drive arrangement (not shown in this figure) that will be described below.
      <br/>
      In addition, differential 11 has rotatory outputs 14 and 15, respectively, that produce rotatory mechanical energy in response to the rotatory input energy received at rotatory input 13.
      <br/>
      When employed in a motor vehicle (not shown), differential 11 is coupled to the drive shaft (not shown) of the vehicle at rotatory input 13, and rotatory outputs 14 and 15 are coupled to the vehicle's drive wheels (not shown).
    </p>
    <p num="32">
      Differential 11 is shown to be supported on a pair of supports 18 and 19 that are installed on a base 20.
      <br/>
      Each of supports 18 and 19 has installed thereon a respectively associated one of resilient isolating elements 22 and 23.
      <br/>
      A respective one of engagement arrangements 24 and 25 are installed on resilient isolating elements 22 and 23.
      <br/>
      The engagement arrangements will be described in detail hereinbelow and serve to couple differential 11 at its rotatory outputs 14 and 15 whereby it is secured with respect to base 20, yet limited motion of differential 11 is permitted relative to base 20.
    </p>
    <p num="33">
      FIG. 1 further shows a pair of load arrangements 28 and 29 that apply a controllable load to respectively associated ones of rotatory outputs 14 and 15.
      <br/>
      The rotatory outputs are coupled mechanically (coupling not shown in this figure) to load arrangements 28 and 29 in a manner that facilitates limited motion of the rotatory outputs with respect to base 20.
      <br/>
      The permissible displacement of differential 11 in accordance with the present invention is along multiple planes of freedom, and, as will be described hereinbelow, the coupling arrangements (not shown in this figure, between rotatory outputs 14 and 15 and their respective associated load arrangements 28 and 29 permit axial and rotative degrees of freedom of motion.
      <br/>
      Such couplings will be described with respect to FIGS. 9-12.
    </p>
    <p num="34">
      FIG. 2 is a side plan view of the embodiment of FIG. 1.
      <br/>
      This figure is taken along line 2--2 of FIG. 1.
      <br/>
      In addition to some of the structure shown in FIG. 1, FIG. 2 shows a safety cover 30 that protects the user (not shown) of the isolating arrangement in accordance with established safety standards.
      <br/>
      Elements of structure that correspond to those discussed hereinabove with respect to FIG. 1 are similarly designated.
    </p>
    <p num="35">
      FIG. 2 shows engagement arrangement 24 having engagement arms 32 and 33 that are shown in an engaged position around rotatory output 14.
      <br/>
      As will be described hereinbelow, engagement arms 32 and 33 have engaged and disengaged (not shown) positions in response to actuation of an engagement driver which is shown in this figure in the form of a linear actuator 35.
    </p>
    <p num="36">
      A safety cover 30 is shown to be coupled to a cover hinge 31, whereby the safety cover is rotatable thereabout in response to actuation of a cover actuator 34.
      <br/>
      In operation, the safety cover is arranged in the position shown in the figure during performance of the testing procedure, and it is raised to a position that is not shown in order to facilitate installation and removal of the system under test, i.e., differential 11.
    </p>
    <p num="37">FIG. 2 additionally shows a drive motor 40, which in this embodiment, is coupled to a belt pulley 42, shown in FIG. 1.</p>
    <p num="38">
      FIG. 3 is an exploded plan representation of the embodiment of FIG. 1 showing certain drive components.
      <br/>
      Elements of structure that have previously been discussed are similarly designated.
      <br/>
      The drive arrangement, and the manner by which it is coupled to differential 11, will be discussed in detail hereinbelow with respect to FIGS. 5-8.
    </p>
    <p num="39">
      FIG. 4 is a top plan view of the embodiment of FIG. 1.
      <br/>
      Elements of structure that have previously been discussed are similarly designated.
      <br/>
      Moreover, differential 11 has been removed, and therefore, is not visible in this figure.
    </p>
    <p num="40">
      In FIG. 4, each of load arrangements 28 and 29 has associated therewith a respective one of load coupler arrangements 44 and 45, each of which is coupled by a respective load belt 46 and 47 to a respective one of load units 48 and 49.
      <br/>
      Load arrangement 28 will be described in detail hereinbelow with respect to FIG. 11, and the load coupler arrangements, 44 and 45, will be described in detail with respect to FIG. 12. Referring to FIG. 4, rotatory outputs 14 and 15 (not shown in this figure) are coupled (coupling not shown in this figure) to respectively associated ones of load coupler arrangements 44 and 45 which, as previously noted, provide multiple degrees of freedom of movement.
      <br/>
      Load units 48 and 49, in this specific illustrative embodiment of the invention, are in the form of electric brakes or electric motors.
      <br/>
      Of course, other forms of loads can be employed in the practice of the invention.
      <br/>
      In embodiments of the invention where the load units are in the form of electric motors, such motors can provide simulated braking and driving operations.
      <br/>
      Thus, in the present embodiment where the isolating arrangement is directed to the testing of a drive component for a vehicle, such as a differential, the load units can be operated in a drag, or generator mode, wherein the differential would be operated in a simulated drive mode.
      <br/>
      That is, the load is driven by the differential.
      <br/>
      Alternatively, the load units can be operated in a motor drive mode, wherein the differential is itself driven by the load, i.e., operated in a simulated coast mode.
      <br/>
      In a highly advantageous embodiment of the invention, the differential can be operated and thereby tested in drive and coast modes of operation in forward and reverse directions.
      <br/>
      It is to be remembered that during drive and coast modes of operation different gear tooth surfaces (not shown) within the differential are caused to communicate with one another, thereby affording enhanced testing capability.
    </p>
    <p num="41">
      FIG. 5 is a partially phantom front plan view of a drive arrangement that supplies rotatory mechanical energy to an isolated mechanical energy transfer system under test.
      <br/>
      Elements of structure that have previously been discussed are similarly designated.
      <br/>
      As shown in this figure, output shafts 52 and 53 are shown protruding from the fragmented representation of rotatory outputs 14 and 15, respectively.
      <br/>
      The output shafts rotate in response to the application of a rotatory drive at rotatory input 13.
    </p>
    <p num="42">
      FIG. 6 is side plan view of the drive system of FIG. 5.
      <br/>
      The operation of the drive arrangement that will supply a rotatory drive to rotatory input 13 of differential 11 is described herein with reference to FIGS. 5-9. As stated, drive motor 40 is coupled via a drive belt 41 to belt pulley 42 which is installed on a drive shaft 55 that is shown in the figures to extend axially vertically.
      <br/>
      Belt pulley 42 contains a torque sensing arrangement (not shown) that provides an electrical signal responsive to torque differential between the belt pulley and drive shaft 55.
      <br/>
      The electrical signal responsive to torque (not shown) is available at signal output connector 56.
    </p>
    <p num="43">
      In this specific illustrative embodiment of the invention, the torque sensing arrangement contained within belt pulley 42 and its associated signal output connector 56 is in the form of a strain gauge (not shown) installed to respond to the displacement of a web (not shown).
      <br/>
      That is, in the practice of this aspect of the invention, torque is transmitted across a web whereby, for example the torque is applied across the periphery of the web, and an output shaft is coupled nearer to the center of the web.
      <br/>
      Of course, these may be reversed.
      <br/>
      As torque is applied, the web is correspondingly deformed, and a strain gauge installed on the web measures the deformity in the web in response to the applied torque.
      <br/>
      Over a predetermined range of torque, the deformation of the web, as determined by the strain gauge, can be correlated to the magnitude of the applied torque.
      <br/>
      Signal output connector 56, in this specific illustrative embodiment of the invention, additionally contains circuitry (not shown) that is AC coupled to the torque sensing arrangement, and that modulates and demodulates the resulting torque signal.
    </p>
    <p num="44">
      Shaft 55 is shown in FIG. 6 to be supported against axially transverse motion by a pair of journal bearings 58.
      <br/>
      Drive shaft 55, therefore, rotates about its axis in response to a rotatory drive energy supplied by drive motor 40 and delivered thereto by drive belt 41.
    </p>
    <p num="45">
      A coupling arrangement 60 that is fixed axially onto drive shaft 55 permits resilient axial displacement of a coupling shaft 62 with respect to the axis of drive shaft 55.
      <br/>
      Coupling arrangement 60 is formed of a flanged member 61 that is coupled to rotate with drive shaft 55.
      <br/>
      A further flanged member 63 is shown to be engaged with coupling shaft 62.
      <br/>
      Flanged members 61 and 63 are each provided with respective resilient elements 65 that facilitate the permissible axial displacement of coupling shaft 62 with respect to the central axis defined by drive shaft 55.
      <br/>
      The rotatory energy is transmitted across intermediate element 67, with which resilient elements 65 communicate.
    </p>
    <p num="46">
      FIG. 7 is a side plan representation of the drive system as shown in FIG. 6, enlarged to show greater detail.
      <br/>
      As shown in FIGS. 6 and 7, the uppermost end of coupling shaft 62 is arranged to be connected to rotatory input 13 of differential 11 (shown in fragmented form in these figures).
      <br/>
      Differential 11 is of the conventional type having an hexagonal nut 69 (FIG. 7) installed at rotatory input 13.
      <br/>
      Rotatory input 13 is formed as a pinion shaft, and hexagonal nut 13 is threadedly engaged therewith.
      <br/>
      The application of a high tightening torque to hexagonal nut 13 during assembly of the differential prevents same from loosening during application of the rotatory energy via coupling shaft 62.
    </p>
    <p num="47">
      FIG. 7 shows differential 11 in the process of being installed onto coupling shaft 62, and therefore hexagonal nut 69 is shown in two positions, where it is designated 69 and 69', respectively.
      <br/>
      Upon completion of the installation of differential 11, hexagonal nut 69 becomes engaged with a nut driver 70.
      <br/>
      Nut driver 70 is axially translatable, and therefore is shown in two positions, where it is designated 70 and 70'.
    </p>
    <p num="48">
      FIG. 8 is a side plan view of nut driver 70 that couples the drive system to the mechanical system under test.
      <br/>
      FIG. 9 is a top plan view of nut driver 70 of FIG. 8 showing therein three engagement surfaces for coupling with the flanks of an hexagonal nut (not shown in this figure) at the rotatory input of the mechanical system under test.
      <br/>
      As shown in FIG. 8 and FIG. 9, nut driver 70 has a tapered outward appearance when viewed from the side (FIG. 8).
      <br/>
      Internally, nut driver 70 is provided with three engagement surfaces 71.
      <br/>
      The engagement surfaces engage with the flank surfaces of the nut (not shown) at rotatory input 13 of differential 11.
      <br/>
      The nut driver is, as previously noted, axially displaceable along the axis of coupling shaft 62, and is urged upward toward the nut at the rotatory input of the differential by operation of a resilient spring member 72 (FIG. 6).
      <br/>
      Thus, the nut driver is urged into communication with the nut by operation of the light resilient bias supplied by spring 72, thereby ensuring engagement between nut driver 70 and the hexagonal nut (not shown in FIGS. 8 and 9) at the rotatory input of differential 11.
      <br/>
      It is to be noted that the light axial bias applied by the engagement spring is negligible and affords the differential a degree of freedom of movement in the axial direction.
    </p>
    <p num="49">
      Referring once again to FIG. 7, sensors 73-76 are shown for monitoring various aspects of the operation of the differential in response to the application of the rotatory input.
      <br/>
      For example, in one embodiment of the invention, the various sensors are configured to monitor angular position of the rotatory input, transaxial displacement of the drive shaft, transaxial displacement of the differential in response to the application of the rotatory input energy, temperature in the region of the input bearing (not shown) of the differential, acoustic noise, etc.
    </p>
    <p num="50">
      FIG. 10 is a plan representation of a clamping arrangement constructed in accordance with the principles of the invention, the clamping arrangement being shown in two positions.
      <br/>
      Elements of structure that correspond to those previously described are similarly designated.
      <br/>
      As shown, support 18 is coupled to base 20, illustratively via one or more fasteners 140.
      <br/>
      In this embodiment, a pair of resilient support elements 141 are disposed on support element 18 and there is supported thereon an isolation support 142.
      <br/>
      The isolation support has a central V-shaped region 144 in the vicinity of which are installed support bearings 146 and 147.
      <br/>
      Rotatory output 14 of differential 11 (not shown in this figure) rests on the support bearings.
    </p>
    <p num="51">
      Engagement arms 32 and 33, as previously noted, have first and second positions corresponding to open and closed conditions.
      <br/>
      Engagement arms 32 and 33 are shown in the closed condition, wherein rotatory output 14 is clamped to support bearings 146 and 147.
      <br/>
      When the support arms are in the open position, identified as 32' and 33' (shown in phantom), the differential can be removed or installed onto isolation support 142.
      <br/>
      Actuation of the engagement arms between the open and closed conditions is effected by operation of linear actuator 35 which is coupled to the engagement arms by respectively associated ones of engagement coupler links 148 and 149.
      <br/>
      Engagement coupler links 148 and 149 are each coupled at a respective first ends thereof to a respectively associated one of engagement arms 32 and 33, and they each are coupled to one another at a central pivot coupling 150.
      <br/>
      An armature 151 of linear actuator 35 travels vertically to effect clamping and release of rotatory output 14.
    </p>
    <p num="52">
      When armature 151 is extended upward, engagement arms 32 and 33 are urged toward rotatory output 14, whereby spring-loaded contacts 152 and 153 communicate with rotatory output 14.
      <br/>
      In this embodiment, the spring-loaded contacts exert a resilient biased force against rotatory output 14 facilitating the latching of the engagement arms by operation of armature 151.
      <br/>
      As shown, when the armature is extended fully upward, engagement coupler links 148 and 149 are urged beyond the point where their respective axes are parallel, and therefore, the engagement coupler links are biased against the underside of isolation support 142.
      <br/>
      It should be noted that the pivot pin (not specifically shown) coupled to armature 151 at pivot coupling 150 has a smaller diameter than the apertures in the engagement coupler links.
      <br/>
      Thus, during testing of the vibration and noise of the differential, armature 151 oflinear actuator 35 is essentially decoupled from engagement coupler links 148 and 149 and isolation support 142.
    </p>
    <p num="53">When it is desired to remove differential 11 from isolating arrangement 10, armature 151 is withdrawn, whereupon pivot coupling 150 is translated to the location identified as 150'. In this position, the engagement arms are translated to the location shown in phantom as 32' and 33'.</p>
    <p num="54">
      In a further embodiment of the invention, one or both of spring-loaded contacts 152 and 153 is provided with a displacements sensor 154 that produces an electrical signal, or other indication, responsive to the extent of inward translation of the spring-loaded contact.
      <br/>
      Such an indication would be responsive to the outside dimension of the rotatory output of differential 11, thereby providing a means for determining dimensional variations of the differential housing (not specifically identified in this figure) during a production run.
    </p>
    <p num="55">
      FIG. 11 is a compact drive arrangement constructed in accordance with the invention for coupling the rotatory output of a mechanical energy transfer system under test (not shown in this figure) to a rotatory load, which will be described hereinbelow in the form of an electric rotatory device that is operable in drive and generator modes.
      <br/>
      As shown in this figure, a load arrangement 80 is provided with a load motor 81 having a belt pulley 82 arranged to rotate with a load motor shaft 83.
    </p>
    <p num="56">
      In this specific embodiment, pulley 82 is coupled to a further belt pulley 85 via a load belt 86.
      <br/>
      Pulley 85 is coupled to a tubular shaft 89 having a flanged portion 90 that is arranged in axial communication with tubular shaft 89.
      <br/>
      In a manner similar to that of pulley 46 in FIG. 6, belt pulley 82 in FIG. 11 contains a torque sensing arrangement 87 that provides an electrical signal (not shown) responsive to a torque differential between the belt pulley and load motor shaft 83.
      <br/>
      The electrical signal responsive to torque is available at signal output connector 84, as described below.
    </p>
    <p num="57">
      In this specific illustrative embodiment of the invention, torque sensing arrangement 87 contained within belt pulley 82 and its associated signal output connector 84 include a strain gauge 88 installed to respond to the displacement of a web 92.
      <br/>
      That is, in the practice of this aspect of the invention, torque is transmitted across web 92 wherein, for example, the torque is applied across the periphery of the web, and an output shaft 98 is coupled nearer to the center of the web.
      <br/>
      Of course, the application of the torque may be rotationally reversed.
      <br/>
      As the torque is applied, web 92 is correspondingly deformed, and strain gauge 88 installed on the web measures the deformity in the web in response to the applied torque.
      <br/>
      Over a predetermined range of torque, the deformation of web 92, as determined by measurement of the electrical response of strain gauge 88 at signal output connector 84, can be correlated to the magnitude of the applied torque.
    </p>
    <p num="58">
      As described hereinabove with respect to signal output connector 56 in FIG. 6, in this specific illustrative embodiment of the invention, signal output connector 84 in FIG. 11 additionally contains circuitry (not shown) that is AC coupled to the torque sensing arrangement, and that modulates and demodulates the resulting torque signal.
      <br/>
      The torque signal will be to a significant extent responsive to the load or drive characteristic of load motor 81, which is controllable by the application of appropriate electrical signals (not shown) or connection of electrical loads (not shown) at electrical terminals 99 thereof.
    </p>
    <p num="59">
      Tubular shaft 89 is supported rotatably by ball bearings 91.
      <br/>
      On the other side of pulley 85 is arranged a resilient element 93 that is secured to remain in communication with pulley 85 by operation of an end cap 94.
      <br/>
      End cap 94 has internally affixed thereto a load shaft 95 that is arranged to extend along the interior length of tubular shaft 89.
      <br/>
      Thus, notwithstanding that tubular shaft 89 is axially fixed in a support 96, load shaft 95 will rotate with the tubular shaft but can experience displacement transverse to axis of rotation 98.
      <br/>
      Thus, any rotatory element (not shown in this figure) that would be coupled to load shaft 95 at its associated coupler 97 would be provided with freedom of motion in any direction transverse to the axis of rotation of the load shaft, and therefore would not be constrained in the axially transverse direction.
    </p>
    <p num="60">
      FIG. 12 is a partially cross-sectional side plan view of a compact drive arrangement similar in some respects to that of FIG. 11. This figure shows a shaft support system 100 that provides the degree of freedom of motion discussed hereinabove with respect to the embodiment of FIG. 11, and additionally provides axial thrust support.
      <br/>
      Shaft support system 100 is provided with a pulley 101 that can be coupled to another rotatory element (not shown) via a belt 102.
      <br/>
      The pulley is fixed to a tubular shaft 104 that is axially fixed in a support 105 by ball bearings 106.
      <br/>
      At the other end of tubular shaft 104, the tubular shaft is expanded radially to form a shaft portion 108 having a large diameter than the central portion of the tubular shaft.
      <br/>
      A resilient coupling arrangement that is generally designated as 110 is resiliently coupled to shaft portion 108.
      <br/>
      Resilient coupling arrangement 110 is provided with an intermediate plate 111 and an end plate 112 that are resiliently coupled to one another whereby they rotate with tubular shaft 104.
      <br/>
      A central shaft 114 is coupled at its right-most end to end plate 112 so as to be rotatable therewith.
      <br/>
      The central shaft, however, experiences freedom of movement in all directions transverse to its axis of rotation.
      <br/>
      Any travel of central shaft 114 toward the right hand side is limited by an end stop 115, which is arranged, in this embodiment, to provide a measure of axial adjustment.
      <br/>
      The other end of central shaft 114 is coupled to a resilient coupling arrangement which is generally designated as 117.
    </p>
    <p num="61">
      FIG. 13 is a partially phantom enlarged representation of the resilient coupling element shown in FIG. 12. Resilient coupling element 117 is shown in this figure in an expanded form to facilitate this detailed description.
      <br/>
      Central shaft 114 (FIG. 12) has a reduced diameter end portion 120 on which is installed a flanged washer 121 having a reduced diameter portion 122 and a flange 123 formed therearound.
      <br/>
      A further flanged element 125 is installed on reduced diameter end portion 120 of central shaft 114, a shear pin 127 being disposed between flanged washer 121 and further flanged element 125.
      <br/>
      In addition, an annular portion 128 is arranged to surround the flanged washer and the further flanged element, and to overlie circumferentially the axial region where resilient element 127 is disposed.
      <br/>
      All of these elements are secured to reduced diameter end portion 120 of central shaft 114 by a fastener 129 and a washer 130.
      <br/>
      As shown, fastener 129 is threadedly engaged axially onto the end of central shaft 114.
    </p>
    <p num="62">
      A support portion 132 is fixed onto further flanged element 125 by fasteners 133.
      <br/>
      Support portion 132 is resiliently coupled to a flanged shaft 135 by means of studs 136.
      <br/>
      Thus, even though central shaft 114 enjoys freedom of movement transverse to its axis of rotation, resilient coupling arrangement 117 provides yet further freedom of movement in all directions transverse to the axis of rotation for flanged shaft 135.
      <br/>
      Flanged shaft 135, in one embodiment of the invention, is ultimately coupled to a rotatory output, such as rotatory output 15 of FIG. 1.
      <br/>
      Alternatively, shaft support system 100 can be used in the drive arrangement of FIG. 6 to provide significant degree of motion lateral to the axis of rotation to the drive shaft.
    </p>
    <p num="63">
      FIG. 14 is an isometric representation of an arrangement for isolating a system under test, the isolation system being constructed in accordance with the principles of the invention.
      <br/>
      In this embodiment, the system under test is an electrical energy transfer device.
      <br/>
      As shown in this figure, an isolation support 160 isolates an electrical energy transfer device, illustratively in the form of an electrical transformer 162.
      <br/>
      The electrical transformer is secured to an isolation base 164 by operation of a toggle locking device 165.
      <br/>
      Isolation base 164 is mechanically isolated from a ground surface 166 by a plurality of resilient isolation elements 170.
      <br/>
      That is, the isolation base is permitted freedom of movement in at least one plane of motion, and preferably a plurality of planes of motion, by operation of the resilient isolation elements.
    </p>
    <p num="64">
      In the practice of this specific illustrative embodiment of the invention, the resilient isolation elements have a resilience characteristic that, as previously noted in regard of other embodiments of the invention, exclude a natural frequency of isolation support 160 and transformer 162.
      <br/>
      The motion of the transformer and the isolation support is therefore responsive substantially entirely to the electrical energy that is transferred to or from transformer 162 via its electrical terminals 172.
    </p>
    <p num="65">
      FIG. 15 is a process diagram of a typical process for conducting an energy analysis of a gear system.
      <br/>
      In this known system, gears under test 180 are driven by a drive 181, the speed of which is controlled by a speed control 183.
      <br/>
      Information relating to the drive speed is conducted to a digital data storage system 185.
    </p>
    <p num="66">
      Analog sensors 187 obtain analog data from gears under test 180, the analog signals from the sensors being conducted to an A/D converter 188.
      <br/>
      The A/D converter performs the conversion of the analog signals in response to a clock 190, and the resulting digital data is conducted to digital data storage system 185.
      <br/>
      Thus, digital data storage system 185 contains the digitized analog signals obtained from sensors 187, which data is correlated to the speed at which gears under test 180 are driven.
    </p>
    <p num="67">
      The digital data of digital data storage system 185 is converted to the frequency domain by subjecting same to a fast Fourier transform at step 193.
      <br/>
      The resulting frequency components are then ordered at step 194 and analyzed manually at step 195.
      <br/>
      At this step, the collected data, in the frequency domain, is analyzed in the context of predetermined test criteria.
      <br/>
      The pass/fail decision is then made at step 197, and if the predetermined criteria is not met, a "fail" indication is produced at step 198.
      <br/>
      Otherwise, a "pass" indication is issued at step 199.
    </p>
    <p num="68">
      FIG. 16 is a process diagram of a process for conducting an energy analysis in accordance with the principles of the present invention.
      <br/>
      As show in this figure, gears under test 201 are driven into rotation by a drive system 202, which also drives an encoder 204.
      <br/>
      Encoder 204 delivers signals responsive to the rotation of gears under test 201 to an A/D converter 206.
      <br/>
      In this embodiment, the signal from encoder 204 serves as a pacing clock for the A/D converter.
      <br/>
      Information relating to noise and displacement issued by the gears under test is collected by analog sensors 207.
      <br/>
      The resulting analog signals are conducted to A/D converter 206 where they are converted to digital signals correlated to the rotation of drive system 202.
    </p>
    <p num="69">
      The digital signals from A/D converter 206 are conducted to a digital data store 210 where they are maintained in correlation to the drive information obtained from encoder 204.
      <br/>
      In this specific illustrative embodiment of the invention, the digital data is stored two-dimensionally, wherein sensor signal amplitude is identified with the y-axis, and rotational position is identified with the x-axis.
      <br/>
      The correlated digital data is subjected to a fast Fourier transform at step 212 wherein the data is converted into its frequency components.
    </p>
    <p num="70">
      Data in the frequency domain is subjected to processing at step 214, where a power spectrum density is created using a data window.
      <br/>
      The power spectrum density data is then analyzed harmonically at step 215 to determine its relationship with predetermined test criteria.
      <br/>
      The decision whether the power spectrum density data passes or fails with respect to predetermined test criteria is made at step 216, and the predetermined criteria is not met, a "fail" indication is produced at step 217.
      <br/>
      Otherwise, a "pass" indication is issued at step 218.
    </p>
    <p num="71">
      FIG. 17 is a diagram of a process for conducting an analysis 230 in accordance with the principles of the present invention for determining bumps and nicks in a mechanical energy transfer system.
      <br/>
      As show in this figure, gears under test 231 are driven into rotation by a drive system 232, via a torque sensor 234.
      <br/>
      Torque sensor 234 delivers signals responsive to the rotatory force supplied to gears under test 231 to an A/D converter 236.
      <br/>
      Information relating to noise and displacement issued by the gears under test is collected by noise sensors 237, which may include velocity sensors (not shown in this figure), accelerometers (not shown in this figure), microphones (not shown in this figure), etc.
      <br/>
      The resulting noise signals are conducted to A/D converter 236 where they are converted to digital signals correlated to the torque applied by drive system 232 to gears under test 231.
    </p>
    <p num="72">
      The digital signals from A/D converter 236 are conducted to a digital data store 240 where they are maintained in correlation to the drive information obtained from torque sensor 234.
      <br/>
      In this specific illustrative embodiment of the invention, the digital data is stored as two two-dimensional data sets, wherein noise sensor signal amplitude is identified with a first y-axis, and time is identified with the x-axis.
      <br/>
      The amplitude of the torque signal is identified with a second y-axis, and time is again identified with the x-axis.
    </p>
    <p num="73">
      Correlated data from digital data store 240 is subjected to analysis at step 242, wherein peaks that occur simultaneously in the torque and noise signal waveforms are identified.
      <br/>
      These peaks are then measured at step 244 to determine whether they exceed predetermined thresholds.
      <br/>
      Those peaks that exceed the predetermined thresholds are then tested at step 245 against the harmonics of each gear tooth frequency, to determine whether the peaks correspond to anomalous conditions.
    </p>
    <p num="74">
      The decision whether the gears under test pass or fail with respect to predetermined test criteria is made at step 246, and if the predetermined criteria is not met, a "fail" indication is produced at step 247.
      <br/>
      Otherwise, a "pass" indication is issued at step 248.
      <br/>
      In some embodiments of the invention, a calculation of the severity of the bumps or nicks that caused the anomalous conditions is calculated at step 249.
    </p>
    <p num="75">
      In one embodiment of the process of FIG. 17, analysis is performed using only the torque data derived from torque sensor 234, without correlation to the noise data obtained from noise sensor 237.
      <br/>
      In this embodiment, therefore, noise sensor 237 need not be provided, as the noise signal therefrom is not used.
      <br/>
      Thus, torque sensor 234 delivers signals responsive to the rotatory force supplied to gears under test 231 to A/D converter 236, and the digital data is stored as a single two-dimensional data set, wherein the amplitude of the torque signal is identified with the y-axis, and time is identified with the x-axis.
    </p>
    <p num="76">
      Peaks in the torque signal are then measured at step 244 to determine whether they exceed a predetermined threshold.
      <br/>
      Those peaks that exceed the predetermined thresholds are then tested at step 245 against the harmonics of each gear tooth frequency, to determine whether the peaks correspond to anomalous conditions.
    </p>
    <p num="77">
      The decision whether the gears under test pass or fail with respect to predetermined test criteria is made at step 246, and if the predetermined criteria is not met, a "fail" indication is produced at step 247.
      <br/>
      Otherwise, a "pass" indication is issued at step 248.
      <br/>
      As previously noted, a calculation of the severity of the bumps or nicks that caused the anomalous condition is calculated at step 249.
    </p>
    <p num="78">
      Although the invention has been described in terms of specific embodiments and applications, persons skilled in the art can, in light of this teaching, generate additional embodiments without exceeding the scope or departing from the spirit of the claimed invention.
      <br/>
      Accordingly, it is to be understood that the drawing and description in this disclosure are proffered to facilitate comprehension of the invention, and should not be construed to limit the scope thereof
    </p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>What is claimed is:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1.</claim-text>
      <claim-text>A drive coupling arrangement for transmitting substantially exclusively torque from a drive arrangement to a gear assembly under test, the drive coupling arrangement comprising:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>a first coupler portion attached to the gear assembly under test, said coupler having a polygonal cross-sectional configuration that extends continuously over a predetermined length of axis, the polygonal cross-sectional configuration having a plurality of substantially planar surfaces that extend parallel to the predetermined length of axis;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and a second coupler portion having an internal cross-sectional configuration that accommodates the polygonal cross-sectional configuration of said first coupler portion, said second coupler portion having a plurality of engagement portions, each of which communicating exclusively with respectively associated ones of a predetermined number of the substantially planar surfaces of said first coupler portion, and being axially translatable along said first coupler portion for a portion of the predetermined length of axis, wherein said first and second coupler portions exert a non-slip torque against one another via the substantially planar surfaces of said first coupler portion and the engagement portions of said second coupler portion, over a predetermined range of the portion of the predetermined length of axis.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="2">
      <claim-text>2. The drive coupling arrangement of claim 1, wherein said first coupler portion comprises an assembly nut of the gear assembly under test at a rotatory terminal thereof.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="3">
      <claim-text>3. The drive coupling arrangement of claim 1, wherein the polygonal cross-sectional configuration corresponds to a hexagon having six substantially planar surfaces.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="4">
      <claim-text>4. The drive coupling arrangement of claim 3, wherein said second coupler portion has three engagement portions that engage three respective substantially planar surfaces of said first coupler portion.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="5">
      <claim-text>5. The coupling arrangement of claim 1, wherein said second coupler portion is coupled to the drive arrangement.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="6">
      <claim-text>6. The coupling arrangement of claim 1, wherein there is further provided a resilient biasing element for urging said second coupler portion axially toward said first coupler portion.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="7">
      <claim-text>7. The coupling arrangement of claim 6, wherein the predetermined length of axis is substantially vertically arranged, said first coupler portion being disposed axially superior to said second coupler portion, said resilient biasing element urging said second coupler portion axially upward toward said first coupler portion.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>