<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06180858B2.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as second publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06180858</doc-number>
        <kind>B2</kind>
        <date>20010130</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6180858</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B2</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference is-representative="YES" family-id="23251111" extended-family-id="42114596">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>09321562</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19990528</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>1999US-09321562</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>43173259</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>32156299</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19990528</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>1999US-09321562</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010130</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>A01H   5/10        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>A</section>
        <class>01</class>
        <subclass>H</subclass>
        <main-group>5</main-group>
        <subgroup>10</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>800320100</text>
        <class>800</class>
        <subclass>320100</subclass>
      </main-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="1">
        <text>435412000</text>
        <class>435</class>
        <subclass>412000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="2">
        <text>435424000</text>
        <class>435</class>
        <subclass>424000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="3">
        <text>435430000</text>
        <class>435</class>
        <subclass>430000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="4">
        <text>435430100</text>
        <class>435</class>
        <subclass>430100</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="5">
        <text>438412000</text>
        <class>438</class>
        <subclass>412000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="6">
        <text>438424000</text>
        <class>438</class>
        <subclass>424000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="7">
        <text>438430000</text>
        <class>438</class>
        <subclass>430000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="8">
        <text>800271000</text>
        <class>800</class>
        <subclass>271000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="9">
        <text>800275000</text>
        <class>800</class>
        <subclass>275000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="10">
        <text>800298000</text>
        <class>800</class>
        <subclass>298000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="11">
        <text>800300100</text>
        <class>800</class>
        <subclass>300100</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="12">
        <text>800301000</text>
        <class>800</class>
        <subclass>301000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="13">
        <text>800302000</text>
        <class>800</class>
        <subclass>302000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <classifications-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="1">
        <text>A01H-005/10</text>
        <section>A</section>
        <class>01</class>
        <subclass>H</subclass>
        <main-group>5</main-group>
        <subgroup>10</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
    </classifications-ecla>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>A01H-005/10</classification-symbol>
        <section>A</section>
        <class>01</class>
        <subclass>H</subclass>
        <main-group>5</main-group>
        <subgroup>10</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>30</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>0</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>0</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6180858</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Inbred corn line LH172BT810</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="1">
          <text>EGGERLING DONALD G</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5276266</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5276266</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="2">
          <text>LUNDQUIST RONALD C, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5508468</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5508468</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <nplcit num="1">
          <text>Phillips et al. "Cell/Tissue Culture and In Vitro Manipulation", In Corn and Corn Improvement, 3rd. Ed., ASA Publication, #18, pp. 345-349 &amp; 356-357, 1988.</text>
        </nplcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant data-format="original" app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>Holden's Foundation Seeds LLC</orgname>
            <address>
              <address-1>Williamsburg, IA, US</address-1>
              <city>Williamsburg</city>
              <state>IA</state>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
        <applicant data-format="questel" app-type="applicant" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>HOLDEN S FOUNDATION SEEDS</orgname>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Johnson, Arthur L.</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Williamsburg, IA, US</address-1>
              <city>Williamsburg</city>
              <state>IA</state>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
      <agents>
        <agent sequence="1" rep-type="agent">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>Rothwell, Figg, Ernst &amp; Manbeck</orgname>
          </addressbook>
        </agent>
      </agents>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>Benzion, Gary</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>GRANTED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      An inbred corn line, designated LH172Bt810, is disclosed.
      <br/>
      The invention relates to the seeds of inbred corn line LH172Bt810, to the plants of inbred corn line LH172Bt810 and to methods for producing a corn plant produced by crossing the inbred line LH172Bt810 with itself or another corn line.
      <br/>
      The invention further relates to hybrid corn seeds and plants produced by crossing the inbred line LH172Bt810 with another corn line.
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <heading>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="1">
      The present invention relates to a new and distinctive corn inbred line, designated LH172Bt810.
      <br/>
      There are numerous steps in the development of any novel, desirable plant germplasm.
      <br/>
      Plant breeding begins with the analysis and definition of problems and weaknesses of the current germplasm, the establishment of program goals, and the definition of specific breeding objectives.
      <br/>
      The next step is selection of germplasm that possess the traits to meet the program goals.
      <br/>
      The goal is to combine in a single variety or hybrid an improved combination of desirable traits from the parental germplasm.
      <br/>
      These important traits may include higher yield, resistance to diseases and insects, better stalks and roots, tolerance to drought and heat, and better agronomic quality.
    </p>
    <p num="2">
      Choice of breeding or selection methods depends on the mode of plant reproduction, the heritability of the trait(s) being improved, and the type of cultivar used commercially (e.g., F1 hybrid cultivar, pureline cultivar, etc.).
      <br/>
      For highly heritable traits, a choice of superior individual plants evaluated at a single location will be effective, whereas for traits with low heritability, selection should be based on mean values obtained from replicated evaluations of families of related plants.
      <br/>
      Popular selection methods commonly include pedigree selection, modified pedigree selection, mass selection, and recurrent selection.
    </p>
    <p num="3">
      The complexity of inheritance influences choice of the breeding method.
      <br/>
      Backcross breeding is used to transfer one or a few favorable genes for a highly heritable trait into a desirable cultivar.
      <br/>
      This approach has been used extensively for breeding disease-resistant cultivars.
      <br/>
      Various recurrent selection techniques are used to improve quantitatively inherited traits controlled by numerous genes.
      <br/>
      The use of recurrent selection in self-pollinating crops depends on the ease of pollination, the frequency of successful hybrids from each pollination, and the number of hybrid offspring from each successful cross.
    </p>
    <p num="4">
      Each breeding program should include a periodic, objective evaluation of the efficiency of the breeding procedure.
      <br/>
      Evaluation criteria vary depending on the goal and objectives, but should include gain from selection per year based on comparisons to an appropriate standard, overall value of the advanced breeding lines, and number of successful cultivars produced per unit of input (e.g., per year, per dollar expended, etc.).
    </p>
    <p num="5">
      Promising advanced breeding lines are thoroughly tested and compared to appropriate standards in environments representative of the commercial target area(s) for three years at least.
      <br/>
      The best lines are candidates for new commercial cultivars; those still deficient in a few traits are used as parents to produce new populations for further selection.
    </p>
    <p num="6">
      These processes, which lead to the final step of marketing and distribution, usually take from eight to 12 years from the time the first cross is made.
      <br/>
      Therefore, development of new cultivars is a time-consuming process that requires precise forward planning, efficient use of resources, and a minimum of changes in direction.
    </p>
    <p num="7">
      A most difficult task is the identification of individuals that are genetically superior, because for most traits the true genotypic value is masked by other confounding plant traits or environmental factors.
      <br/>
      One method of identifying a superior plant is to observe its performance relative to other experimental plants and to a widely grown standard cultivar.
      <br/>
      If a single observation is inconclusive, replicated observations provide a better estimate of its genetic worth.
    </p>
    <p num="8">
      The goal of plant breeding is to develop new, unique and superior corn inbred lines and hybrids.
      <br/>
      The breeder initially selects and crosses two or more parental lines, followed by repeated selfing and selection, producing many new genetic combinations.
      <br/>
      The breeder can theoretically generate billions of different genetic combinations via crossing, selfing and mutations.
      <br/>
      The breeder has no direct control at the cellular level.
      <br/>
      Therefore, two breeders will never develop the same line, or even very similar lines, having the same corn traits.
    </p>
    <p num="9">
      Each year, the plant breeder selects the germplasm to advance to the next generation.
      <br/>
      This germplasm is grown under unique and different geographical, climatic and soil conditions, and further selections are then made, during and at the end of the growing season.
      <br/>
      The inbred lines which are developed are unpredictable.
      <br/>
      This unpredictability is because the breeder's selection occurs in unique environments, with no control at the DNA level (using conventional breeding procedures), and with millions of different possible genetic combinations being generated.
      <br/>
      A breeder of ordinary skill in the art cannot predict the final resulting lines he develops, except possibly in a very gross and general fashion.
      <br/>
      The same breeder cannot produce the same line twice by using the exact same original parents and the same selection techniques.
      <br/>
      This unpredictability results in the expenditure of large research monies to develop a superior new corn inbred line.
    </p>
    <p num="10">
      The development of commercial corn hybrids requires the development of homozygous inbred lines, the crossing of these lines, and the evaluation of the crosses.
      <br/>
      Pedigree breeding and recurrent selection breeding methods are used to develop inbred lines from breeding populations.
      <br/>
      Breeding programs combine desirable traits from two or more inbred lines or various broad-based sources into breeding pools from which inbred lines are developed by selfing and selection of desired phenotypes.
      <br/>
      The new inbreds are crossed with other inbred lines and the hybrids from these crosses are evaluated to determine which have commercial potential.
    </p>
    <p num="11">
      Pedigree breeding is used commonly for the improvement of self-pollinating crops or inbred lines of cross-pollinating crops.
      <br/>
      Two parents which possess favorable, complementary traits are crossed to produce an F1.
      <br/>
      An F2 population is produced by selfing one or several F1 's or by intercrossing two F1 's (sib mating).
      <br/>
      Selection of the best individuals is usually begun in the F2 population; then, beginning in the F3, the best individuals in the best families are selected.
      <br/>
      Replicated testing of families, or hybrid combinations involving individuals of these families, often follows in the F4 generation to improve the effectiveness of selection for traits with low heritability.
      <br/>
      At an advanced stage of inbreeding (i.e., F6 and F7), the best lines or mixtures of phenotypically similar lines are tested for potential release as new cultivars.
    </p>
    <p num="12">
      Mass and recurrent selections can be used to improve populations of either self- or cross-pollinating crops.
      <br/>
      A genetically variable population of heterozygous individuals is either identified or created by intercrossing several different parents.
      <br/>
      The best plants are selected based on individual superiority, outstanding progeny, or excellent combining ability.
      <br/>
      The selected plants are intercrossed to produce a new population in which further cycles of selection are continued.
    </p>
    <p num="13">
      Backcross breeding has been used to transfer genes for a simply inherited, highly heritable trait into a desirable homozygous cultivar or inbred line which is the recurrent parent.
      <br/>
      The source of the trait to be transferred is called the donor parent.
      <br/>
      The resulting plant is expected to have the attributes of the recurrent parent (e.g., cultivar) and the desirable trait transferred from the donor parent.
      <br/>
      After the initial cross, individuals possessing the phenotype of the donor parent are selected and repeatedly crossed (backcrossed) to the recurrent parent.
      <br/>
      The resulting plant is expected to have the attributes of the recurrent parent (e.g., cultivar) and the desirable trait transferred from the donor parent.
    </p>
    <p num="14">Descriptions of other breeding methods that are commonly used for different traits and crops can be found in one of several reference books (e.g., Allard, 1960; Simmonds, 1979; Sneep et al., 1979; Fehr, 1987).</p>
    <p num="15">
      Proper testing should detect any major faults and establish the level of superiority or improvement over current cultivars.
      <br/>
      In addition to showing superior performance, there must be a demand for a new cultivar that is compatible with industry standards or which creates a new market.
      <br/>
      The introduction of a new cultivar will incur additional costs to the seed producer, the grower, processor and consumer; for special advertising and marketing, altered seed and commercial production practices, and new product utilization.
      <br/>
      The testing preceding release of a new cultivar should take into consideration research and development costs as well as technical superiority of the final cultivar.
      <br/>
      For seed-propagated cultivars, it must be feasible to produce seed easily and economically.
    </p>
    <p num="16">
      Once the inbreds that give the best hybrid performance have been identified, the hybrid seed can be reproduced indefinitely as long as the homogeneity of the inbred parent is maintained.
      <br/>
      A single-cross hybrid is produced when two inbred lines are crossed to produce the F1 progeny.
      <br/>
      A double-cross hybrid is produced from four inbred lines crossed in pairs (A * B and C * D) and then the two F1 hybrids are crossed again (A * B) * (C * D).
      <br/>
      Much of the hybrid vigor exhibited by F1 hybrids is lost in the next generation (F2).
      <br/>
      Consequently, seed from hybrid varieties is not used for planting stock.
    </p>
    <p num="17">
      Corn is an important and valuable field crop.
      <br/>
      Thus, a continuing goal of plant breeders is to develop stable, high yielding corn hybrids that are agronomically sound.
      <br/>
      The reasons for this goal are obviously to maximize the amount of grain produced on the land used and to supply food for both animals and humans.
      <br/>
      To accomplish this goal, the corn breeder must select and develop corn plants that have the traits that result in superior parental lines for producing hybrids.
    </p>
    <heading>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="18">
      According to the invention, there is provided a novel inbred corn line, designated LH172Bt810.
      <br/>
      This invention thus relates to the seeds of inbred corn line LH172Bt810, to the plants of inbred corn line LH172Bt810 and to methods for producing a corn plant produced by crossing the inbred line LH172Bt810 with itself or another corn line.
      <br/>
      This invention further relates to hybrid corn seeds and plants produced by crossing the inbred line LH172Bt810 with another corn line.
    </p>
    <p num="19">
      The inbred corn plant of the invention may further comprise, or have, a cytoplasmic factor that is capable of conferring male sterility.
      <br/>
      Parts of the corn plant of the present invention are also provided, such as e.g., pollen obtained from an inbred plant and an ovule of the inbred plant.
    </p>
    <p num="20">
      In one aspect, the present invention provides for single gene converted plants of LH172Bt810.
      <br/>
      The single transferred gene may preferably be a dominant or recessive allele.
      <br/>
      Preferably, the single transferred gene will confer such traits as male sterility, herbicide resistance, insect resistance, resistance for bacterial, fungal, or viral disease, male fertility, enhanced nutritional quality, and industrial usage.
      <br/>
      The single gene may be a naturally occurring maize gene or a transgene introduced through genetic engineering techniques.
    </p>
    <p num="21">
      In another aspect, the present invention provides regenerable cells for use in tissue culture or inbred corn plant LH172Bt810.
      <br/>
      The tissue culture will preferably be capable of regenerating plants having the physiological and morphological characteristics of the foregoing inbred corn plant, and of regenerating plants having substantially the same genotype as the foregoing inbred corn plant.
      <br/>
      Preferably, the regenerable cells in such tissue cultures will be embryos, protoplasts, meristematic cells, callus, pollen, leaves, anthers, roots, root tips, silk, flowers, kernels, ears, cobs, husks or stalks.
      <br/>
      Still further, the present invention provides corn plants regenerated from the tissue cultures of the invention.
    </p>
    <heading>DEFINITIONS</heading>
    <p num="22">
      In the description and tables which follow, a number of terms are used.
      <br/>
      In order to provide a clear and consistent understanding of the specification and claims, including the scope to be given such terms, the following definitions are provided:
    </p>
    <p num="23">
      Predicted RM.
      <br/>
      This trait for a hybrid, predicted relative maturity (RM), is based on the harvest moisture of the grain.
      <br/>
      The relative maturity rating is based on a known set of checks and utilizes conventional maturity systems such as the Minnesota Relative Maturity Rating System.
    </p>
    <p num="24">
      MN RM. This represents the Minnesota Relative Maturity Rating (MN RM) for the hybrid and is based on the harvest moisture of the grain relative to a standard set of checks of previously determined MN RM rating.
      <br/>
      Regression analysis is used to compute this rating.
    </p>
    <p num="25">
      Yield (Bushels/Acre).
      <br/>
      The yield in bushels/acre is the actual yield of the grain at harvest adjusted to 15.5% moisture.
    </p>
    <p num="26">Moisture. The moisture is the actual percentage moisture of the grain at harvest.</p>
    <p num="27">
      GDU Silk. The GDU silk (=heat unit silk) is the number of growing degree units (GDU) or heat units required for an inbred line or hybrid to reach silk emergence from the time of planting.
      <br/>
      Growing degree units are calculated by the Barger Method, where the heat units for a 24-hour period are:  (Equation image '1' not included in text)
    </p>
    <p num="28">
      The highest maximum used is 86 (degree)  F. and the lowest minimum used is 50 (degree)  F. For each hybrid, it takes a certain number of GDUs to reach various stages of plant development.
      <br/>
      GDUs are a way of measuring plant maturity.
    </p>
    <p num="29">
      Stalk Lodging.
      <br/>
      This is the percentage of plants that stalk lodge, i.e., stalk breakage, as measured by either natural lodging or pushing the stalks determining the percentage of plants that break off below the ear.
      <br/>
      This is a relative rating of a hybrid to other hybrids for standability.
    </p>
    <p num="30">
      Root Lodging.
      <br/>
      The root lodging is the percentage of plants that root lodge; i.e., those that lean from the vertical axis at an approximate 30 (degree)  angle or greater would be counted as root lodged.
    </p>
    <p num="31">
      Plant Height.
      <br/>
      This is a measure of the height of the hybrid from the ground to the tip of the tassel, and is measured in centimeters.
    </p>
    <p num="32">
      Ear Height.
      <br/>
      The ear height is a measure from the ground to the ear node attachment, and is measured in centimeters.
    </p>
    <p num="33">
      Dropped Ears.
      <br/>
      This is a measure of the number of dropped ears per plot, and represents the percentage of plants that dropped an ear prior to harvest.
    </p>
    <p num="34">
      Allele. The allele is any of one or more alternative forms of a gene, all of which alleles relate to one trait or characteristic.
      <br/>
      In a diploid cell or organism, the two alleles of a given gene occupy corresponding loci on a pair of homologous chromosomes.
    </p>
    <p num="35">
      Backcrossing.
      <br/>
      Backcrossing is a process in which a breeder repeatedly crosses hybrid progeny back to one of the parents, for example, a first generation hybrid F1 with one of the parental genotypes of the F1 hybrid.
    </p>
    <p num="36">
      Essentially all the physiological and morphological characteristics.
      <br/>
      A plant having essentially all the physiological and morphological characteristics means a plant having the physiological and morphological characteristics, except for the characteristics derived from the converted gene.
    </p>
    <p num="37">
      Quantitative Trait Loci (QTL).
      <br/>
      Quantitative trait loci (QTL) refer to genetic loci that control to some degree numerically representable traits that are usually continuously distributed.
    </p>
    <p num="38">
      Regeneration.
      <br/>
      Regeneration refers to the development of a plant from tissue culture.
    </p>
    <p num="39">
      Single Gene Converted.
      <br/>
      Single gene converted or conversion plant refers to plants which are developed by a plant breeding technique called backcrossing wherein essentially all of the desired morphological and physiological characteristics of an inbred are recovered in addition to the single gene transferred into the inbred via the backcrossing technique or via genetic engineering.
    </p>
    <heading>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="40">Inbred corn line LH172Bt810 is a yellow dent corn with superior characteristics, and provides an excellent parental line in crosses for producing first generation (F1) hybrid corn.</p>
    <p num="41">
      LH172Bt810 was developed by using a Holden's third party licensee partially converted line containing the Bt gene at the BC2 stage as a non-recurrent parent to backcross the Bt gene into the LH172 genetic background.
      <br/>
      Molecular marker assays were used to select individual plants for advancement.
      <br/>
      Ear rows homozygous for the Bt810 trait were sampled for molecular marker evaluation.
      <br/>
      Utilizing the marker and phenotype comparison to the recurrent parent, individual families were selected and advanced.
    </p>
    <p num="42">Yield, stalk quality, root quality, disease tolerance, late plant greenness, late plant intactness, ear retention, pollen shedding ability, silking ability and corn borer tolerance were the criteria used to determine the rows from which ears were selected.</p>
    <p num="43">Inbred corn line LH172Bt810 has the following morphologic and other characteristics (based primarily on data collected at Williamsburg, Iowa).</p>
    <heading>VARIETY DESCRIPTION INFORMATION</heading>
    <p num="44">
      1.
      <br/>
      TYPE: Dent
      <br/>
      2.
      <br/>
      REGION WHERE DEVELOPED: Northcentral U.S.
      <br/>
      3. MATURITY:
    </p>
    <p num="45">
      --
      <br/>
      --
      <br/>
      --           Days Heat Units
      <br/>
      -- From emergence to 50% of plants in silk: 77     1552
      <br/>
      -- From emergence to 50% of plants in pollen 72     1448
      <br/>
      --   (Equation image '2' not included in text)
      <br/>
      4.
      <br/>
      PLANT:
    </p>
    <p num="46">
      Plant Height (to tassel tip): 158.0 cm (SD=6.40)
      <br/>
      Ear Height (to base of top ear): 65.8 cm (7.30)
      <br/>
      Average Length of Top Ear Internode: 12.9 cm (1.12)
      <br/>
      Average number of Tillers: 0 (0)
      <br/>
      Average Number of Ears per Stalk: 1.0 (0.0)
      <br/>
      Anthocyanin of Brace Roots: Absent
      <br/>
      5.
      <br/>
      LEAF:
      <br/>
      Width of Ear Node Leaf: 9.9 cm (0.65)
      <br/>
      Length of Ear Node Leaf: 71.0 cm (3.25)
      <br/>
      Number of leaves above top ear: 5 (0.60)
      <br/>
      Leaf Angle from 2nd Leaf above ear at anthesis to Stalk above leaf: 22 (degree)  (5.08)
      <br/>
      Leaf Color: Medium Green--Munsell Code 5 GY 4/8
      <br/>
      Leaf Sheath Pubescence (Rate on scale from 1=none to 9=like peach fuzz): 2
      <br/>
      Marginal Waves (Rate on scale from 1=none to 9=many): 3
      <br/>
      Longitudinal Creases (Rate on scale from 1=none to 9=many): 3
      <br/>
      6.
      <br/>
      TASSEL:
      <br/>
      Number of Lateral Branches: 8 (1.71)
      <br/>
      Branch Angle from Central Spike: 20 (degree)  (6.59)
      <br/>
      Tassel Length (from top leaf collar to tassel top): 30.1 cm (3.28)
      <br/>
      Pollen Shed (Rate on scale from 0=male sterile to 9=heavy shed): 7
      <br/>
      Anther Color: Purple--Munsell Code 5RP 5/4
      <br/>
      Glume Color: Medium green--Munsell Code 5GY 5/6
      <br/>
      Bar Glumes: Absent
      <br/>
      7a.
      <br/>
      EAR: (Unhusked Data)
      <br/>
      Silk Color (3 days after emergency): Light green--Munsell Code 2.5GY 8/8
      <br/>
      Fresh Husk Color (25 days after 50% silking): Light green--Munsell Code 2.5GY 7/8
      <br/>
      Dry Husk Color (65 days after 50% silking): Buff--Munsell Code 7.5YR 7/4
      <br/>
      Position of Ear: Upright
      <br/>
      Husk Tightness (Rate on scale from 1=very loose to 9=very tight): 5
      <br/>
      Husk Extension: Medium (&lt;8 cm)
      <br/>
      7b. EAR: (Husked Ear Data)
      <br/>
      Ear Length: 16.0 cm (1.65)
      <br/>
      Ear Diameter at mid-point: 44.9 mm (2.40)
      <br/>
      Ear Weight: 89.7 gm (20.58)
      <br/>
      Number of Kernel Rows: 16 (1.43)
      <br/>
      Kernel Rows: Distinct
      <br/>
      Row Alignment: Straight
      <br/>
      Shank Length: 8.9 cm (2.75)
      <br/>
      EarTaper: Average
      <br/>
      8.
      <br/>
      KERNEL: (Dried)
      <br/>
      Kernel Length: 10.6 mm (0.6)
      <br/>
      Kernel Width: 8.7 mm (0.7)
      <br/>
      Kernel Thickness: 5.2 mm (0.7)
      <br/>
      Round Kernels (Shape Grade): 42.5% (6.30)
      <br/>
      Aleurone Color Pattern: Homozygous
      <br/>
      Aleurone Color: White--Munsell Code 2.5Y 8/2
      <br/>
      Hard Endosperm Color: Yellow--Munsell Code 2.5Y 8/10
      <br/>
      Endosperm Type: Normal Starch
      <br/>
      Weight per 100 kernels: 27.3 gm (0.60)
      <br/>
      9. COB:
      <br/>
      Cob Diameter at Mid-Point: 33.4 mm (1.60)
      <br/>
      Cob Color: Red--Munsell code 1OR 3/6
      <br/>
      10.
      <br/>
      DISEASE RESISTANCE:
      <br/>
      Rating �1=(most susceptible) through 9=(most resistant)�
    </p>
    <p num="47">
      - 8 Anthracnose Leaf Blight (Colletotrichum graminicola)
      <br/>
      - 7 Eyespot (Kabatiella zeae)
      <br/>
      - 6 Gray Leaf Spot (Cercospora zeae-maydis)
      <br/>
      - 8 Helminthosporium Leaf Spot (Bipolaris zeicola) Race 3
      <br/>
      - 7 Northern Leaf Blight (Exserohilum turcicum) Race 1
      <br/>
      - 4 Southern Leaf Blight (Bipolaris maydis)
      <br/>
      11.
      <br/>
      AGRONOMIC TRAITS:
      <br/>
      - 6 Stay Green (at 65 days after anthesis) (Rate on scale from 1=worst to 9=excellent)
      <br/>
      - 0% Dropped Ears (at 65 days after anthesis)
      <br/>
      - 0% Pre-anthesis Brittle Snapping
      <br/>
      - 0% Pre-anthesis Root Lodging
      <br/>
      - 0% Post-anthesis Root Lodging (at 65 days after anthesis)
    </p>
    <p num="48">
      This invention is also directed to methods for producing a corn plant by crossing a first parent corn plant with a second parent corn plant, wherein the first or second corn plant is the inbred corn plant from the line LH172Bt810.
      <br/>
      Further, both first and second parent corn plants may be from the inbred line LH172Bt810.
      <br/>
      Therefore, any methods using the inbred corn line LH172Bt810 are part of this invention: selfing, backcrosses, hybrid breeding, and crosses to populations.
      <br/>
      Any plants produced using inbred corn line LH172Bt810 as a parent are within the scope of this invention.
      <br/>
      Advantageously, the inbred corn line is used in crosses with other corn varieties to produce first generation (F1) corn hybrid seed and plants with superior characteristics.
    </p>
    <p num="49">As used herein, the term "plant" includes plant cells, plant protoplasts, plant cell of tissue culture from which corn plants can be regenerated, plant calli, plant clumps, and plant cells that are intact in plants or parts of plants, such as pollen, flowers, kernels, ears, cobs, leaves, husks, stalks, and the like.</p>
    <p num="50">
      The present invention contemplates a corn plant regenerated from a tissue culture of an inbred (e.g., LH172Bt810) or hybrid plant of the present invention.
      <br/>
      As is well known in the art, tissue culture of corn can be used for the in vitro regeneration of a corn plant.
      <br/>
      By way of example, a process of tissue culturing and regeneration of corn is described in European Patent Application, publication 160,390, the disclosure of which is incorporated by reference.
      <br/>
      Corn tissue culture procedures are also described in Green &amp; Rhodes (1982) and Duncan, et al., (1985).
      <br/>
      The study by Duncan et al., (1985) indicates that 97 percent of cultured plants produced calli capable of regenerating plants.
      <br/>
      Subsequent studies have shown that both inbreds and hybrids produced 91 percent regenerable calli that produced plants.
    </p>
    <p num="51">
      Other studies indicate that non-traditional tissues are capable of producing somatic embryogenesis and plant regeneration.
      <br/>
      See, e.g., Songstad et al., (1988); Rao et al., (1986); and Conger et al., (1987), the disclosures of which are incorporated herein by reference.
      <br/>
      Regenerable cultures may be initiated from immature embryos as described in PCT publication WO 95/06128, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference.
    </p>
    <p num="52">Thus, another aspect of this invention is to provide for cells which upon growth and differentiation produce the inbred line LH172Bt810.</p>
    <p num="53">
      LH172Bt810 is similar to LH172, however, there are numerous differences including the plant color.
      <br/>
      LH172Bt810 is lighter green in plant color than LH172.
      <br/>
      When using the Munsell Color Charts for Plant Tissues as a reference, LH172Bt810 would be classified as 5GY 4/8 and LH172 would be classified as 5GY 4/6.
    </p>
    <p num="54">
      Some of the criteria used to select ears in various generations include: yield, stalk quality, root quality, disease tolerance, late plant greenness, late season plant intactness, ear retention, pollen shedding ability, silking ability, and corn borer tolerance.
      <br/>
      During the development of the line, crosses were made to inbred testers for the purpose of estimating the line's general and specific combining ability, and evaluations were run by the Williamsburg, Iowa Research Station.
      <br/>
      The inbred was evaluated further as a line and in numerous crosses by the Williamsburg and other research stations across the Corn Belt.
      <br/>
      The inbred has proven to have a very good combining ability in hybrid combinations.
    </p>
    <p num="55">
      The inbred has shown uniformity and stability.
      <br/>
      It has been self-pollinated and ear-rowed a sufficient number of generations, with careful attention to uniformity of plant type to ensure homozygosity and phenotypic stability.
      <br/>
      The line has been increased both by hand and sibbed in isolated fields with continued observations for uniformity.
      <br/>
      No variant traits have been observed or are expected in LH172Bt810.
    </p>
    <heading>TABLES</heading>
    <p num="56">
      In the tables that follow, the traits and characteristics of inbred corn line LH172Bt810 are given in hybrid combination.
      <br/>
      The data collected on inbred corn line LH172Bt810 is presented for the key characteristics and traits.
      <br/>
      The tables present yield test information about LH172Bt810.
      <br/>
      LH172Bt810 was tested in several hybrid combinations at numerous locations, with two or three replications per location.
      <br/>
      Information about these hybrids, as compared to several check hybrids, is presented.
    </p>
    <p num="57">
      The first pedigree listed in the comparison group is the hybrid containing LH172Bt810.
      <br/>
      Information for the pedigree includes:
    </p>
    <p num="58">
      1.
      <br/>
      Mean yield of the hybrid across all locations.
    </p>
    <p num="59">2. A mean for the percentage moisture (% M) for the hybrid across all locations.</p>
    <p num="60">3. A mean of the percentage of plants with stalk lodging (% Stalk) across all locations.</p>
    <p num="61">4. A mean of the percentage of plants with root lodging (% Root) across all locations.</p>
    <p num="62">
      The series of hybrids listed under the hybrid containing LH172Bt810 are considered check hybrids.
      <br/>
      The check hybrids are compared to hybrids containing the inbred LH172Bt8 O.
    </p>
    <p num="63">
      The (+) or (-) sign in front of each number in each of the columns indicates how the mean values across plots of the hybrid containing inbred LH172Bt810 compare to the check crosses.
      <br/>
      A (+) or (-) sign in front of the number indicates that the mean of the hybrid containing inbred LH172Bt810 was greater or lesser, respectively, than the mean of the check hybrid.
      <br/>
      For example, a +4 in yield signifies that the hybrid containing inbred LH172Bt810 produced 4 bushels more corn than the check hybrid.
      <br/>
      If the value of the stalks has a (-) in front of the number 2, for example, then the hybrid containing the inbred LH172Bt810 had 2% less stalk lodging than the check hybrid.
    </p>
    <p num="64">
      -- TABLE 1
      <br/>
      -- COMPARISON OF
      <br/>
      -- LH172Bt810  *  LH198 vs.
      <br/>
      LH172  *  LH198
      <br/>
      --                Mean Yield  % M         % Stalk % Root
      <br/>
      --      Difference  +4     +0.05  0       0
      <br/>
      --      Locations   22          22          22      22
    </p>
    <p num="65">
      -- TABLE 2
      <br/>
      -- COMPARISON OF
      <br/>
      -- LH172Bt810  *  LH202 vs.
      <br/>
      LH172  *  LH202
      <br/>
      --                Mean Yield  % M         % Stalk % Root
      <br/>
      --      Difference  +6     +0.08  0       +1
      <br/>
      --      Locations   20          20          20      20
    </p>
    <p num="66">
      -- TABLE 3
      <br/>
      -- COMPARISON OF
      <br/>
      -- LH172Bt810  *  HC33 vs.
      <br/>
      LH172  *  HC33
      <br/>
      --                Mean Yield  % M         % Stalk % Root
      <br/>
      --      Difference  -2    +0.07  0       -1
      <br/>
      --      Locations   32          32          32      32
    </p>
    <p num="67">
      When the term inbred corn plant is used in the context of the present invention, this also includes any single gene conversions of that inbred.
      <br/>
      The term single gene converted plant as used herein refers to those corn plants which are developed by a plant breeding technique called backcrossing wherein essentially all of the desired morphological and physiological characteristics of an inbred are recovered in addition to the single gene transferred into the inbred via the backcrossing technique.
      <br/>
      Backcrossing methods can be used with the present invention to improve or introduce a characteristic into the inbred.
      <br/>
      The term backcrossing as used herein refers to the repeated crossing of a hybrid progeny back to one of the parental corn plants for that inbred.
      <br/>
      The parental corn plant which contributes the gene for the desired characteristic is termed the nonrecurrent or donor parent.
      <br/>
      This terminology refers to the fact that the nonrecurrent parent is used one time in the backcross protocol and therefore does not recur.
      <br/>
      The parental corn plant to which the gene or genes from the nonrecurrent parent are transferred is known as the recurrent parent as it is used for several rounds in the backcrossing protocol (Poehlman &amp; Sleper, 1994; Fehr, 1987).
      <br/>
      In a typical backcross protocol, the original inbred of interest (recurrent parent) is crossed to a second inbred (nonrecurrent parent) that carries the single gene of interest to be transferred.
      <br/>
      The resulting progeny from this cross are then crossed again to the recurrent parent and the process is repeated until a corn plant is obtained wherein essentially all of the desired morphological and physiological characteristics of the recurrent parent are recovered in the converted plant, in addition to the single transferred gene from the nonrecurrent parent.
    </p>
    <p num="68">
      The selection of a suitable recurrent parent is an important step for a successful backcrossing procedure.
      <br/>
      The goal of a backcross protocol is to alter or substitute a single trait or characteristic in the original inbred.
      <br/>
      To accomplish this, a single gene of the recurrent inbred is modified or substituted with the desired gene from the nonrecurrent parent, while retaining essentially all of the rest of the desired genetic, and therefore the desired physiological and morphological, constitution of the original inbred.
      <br/>
      The choice of the particular nonrecurrent parent will depend on the purpose of the backcross, one of the major purposes is to add some commercially desirable, agronomically important trait to the plant.
      <br/>
      The exact backcrossing protocol will depend on the characteristic or trait being altered to determine an appropriate testing protocol.
      <br/>
      Although backcrossing methods are simplified when the characteristic being transferred is a dominant allele, a recessive allele may also be transferred.
      <br/>
      In this instance it may be necessary to introduce a test of the progeny to determine if the desired characteristic has been successfully transferred.
    </p>
    <p num="69">
      Many single gene traits have been identified that are not regularly selected for in the development of a new inbred but that can be improved by backcrossing techniques.
      <br/>
      Single gene traits may or may not be transgenic, examples of these traits include but are not limited to, male sterility, waxy starch, herbicide resistance, resistance for bacterial, fungal, or viral disease, insect resistance, male fertility, enhanced nutritional quality, industrial usage, yield stability and yield enhancement.
      <br/>
      These genes are generally inherited through the nucleus.
      <br/>
      Some known exceptions to this are the genes for male sterility, some of which are inherited cytoplasmically, but still act as single gene traits.
      <br/>
      Several of these single gene traits are described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,777,196, the disclosure of which is specifically hereby incorporated by reference.
      <br/>
      A further aspect of the invention relates to tissue culture of corn plants designated LH172Bt810.
      <br/>
      As used herein, the term "tissue culture" indicates a composition comprising isolated cells of the same or a different type or a collection of such cells organized into parts of a plant.
      <br/>
      Exemplary types of tissue cultures are protoplasts, calli, plant clumps, and plant cells that can generate tissue culture that are intact in plants or parts of plants, such as embryos, pollen, flowers, kernels, ears, cobs, leaves, husks, stalks, roots, root tips, anthers, silk and the like.
      <br/>
      In a preferred embodiment, tissue culture is embryos, protoplast, meristematic cells, pollen, leaves or anthers.
      <br/>
      Means for preparing and maintaining plant tissue culture are well known in the art.
      <br/>
      By way of example, a tissue culture comprising organs such as tassels or anthers, has been used to produce regenerated plants. (See U.S. Pat. No. 5,445,961 and U.S. Pat. No. 5,322,789, the disclosures of which are incorporated herein by reference).
    </p>
    <heading>DEPOSIT INFORMATION</heading>
    <p num="70">Inbred seeds of LH172Bt810 have been placed on deposit with the American Type Culture Collection (ATCC), Manassas, Va., under Deposit Accession Number on PTA-169, on Jun. 3, 1999. A Plant Variety Protection Certificate is being applied for with the United States Department of Agriculture.</p>
    <p num="71">Although the foregoing invention has been described in some detail by way of illustration and example for purposes of clarity and understanding, it will be obvious that certain changes and modifications may be practiced within the scope of the invention, as limited only by the scope of the appended claims.</p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>What is claimed is:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1.</claim-text>
      <claim-text>An inbred corn seed designated LH172Bt810, wherein a sample of said seed has been deposited under ATCC Accession No. PTA-169.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="2">
      <claim-text>2. A corn plant, or its parts, produced by growing the seed of claim 1.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="3">
      <claim-text>3. Pollen of the plant of claim 2.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="4">
      <claim-text>4. An ovule of the plant of claim 2.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="5">
      <claim-text>5. A corn plant having all of the physiological and morphological characteristics of the corn plant of claim 2, or its parts.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="6">
      <claim-text>6. Tissue culture of the seed of claim 1.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="7">
      <claim-text>7. A corn plant regenerated from the tissue culture of claim 6, wherein said corn plant is capable of expressing all the physiological and morphological characteristics of inbred corn line LH172Bt810.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="8">
      <claim-text>8. Tissue culture of regenerable cells of the plant, or its parts, of claim 2.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="9">
      <claim-text>9. The tissue culture of claim 8, wherein the regenerable cells are from embryos, meristematic cells, pollen, leaves, anthers, roots, root tips, silk, flower, kernels, ears, cobs, husks, stalks, protoplasts derived therefrom or calli derived therefrom.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="10">
      <claim-text>10. A corn plant regenerated from the tissue culture of claim 9, wherein said corn plant is capable of expressing all the physiological and morphological characteristics of inbred corn line LH172Bt810.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="11">
      <claim-text>11. A method for producing a hybrid corn seed comprising crossing a first inbred parent corn plant with a second inbred parent corn plant and harvesting the resultant hybrid corn seed, wherein said first or second parent corn plant is the corn plant of claim 2.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="12">
      <claim-text>12. A hybrid corn seed produced by the method of claim 11.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="13">
      <claim-text>13. A hybrid corn plant, or its parts, produced by growing said hybrid corn seed of claim 12.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="14">
      <claim-text>14. Corn seed produced by growing said hybrid corn plant of claim 13.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="15">
      <claim-text>15. A corn plant, or its parts, produced from seed of claim 14.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="16">
      <claim-text>16. A method for producing a hybrid corn seed comprising crossing an inbred plant according to claim 2 with another, different corn plant.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="17">
      <claim-text>17. A hybrid corn seed produced by the method of claim 16.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="18">
      <claim-text>18. A hybrid corn plant, or its parts, produced by growing said hybrid corn seed of claim 17.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="19">
      <claim-text>19. Corn seed produced from said hybrid corn plant of claim 18.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="20">
      <claim-text>20. A corn plant, or its parts, produced from the corn seed of claim 19.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="21">
      <claim-text>21. The corn plant of claim 5, further comprising a single gene conversion.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="22">
      <claim-text>22. The corn plant of claim 21, further comprising a cytoplasmic factor conferring male sterility.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="23">
      <claim-text>23. The single gene conversion of the corn plant of claim 21, where the gene is a gene which is introduced by transgenic methods.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="24">
      <claim-text>24. The single gene conversion of the corn plant of claim 21, where the gene is a dominant allele.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="25">
      <claim-text>25. The single gene conversion of the corn plant of claim 21, wherein the gene is a recessive allele.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="26">
      <claim-text>26. The single gene conversion corn plant of claim 21, where the gene confers herbicide resistance.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="27">
      <claim-text>27. The single gene conversion of the corn plant of claim 21, where the gene confers insect resistance.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="28">
      <claim-text>28. The single gene conversion of the corn plant of claim 21, where the gene confers resistance to bacterial, fungal, or viral disease.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="29">
      <claim-text>29. The single gene conversion of the corn plant of claim 21, where the gene confers male sterility.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="30">
      <claim-text>30. The single gene conversion of the corn plant of claim 21, where the gene confers waxy starch.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>