<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06186461B1.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as first publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06186461</doc-number>
        <kind>B1</kind>
        <date>20010213</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6186461</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B1</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference is-representative="YES" family-id="23270124" extended-family-id="42114796">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>09325946</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19990604</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>1999US-09325946</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>43173545</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>32594699</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19990604</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>1999US-09325946</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010213</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>B43K  23/00        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>B</section>
        <class>43</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>23</main-group>
        <subgroup>00</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="2">
        <text>B43K  23/12        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>B</section>
        <class>43</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>23</main-group>
        <subgroup>12</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>248314000</text>
        <class>248</class>
        <subclass>314000</subclass>
      </main-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="1">
        <text>206214000</text>
        <class>206</class>
        <subclass>214000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="2">
        <text>224219000</text>
        <class>224</class>
        <subclass>219000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <classifications-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="1">
        <text>B43K-023/00B2</text>
        <section>B</section>
        <class>43</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>023</main-group>
        <subgroup>00B2</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="2">
        <text>B43K-023/12</text>
        <section>B</section>
        <class>43</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>23</main-group>
        <subgroup>12</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
    </classifications-ecla>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>B43K-023/002</classification-symbol>
        <section>B</section>
        <class>43</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>23</main-group>
        <subgroup>002</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
      <patent-classification sequence="2">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>B43K-023/12</classification-symbol>
        <section>B</section>
        <class>43</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>23</main-group>
        <subgroup>12</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6186461</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Marker pen holder</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="1">
          <text>HELMUTH RIEPE</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>3315644</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US3315644</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="2">
          <text>HAYDUCHOK LEON</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5163549</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5163549</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="3">
          <text>TUCKER RICHARD B C</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5332090</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5332090</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="4">
          <text>ALEXANDER K</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5372252</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5372252</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="5">
          <text>FEDER EMIL</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5628400</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5628400</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="6">
          <text>CASSEL DOUGLAS</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5823363</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5823363</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>PELAEZ PEDRO R.</name>
          </addressbook>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Pelaez, Pedro R.</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Miami, FL, 33016, US</address-1>
              <city>Miami</city>
              <state>FL</state>
              <postcode>33016</postcode>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
      <agents>
        <agent sequence="1" rep-type="agent">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Sanchelima, J.</name>
          </addressbook>
        </agent>
      </agents>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>Ramirez, Ramon O.</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>LAPSED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      A holder for marker pens that keep the latter readily available for use while providing a relatively sealed compartment that prevents or minimize the circulation of air around the tip of the pen.
      <br/>
      The housing has slanted walls that provide structural stability to the holder when it holds one or more pens.
      <br/>
      An opening in the housing includes upper and lower cavities with a slanted portion inbetween acting as a seal for the end of the tubular housing of a pen.
      <br/>
      As step in the lower cavity further reduces its diameter ensuring the further isolation of the pen's tip thus protecting from the frying action of circulating air.
      <br/>
      Portable embodiments for use with a user's belt permit ready access to pens for an ambulatory user.
      <br/>
      One of these embodiments includes a removable pen holder member.
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <p num="1">II. BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</p>
    <p num="2">
      1.
      <br/>
      Field of the Invention
    </p>
    <p num="3">The present invention relates to a marker pen holder.</p>
    <p num="4">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
    <p num="5">
      Many designs for a pen holder exist nowadays.
      <br/>
      However, none of them disclose the novel feature of the present invention.
      <br/>
      The present invention discloses a marker pen holder that has such a design that substitutes the covering cap for the marking tip while holding in place the pen marker.
      <br/>
      This is a very convenient feature for users of pens, such as markers, since it avoids the need to take off and replace the cap constantly.
    </p>
    <p num="6">III. SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</p>
    <p num="7">It is one of the main objects of the present invention to provide a marker pen holder that has such a design that cooperatively and snugly houses the marking/writing tip of a pen marker.</p>
    <p num="8">It is another object of this invention to provide a marker pen holder that holds vertically a marker pen on a flat surface.</p>
    <p num="9">It is another object of this invention to eliminate using the cap, so that it does not have to be removed and replaced constantly.</p>
    <p num="10">It is another object of this invention to provide a marker pen holder that holds a marker pen substantially vertically while being carried on a belt.</p>
    <p num="11">It is still another object of the present invention to provide a holder that prevents the tip from drying up.</p>
    <p num="12">It is yet another object of this invention to provide such a device that is inexpensive to manufacture and maintain while retaining its effectiveness.</p>
    <p num="13">Further objects of the invention will be brought out in the following part of the specification, wherein detailed description is for the purpose of fully disclosing the invention without placing limitations thereon.</p>
    <p num="14">
      IV. BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS
      <br/>
      With the above and other related objects in view, the invention consists in the details of construction and combination of parts as will be more fully understood from the following description, when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings in which:
      <br/>
      FIG. 1 is an isometric view of a marker pen stationary holder with a marker pen in phantom.
      <br/>
      FIG. 2 is a partial cross-sectional view of the present invention.
      <br/>
      FIG. 3 is an isometric view of an alternate embodiment for this invention, having a marker pen holder mounted on a belt.
      <br/>
      FIG. 4 is an isometric view of another alternate embodiment for the invention as shown in FIG. 3.
      <br/>
      FIG. 4a elevational view of a removable holder member used with the alternate embodiment shown in FIG. 4.
    </p>
    <p num="15">V. DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</p>
    <p num="16">
      Referring now to the drawings, where the present invention is generally referred to with numeral 10, it can be observed that it basically includes body 20 with openings 40 disposed adjacent to each other.
      <br/>
      Pen holder 10 can have one or more openings similar to openings 40.
      <br/>
      The preferred embodiment shown has two openings 40.
    </p>
    <p num="17">
      As illustrated in FIGS. 1, marker pen holder 10 has a truncated configuration defined by slanted lateral walls 22, upper wall 24 and bottom wall 26.
      <br/>
      This is intended to provide stability to the combination of holder 10 and pen P.
    </p>
    <p num="18">
      Openings 40 start on upper wall 24 and extend perpendicularly inwardly.
      <br/>
      As best seen in FIG. 2, openings 40 include upper cavity 42 and lower cavity 44.
      <br/>
      Most conventional marker pens have a tubular shape with a rounded termination R next to the tip assembly T. Termination R rests on slanted portion 43 of cavity 42 substantially conforming to it.
      <br/>
      Upper cavity 42 has slanted portion 43 that connects cavity 42 with cavity 44.
      <br/>
      Cavity 44 includes inner step 45 that further reduces the diameter of cavity 44 providing a second resting area for the end of tip assembly T of pen P which is typically larger than the tip member T' of pen P.
    </p>
    <p num="19">In this manner, holder 10 provides two seating areas that substantially conform to the outer tubular dimensions of pen P to prevent circulation of air tending to dry tip member T' while at the same time pen P is readily available for use.</p>
    <p num="20">
      Alternate embodiments are shown in FIGS. 3 and 4 and being generally referred to with numerals 10' and 10".
      <br/>
      Cavities 40' and 40" are similar to cavities 40, in the stationary holder 10.
      <br/>
      The embodiment shown in FIG. 3 includes base member 60' with loop member 50' on one surface and the other surface has pen holder body 20' mounter thereon.
      <br/>
      Also, optional gripping member 70' is cooperatively positioned above opening 40' to secure pen P in place.
    </p>
    <p num="21">
      The embodiment shown in FIG. 4 and referred to with numeral 10" does not use a gripping member.
      <br/>
      Holder body 20" is mounted to one surface of base member 60".
      <br/>
      Opening 61" on base member 60" provides access to tubular pen holder member 66" which is removably mounted to opening 40".
      <br/>
      Member 66" has internal characteristics similar to upper and lower cavities 42 and 44 as well as slanted portion 43, and these are labeled 62", 64", and 63", respectively, in FIG. 4a for the respective outer out walls (the internal cross-section not being shown).
      <br/>
      Belt loop member 50" also functions like belt loop member 50'. Similarly, flange 67" has cooperative dimensions to rest on upper wall 24" suspending member 66" within holder body 20".
    </p>
    <p num="22">
      The foregoing description conveys the best understanding of the objectives and advantages of the present invention.
      <br/>
      Different embodiments may be made of the inventive concept of this invention.
      <br/>
      It is to be understood that all matter disclosed herein is to be interpreted merely as illustrative, and not in a limiting sense.
    </p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>What is claimed is:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1.</claim-text>
      <claim-text>A marker pen holder, comprising a marker pen, a housing body having a flat bottom and cylindrical opening including upper and lower cavities, said upper cavity having a diameter larger than the diameter of said lower cavity, and further including a slanted portion of said opening to make the transition from said upper cavity to said lower cavity with a smaller diameter than the diameter of said upper cavity and said slanted portion having cooperative dimensions to serve as a resting area for the tubular end of said marker pen that includes a tip that protrudes inside said lower cavity, so that said slanted portion and pen combination prevent the circulation of air to said lower cavity housing said tip, and further including a substantially flat member with two surfaces and said housing body being mounted to one of said surfaces, and further including a belt loop on said other surface for cooperatively receiving a belt.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="2">
      <claim-text>2. The marker holder set forth in claim 1 wherein said housing body has a truncated shape with bottom and top walls, spaced apart from each other, and said cylindrical opening being substantially perpendicular to said top and bottom walls.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="3">
      <claim-text>3. A marker pen holder comprising:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>A) a marker pen; B) a housing defining an inner space and an upper wall with on opening; C) a flat base member having first and second surfaces, and said housing being mounted to said first surface, said second surface including a loop member having cooperative dimensions to receive a user's belt; D) a substantially cylindrical holder member mounted within said housing and connecting to said opening and said holder member including an upper cavity, a lower cavity and a slanted portion inbetween so that the diameter of said lower cavity is smaller than the diameter of said upper cavity and said slanted portion having cooperative dimensions to serve as a resting area for the tubular end of said marker pen surrounding its tip that protrudes inside said lower cavity and the slanted portion and marker pen combination prevent the circulation of air to said lower cavity housing the tip of said marker pen.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="4">
      <claim-text>4. The marker pen holder set forth in claim 3 further including: D) gripping mans mounted to said first surface at a cooperative spaced apart relationship with respect to said housing so that the pen holder outside said housing is removably secured by said gripping means.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>