<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06184334B2.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as second publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06184334</doc-number>
        <kind>B2</kind>
        <date>20010206</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6184334</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B2</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference is-representative="YES" family-id="23628280" extended-family-id="1483454">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>09411274</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19991004</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>1999US-09411274</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>1542287</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>41127499</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19991004</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>1999US-09411274</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010206</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>C08G  64/30        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>C</section>
        <class>08</class>
        <subclass>G</subclass>
        <main-group>64</main-group>
        <subgroup>30</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>528196000</text>
        <class>528</class>
        <subclass>196000</subclass>
      </main-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="1">
        <text>528198000</text>
        <class>528</class>
        <subclass>198000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <classifications-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="1">
        <text>C08G-064/30F</text>
        <section>C</section>
        <class>08</class>
        <subclass>G</subclass>
        <main-group>064</main-group>
        <subgroup>30F</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
    </classifications-ecla>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>C08G-064/307</classification-symbol>
        <section>C</section>
        <class>08</class>
        <subclass>G</subclass>
        <main-group>64</main-group>
        <subgroup>307</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>22</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>0</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>0</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6184334</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Alkali metal salts of oxoacids of sulfur as polymerization catalysts</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="1">
          <text>UBE INDUSTRIES</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>JP</country>
            <doc-number>H0753704</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>JP07053704</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <nplcit num="1">
          <text>McCloskey et al., "Salts of Chelating Agents as Polymerization Catalysts", S.N. 09/451,033, filed Nov. 29, 1999.</text>
        </nplcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <nplcit num="2">
          <text>McCloskey et al., "Salts of Non-Volatile Acids as Polymerization Catalysts", S.N. 09/497,398, filed on Feb. 4, 2000.</text>
        </nplcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <nplcit num="3">
          <text>MCloskey et al., "Salts of Aryl Sulfonic Acids as Polymerization Catalysts", S.N. 09/546,597, filed on Apr. 10, 2000.</text>
        </nplcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant data-format="original" app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>General Electric Company</orgname>
            <address>
              <address-1>Schenectady, NY, US</address-1>
              <city>Schenectady</city>
              <state>NY</state>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
        <applicant data-format="questel" app-type="applicant" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>GENERAL ELECTRIC</orgname>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>McCloskey, Patrick Joseph</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Watervliet, NY, US</address-1>
              <city>Watervliet</city>
              <state>NY</state>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Burnell, Timothy Brydon</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Niskayuna, NY, US</address-1>
              <city>Niskayuna</city>
              <state>NY</state>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="3">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Smigelski, Jr., Paul Michael</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Schenectady, NY, US</address-1>
              <city>Schenectady</city>
              <state>NY</state>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
      <agents>
        <agent sequence="1" rep-type="agent">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Johnson, Noreen C.</name>
          </addressbook>
        </agent>
        <agent sequence="2" rep-type="agent">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Stoner, Douglas E.</name>
          </addressbook>
        </agent>
      </agents>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>Boykin, Terressa M.</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>GRANTED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      The present invention relates to a method for the preparation of polycarbonate comprising preparing a polycarbonate by a melt process by reacting a diphenol and a diaryl carbonate in the presence of a catalytically effective amount of one or more alkali metal salts of oxoacids of sulfur.
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <heading>FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="1">
      This invention relates to alkali metal salts of oxoacids of sulfur useful as catalysts in melt polymerizations.
      <br/>
      The invention further relates to polycarbonates prepared using alkali metal salts of oxoacids of sulfur and articles made from these polycarbonates.
    </p>
    <heading>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="2">
      Conventional industrial plants synthesize polycarbonate by mixing together an aqueous solution of dihydric compound (e.g., bisphenol-A) with an organic solvent (e.g., dichloromethane) containing a carbonyl halide (e.g., phosgene).
      <br/>
      Upon mixing the immiscible organic and aqueous phases, the dihydric compound reacts with the carbonyl halide at the phase interface.
      <br/>
      Typically, a phase transfer catalyst, such as a tertiary amine, is added to the aqueous phase to enhance this reaction.
      <br/>
      This synthesis method is commonly known as the "interfacial" synthesis method for preparing polycarbonate.
    </p>
    <p num="3">
      The interfacial method for making polycarbonate has several inherent disadvantages.
      <br/>
      First it is a disadvantage to operate a process which requires phosgene as a reactant due to obvious safety concerns.
      <br/>
      Second it is a disadvantage to operate a process which requires using large amounts of an organic solvent because expensive precautions must be taken to guard against any adverse environmental impact.
      <br/>
      Third, the interfacial method requires a relatively large amount of equipment and capital investment.
      <br/>
      Fourth, the polycarbonate produced by the interfacial process is prone to having inconsistent color, higher levels of particulates, and higher chlorine content, which can cause corrosion.
    </p>
    <p num="4">
      Some new commercial polycarbonate plants synthesize polycarbonate by a transesterification reaction whereby a diester of carbonic acid (e.g., diphenylcarbonate) is condensed with a dihydric compound (e.g., bisphenol-A).
      <br/>
      This reaction is performed without a solvent, and is driven to completion by mixing the reactants under reduced pressure and high temperature with simultaneous distillation of the phenol produced by the reaction.
      <br/>
      This synthesis technique is commonly referred to as the "melt" technique.
      <br/>
      The melt technique is superior over the interfacial technique because it does not employ phosgene, it does not require a solvent, and it uses less equipment.
      <br/>
      Moreover, the polycarbonate produced by the melt process does not contain chlorine contamination from the reactants, has lower particulate levels, and has a more consistent color.
      <br/>
      Therefore it is highly desirable to use the melt technique in a commercial manufacturing process.
    </p>
    <p num="5">
      In the production of polycarbonates by the melt polymerization process, alkali metal hydroxides, in particular sodium hydroxide, are used as polymerization catalysts.
      <br/>
      While alkali metal hydroxides are useful polymerization catalysts, they also effect side reactions which results in branched side reaction products.
      <br/>
      This causes changes in the melt behavior of the polycarbonate, which can lead to difficulties in processing.
    </p>
    <p num="6">It would be desirable, therefore, to develop a catalysts system which effects melt polymerization while minimizing undesirable reaction products, such as branched side reaction products.</p>
    <heading>DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="7">The present invention addresses these concerns and provided further surprising properties.</p>
    <p num="8">The present invention may be understood more readily by reference to the following detailed description of preferred embodiments of the invention and the examples included therein.</p>
    <p num="9">
      Before the present compositions of matter and methods are disclosed and described, it is to be understood that this invention is not limited to specific synthetic methods or to particular formulations, as such may, of course, vary.
      <br/>
      It is also to be understood that the terminology used herein is for the purpose of describing particular embodiments only and is not intended to be limiting.
    </p>
    <p num="10">In the following specification, reference will be made to a number of terms which shall be defined to have the following meanings:</p>
    <p num="11">The singular forms "a", "an" and "the" include plural referents unless the context clearly dictates otherwise. "Optional" or "optionally" means that the subsequently described event or circumstance may or may not occur, and that the description includes instances where the event occurs and instances where it does not.</p>
    <p num="12">As used herein, the term "melt polycarbonate" refers to a polycarbonate made by the transesterification of a carbonate diester with a dihydroxy compound.</p>
    <p num="13">"BPA" is herein defined as bisphenol A or 2,2-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)propane.</p>
    <p num="14">The terms "diphenol" and "dihydric phenol" as used herein are synonymous.</p>
    <p num="15">
      In the present invention, it was unexpectedly found that the use of alkali metal salts of oxoacids of sulfur as polymerization catalysts reduces side reaction products, including "Fries" product and other branched side reaction products.
      <br/>
      The reduction of these products provides the advantages of increased ductility, and prevent the reduction of rheological properties which results when undesirable side reaction products, such as Fries product, are present.
      <br/>
      It was further unexpectedly found that for a given set of conditions, the alkali metal salt of an oxoacid of sulfur; such as sodium metabisulfite, as described in the present invention, produced less Fries than alkali metal hydroxides, such as sodium hydroxide.
    </p>
    <p num="16">
      Specifically, the present invention provides a catalyst system for the production of polycarbonate by the melt process, wherein the polycarbonate has a reduced content of undesirable branched side reaction product, in particular Fries products.
      <br/>
      In particular, it is desirable to have Fries product of less than 1000 ppm, preferably less than 900 ppm, more preferably less than 500 ppm, even more preferably less than 200 ppm.
    </p>
    <p num="17">
      Polycarbonate produced by the melt process typically has higher Fries content than polycarbonates produced by the interfacial method.
      <br/>
      As used herein the term "Fries" or "fries" refers to a repeating unit in polycarbonate having the following formula (I):  (Chemical Structure image '1' not included in text)
    </p>
    <p num="18">
      Variable Rc and Rd each independently represent a hydrogen atom or a monovalent hydrocarbon group and may form a ring structure.
      <br/>
      Variable Rc is a divalent hydrocarbon group.
    </p>
    <p num="19">
      It is very desirable to have a low Fries content in the polycarbonate product, as Fries products reduce the performance characteristics of the polycarbonate, such as the ductility.
      <br/>
      Higher Fries contents results in lower ductility.
      <br/>
      Preparing polycarbonate by the melt process results in the formation of Fries products.
    </p>
    <p num="20">
      The present invention relates to melt polymerization catalysts in a melt polymerization system in which a dihydric phenol and a diester of carbonic acid are reacted.
      <br/>
      Dihydric phenols which are useful in preparing the polycarbonate of the invention may be represented by the general formula  (Chemical Structure image '2' not included in text)
    </p>
    <p num="21">wherein:</p>
    <p num="22">
      R is independently selected from halogen, monovalent hydrocarbon, and monovalent hydrocarbonoxy radicals;
      <br/>
      R1 is independently selected from halogen, monovalent hydrocarbon, and monovalent hydrocarbonoxy radicals:
      <br/>
      W is selected from divalent hydrocarbon radicals,  (Chemical Structure image '3' not included in text)
      <br/>
      n and n1 are independently selected from integers having a value of from 0 to 4 inclusive; and
      <br/>
      b is either zero or one.
    </p>
    <p num="23">
      The monovalent hydrocarbon radicals represented by R and R1 include the alkyl, cycloalkyl, aryl, aralkyl and alkaryl radicals.
      <br/>
      The preferred alkyl radicals are those containing from 1 to about 12 carbon atoms.
      <br/>
      The preferred cycloalkyl radicals are those containing from 4 to about 8 ring carbon atoms.
      <br/>
      The preferred aryl radicals are those containing from 6 to 12 ring carbon atoms, i.e., phenyl, naphthyl, and biphenyl.
      <br/>
      The preferred alkaryl and aralkyl radicals are those containing from 7 to about 14 carbon atoms.
    </p>
    <p num="24">The preferred halogen radicals represented by R and R1 are chlorine and bromine.</p>
    <p num="25">
      The divalent hydrocarbon radicals represented by include the alkylene, alkylidene, cycloalkylene and cycloalkylidene radicals.
      <br/>
      The preferred alkylene radicals are those containing from 2 to about 30 carbon atoms.
      <br/>
      The preferred alkylidene radicals are those containing from 1 to about 30 carbon atoms.
      <br/>
      The preferred cycloalkylene and cycloalkylidene radicals are those containing from 6 to about 16 ring carbon atoms.
    </p>
    <p num="26">
      The monovalent hydrocarbonoxy radicals represented by R and R1 may be represented by the formula--OR2 wherein R2 is a monovalent hydrocarbon radical of the type described hereinafore.
      <br/>
      Preferred monovalent hydrocarbonoxy radicals are the alkoxy and aryloxy radicals.
    </p>
    <p num="27">
      Suitable dihydric phenols include, but are not limited to, BPA; 2,2-bis(3,5-dibromo-4-hydroxyphenyl)propane; 2,2-bis(3,5-dimethyl-4-hydroxyphenyl)propane; 1,1-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)cyclohexane; 1,1-bis(3,5-dimethyl-4-hydroxyphenyl)cyclohexane; 1,1-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)decane; 1,1-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)propane; 1,1-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)cyclodecane; 1,1-bis(3,5-dimethyl-4-hydroxyphenyl)cyclododecane; 4,4-dihydroxyphenyl ether; 4,4-thiodiphenol; 4-4-dihydroxy-3,3-dichlorodiphenyl ether; 4,4-thiodiphenol; 4,4-dihydroxy-3,3-dichlorodiphenyl ether; 4,4-dihydroxy-2,5-dihydroxydiphenyl ether; BPI; 1,1-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)-1-phenylethane; 1,1-bis(3-methyl-4-hydroxyphenyl)-1-phenylethane, and mixtures thereof.
      <br/>
      In one embodiment, the residues of dihydric phenol in the polycarbonate comprise 100 mol % of residues derived from BPA.
    </p>
    <p num="28">
      Optionally, polyfunctional compounds may be utilized.
      <br/>
      Suitable polyfunctional compounds used in the polymerization of branched polycarbonate include, but are not limited to,
      <br/>
      1,1,1-tris(4-hydroxyphenyl)ethane,
      <br/>
      4-�4-�1,1-bis(4-hydroxyphenyl)-ethyl�-dimethylbennzyl�,
      <br/>
      trimellitic anhydride,
      <br/>
      trimellitic acid, or their acid chloride derivatives.
    </p>
    <p num="29">
      As the diester of carbonic acid, various compounds may be used, including, but not limited to diaryl carbonate compounds, dialkyl carbonate compounds and alkylaryl carbonate compounds.
      <br/>
      Suitable diesters of carbonic acid include, but are not limited to, diphenyl carbonate; bis(4-t-butylphenyl)carbonate; bis(2,4-dichlorophenyl)carbonate; bis(2,4,6-trichlorphenyl)carbonate; bis(2-cyanophenyl)carbonate; bis(o-nitrophenyl)carbonate; ditolyl carbonate; m-cresol carbonate; dinaphthyl carbonate; bis(diphenyl)carbonate; diethylcarbonate; dimethyl carbonate; dibutyl carbonate; dicyclohexyl carbonate; and mixtures thereof.
      <br/>
      Of these, diphenyl carbonate is preferred.
      <br/>
      If two or more of these compound are utilized, it is preferable that one is diphenyl carbonate.
    </p>
    <p num="30">
      In the process of the present invention, an endcapping agent may optionally be used.
      <br/>
      Suitable endcapping agents include monovalent aromatic hydroxy compounds, haloformate derivatives of monovalent aromatic hydroxy compounds, monovalent carboxylic acids, halide derivatives of monovalent carboxylic acids, and mixtures thereof.
    </p>
    <p num="31">Suitable endcapping agents include, but are not limited to phenol, p-tert-butylphenol; p-cumylphenol; p-cumylphenolcarbonate; undecanoic acid, lauric acid, stearic acid; phenyl chloroformate, t-butyl phenyl chloroformate, p-cumyl chloroformate, chroman chloroformate, octyl phenyl; nonyl phenyl chloroformate or a mixture thereof.</p>
    <p num="32">If present, the endcapping agent is preferably present in amounts of about 0.01 to about 0.20 moles, preferably about 0.02 to about 0.15 moles, even more preferably about 0.02 to about 0.10 moles per 1 mole of the dihydric phenol.</p>
    <p num="33">
      In the process of the present invention, the catalyst system comprises at least one alkali metal salt of an oxo acid of sulfur. "Catalyst system" as used herein refers to the catalyst or catalysts that catalyze the transesterification of the dihydric phenol and the carbonic acid diester in the melt process.
      <br/>
      Alkali metal salts of oxo acids of sulfur which are suitable as melt polymerization catalysts include, but are not limited to sodium sulfite, sodium bisulfite, sodium metabisulfite, sodium thiosulfate, sodium dithionite, and mixtures thereof; preferably sodium sulfite, sodium metabisulfite and mixture thereof, even more preferably sodium metabisulfite.
      <br/>
      It is most preferable that the alkali metal constituent be sodium for the lowest branching side product formation.
      <br/>
      In one embodiment, the catalyst system consists of sodium metal salts of oxoacids of sulfur.
      <br/>
      It is further preferable that the catalyst system contain little or no sodium sulfate or other alkali metal salts of sulfuric acid.
      <br/>
      Although sodium sulfate and other alkali metal salts of sulfuric acid are not detrimental to the system, they do not produce the preferred molecular weight build.
    </p>
    <p num="34">
      The alkali metal salt of an oxoacid of sulfur is preferably used in an amount of from 10-8 to 10-3 moles of catalyst per 1 mole of dihydric phenol compound, more preferably 10-7 to 10-5 moles of catalyst per 1 mole of dihydric phenol compound.
      <br/>
      When the amount is less than 10-8 mol, there is the possibility that catalyst activity is not exhibited.
      <br/>
      When the amount is greater than 10-3 moles per 1 mole of dihydric phenol, the properties of the final polycarbonate product may be adversely affected.
    </p>
    <p num="35">
      The catalyst may be added in a variety of forms.
      <br/>
      The catalyst may be added as a solid, for example a powder, or it may be dissolved in a solvent, for example water or alcohol.
      <br/>
      In one embodiment, the catalysts is added to the reaction system in the form of an aqueous solution.
      <br/>
      The pH of the aqueous solution is preferably at or near the pH of a freshly prepared solution, which varies depending on the oxo sulfur acid salt which is used as the catalyst.
      <br/>
      For example, the pH of an aqueous solution of sodium sulfite is preferably in a range of from about 8 to about 9; while the pH of an aqueous solution of sodium metabisulfite is preferably in a ringe of from about 3 to about 4.2, more preferably from about 2.5 to about 4, even more preferably at about 3.0 to about 3.2.
    </p>
    <p num="36">
      The oxo sulfur acid salts range from mildly acidic to mildly basic depending on the salt when initially dissolved in water, and tend to become more acidic over time as the result of their instability in water.
      <br/>
      In a range of pH, these catalyts become more selective at reducing Fries, and eventually reduced activity as polymerization catalysts.
      <br/>
      This provides a means for self quenching at the end of the process.
      <br/>
      These catalysts are also reducing agents, and therefore result in less color that sodium hydroxide.
    </p>
    <p num="37">
      As the aqueous solution becomes more acidic, the catalyst becomes more selective, however the molecular weight of the resultant product decreases.
      <br/>
      The desired molecular weight of the product depends on the intended use.
      <br/>
      For example, for optical materials, the number average molecular weight of the product is preferably in the range of about 7,500 to about 9,000; while for sheet materials the number average molecular weight is preferably in the range of about 25,000 to about 30,000.
      <br/>
      Therefore, it may be desirable to approach more acidic pHs in the synthesis of polycarbonate materials relatively low molecular weights, for example, optical materials.
      <br/>
      It is preferable that the pH of the aqueous catalyst solution be maintained above about 2.4.
    </p>
    <p num="38">
      In addition to the alkali metal salt of the oxo sulfur acid, the catalyst system may optionally comprise a quaternary ammonium salt and/or a phosphonium catalyst.
      <br/>
      Examples of suitable quaternary ammonium salts include, but are not limited to ammonium hydroxides having alkyl groups, aryl groups and alkaryl groups, such as teramethylammonium hydroxide (TMAH) and tetrabutylammonium hydroxide (TBAH).
    </p>
    <p num="39">
      If present, the quaternary ammonium salt and/or phosphonium catalyst are preferably present in amounts of from 10-2 to about 10-6, preferably 10-2 to 10-5 moles per 1 mole of dihydric phenol compound, in addition to the alkali metal salt of oxoacid of sulfur.
      <br/>
      Further, alkali metal hydroxides may optionally be present in the catalyst system.
    </p>
    <p num="40">
      The reaction conditions of the melt polymerization are not particularly limited and may be conducted in a wide range of operating conditions.
      <br/>
      The reaction temperature is typically in the range of about 100 to about 350 (degree)  C., more preferably about 180 to about 310 (degree)  C. The pressure may be at atmospheric, or at an added pressure of from atmospheric to about 15 torr in the initial stages of the reaction, and at a reduced pressure at later stages, for example in the range of about 0.2 to about 15 torr.
      <br/>
      The reaction time is generally about 0.1 hours to about 10 hours.
    </p>
    <p num="41">
      Additives may also be added to the polycarbonate product as long as they do not adversely affect the properties of the product.
      <br/>
      These additives include a wide range of substances that are conventionally added to the polycarbonates for a variety of purposes.
      <br/>
      Specific examples include heat stabilizers, epoxy compounds, ultraviolet absorbers, mold release agents, colorants, antistatic agents, slipping agents, anti-blocking agents, lubricants, antifogging agents, natural oils, synthetic oils, waxes, organic fillers, flame retardants, inorganic fillers and any other commonly known class of additives.
    </p>
    <p num="42">
      The reaction can be conducted as a batch or a continuous process.
      <br/>
      Any desired apparatus can be used for the reaction.
      <br/>
      The material and the structure of the reactor used in the present invention is not particularly limited as long as the reactor has an ordinary capability of stirring.
      <br/>
      It is preferable that the reactor is capable of stirring in high viscosity conditions as the viscosity of the reaction system is increased in later stages of the reaction.
    </p>
    <p num="43">
      As an additional advantage, unlike the strongly alkaline alkali earth metal hydroxides, such as sodium hydroxide, the catalyts of the present invention are mildly acidic to only slightly basic.
      <br/>
      As a result, the addition of a catalyst quenching agent is not necessary, but may be added optionally.
      <br/>
      Typical catalyst quenching agents used with sodium hydroxide include, but are not limited to, strong sulfur or phosphorous acids.
      <br/>
      Strong acids hurt hydrolytic stability.
    </p>
    <p num="44">The polycarbonate obtained in accordance with the present invention may be used after being mixed with conventional additives, such as plasticizers, pigments, lubricants, mold release agents, stabilizers and organic fillers.</p>
    <p num="45">It is also possible to blend the polycarbonate with other polymers, including but not limited to, polyolefins, polystyrenes, polysulfonates, polyamides and polyphenylene ethers.</p>
    <heading>EXAMPLES</heading>
    <p num="46">
      The following examples are set forth to provide those of ordinary skill in the are with a complete description of how the compositions of matter and methods claimed herein are made and evaluated, and are not intended to limit the scope of what the inventors regard as their invention.
      <br/>
      Efforts have been made to insure accuracy with respect to numbers (e.g., amounts, temperature, etc.) but some errors and deviations should be accounted for.
      <br/>
      Unless indicated otherwise, parts are by weight, temperature is in  (degree)  C.
    </p>
    <p num="47">
      Molecular weights are reported as number average (Mn) and were determined by GPC analysis of polycarbonate prepared by melt polymerization.
      <br/>
      Standards of polystyrene were used to construct a universal calibration against which polycarbonate could be measured using the Mark-Houwink equation.
      <br/>
      The temperature of the columns was 25 (degree)  C. and the mobile phase was chloroform.
    </p>
    <p num="48">
      Fries content was measured by the KOH methanolysis of resin and is reported as parts per million (ppm).
      <br/>
      The content of Fries for each of the melt polycarbonates listed in Table 1 was determined as follows.
      <br/>
      First, 0.50 grams of polycarbonate was dissolved in 4.0 ml of THF (containing p-terphenyl as internal standard).
      <br/>
      Next, 3.0 ml of 18% KOH in methanol was added to this solution.
      <br/>
      The resulting mixture was stirred for two hours at this temperature.
      <br/>
      Next, 1.0 ml of acetic acid was added, and the mixture was stirred for 5 minutes.
      <br/>
      Potassium acetate was allowed to crystallize over 1 hour.
      <br/>
      The solid was filtered off and the resulting filtrate was analyzed by liquid chromoatograph using p-terphenyl as the internal standard.
    </p>
    <p num="49">The pH as set forth in Table 1 are the pHs for solution of 0.005 M in water, and are for a new bottle of reagent, except for samples 5 and 6.</p>
    <p num="50">
      -- TABLE 1
      <br/>
      -- Sample  Catalyst      Formula   PH      Mn   Fries
      <br/>
      -- 1       Sodium        NaOH      11.60   8252      2763
      <br/>
      --         hydroxide
      <br/>
      -- 2       Sodium        Na2 SO3  9.0     8706       941
      <br/>
      --         sulfite
      <br/>
      -- 3       Sodium        NaHSO3  4.33    8203       830
      <br/>
      --         bisulfite
      <br/>
      -- 4       Sodium        Na2 S2 O5  4.27    8459       484
      <br/>
      --         metabisulfite
      <br/>
      -- 5       Sodium        Na2 S2 O5  4.06    9020       680
      <br/>
      --         metabisulfite
      <br/>
      -- 6       Sodium        Na2 S2 O5  3.24    8208       138
      <br/>
      --         metabisulfite
      <br/>
      -- 7       Sodium        Na2 S2 O5  2.20    No build
      <br/>
      --         metabisulfite
      <br/>
      -- 8       Potassium     K2 S2 O5  4.41    8484      3139
      <br/>
      --         thiosulfate
      <br/>
      -- 9       Sodium        Na2 S2 O3  5.62    9415      1489
      <br/>
      --         thiosulfate
      <br/>
      -- 10  Sodium        Na2 S2 O4  3.25    7727       458
      <br/>
      --         dithionite
      <br/>
      -- 11  Sodium        Na2 SO4  5.80    2151       70
      <br/>
      --         sulfate
      <br/>
      -- *12  TMAH only                       1430       62
      <br/>
      -- *In sample 12, TMAH by itself added as a catalyst, 2.5  *  10-4
      <br/>
      --  moles TMAH/mole BPA
    </p>
    <p num="51">
      The following is a description of how the preparation was prepared for sample 1 in Table.
      <br/>
      The remaining samples were prepared by an otherwise identical procedure using the other catalysts listed in Table 1 except as noted.
    </p>
    <p num="52">Synthesis of Sample 1</p>
    <p num="53">
      The following reactions were carried out in a 1 liter glass batch reactor equipped with a solid nickel helical agitator.
      <br/>
      The glass reactor surface was passivated by acid washing, rinsing, and subsequently drying overnight at 70 (degree)  C. and stored covered until use.
    </p>
    <p num="54">
      The temperature of the reactor was maintained using a fluidized sand bath with a PID controller and measured near the reactor and sand bath interface.
      <br/>
      The pressure of the reactor was controlled by a nitrogen bleed into the vacuum pump downstream of the distillate collection flasks and measured at higher pressures (760 mm Hg to 40 mm Hg) with a mercury barometer, and at lower pressures (40 mm Hg to 1 mm Hg) with an Edward pirani gauge.
    </p>
    <p num="55">
      The reactor was charged with 0.6570 mol BPA and 0.7096 mol diphenyl carbonate prior to assembly.
      <br/>
      The reactor was then assembled, sealed and the atmosphere was exchanged with nitrogen three times.
      <br/>
      With the final nitrogen exchange, the reactor was brought to about atmospheric pressure and submerged into the fluidized bath which was at 180 (degree)  C. After five minutes, agitation was begun at 250 rpm.
      <br/>
      After an additional ten minutes, the reactants were fully melted and a homogeneous mixture was assumed.
      <br/>
      Tetramethyl ammonium hydroxide (TMAH, 1.32 * 10-4 mol) and sodium hydroxide (NaOH, 5.00 * 10-7 mol) were added sequentially after being diluted to the proper concentrations (0.220 M TMAH and 5.00 * 10-3 M NaOH) with 18 Mohm water.
      <br/>
      After the final catalyst was added, timing began, and the temperature was ramped to 210 (degree)  C. in five minutes.
      <br/>
      Once at temperature, the pressure was reduced to 180 mm Hg and phenol distillate was immediately formed.
      <br/>
      After 25 minutes, the pressure was again reduced to 100 mm Hg and maintained for 45 minutes.
    </p>
    <p num="56">
      The temperature was then ramped to 240 (degree)  C. in five minutes and the pressure was lowered to 15 mm Hg.
      <br/>
      These conditions were maintained for 45 minutes.
      <br/>
      The temperature was then ramped to 270 (degree)  C. in five minutes and the pressure was lowered to 2 mm Hg.
      <br/>
      These conditions were maintained for 10 minutes.
      <br/>
      The temperature was then ramped to the final finishing temperature in five minutes and the pressure was reduced to 1.1 mm Hg. The finishing temperature was 310 (degree)  C. After 30 minutes, the reactor was removed from the sand bath and the melt was extruded into liquid nitrogen to quench the reaction.
    </p>
    <p num="57">
      The results in Table 1 clearly illustrate the effectiveness of the alkali metal salts of oxo sulfur acids as melt polymerization catalysts as compared to sodium hydroxide.
      <br/>
      It was further observed that after initial preparation of the aqueous solution, the aqueous solution became gradually more acidic over time.
      <br/>
      The pH of sample 4 is for a new bottle of reagent.
      <br/>
      The pH of sample 5 is the pH of the reagent after standing for four days.
      <br/>
      The pH of sample 6 is the pH of the reagent after standing for 6 days.
    </p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>What is claimed is:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1.</claim-text>
      <claim-text>A method for the preparation of polycarbonate by the melt process comprising</claim-text>
      <claim-text>a) heating, in one or more stages, a mixture comprising a diphenol and a diarylcarbonate;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and b) introducing into the mixture of a), in the same stage or different stages a catalytically effective amount of one or more alkali metal salts of oxoacids of sulfur.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="2">
      <claim-text>2. The method of claim 1, wherein the alkali metal salt of the oxo sulfur acid is selected from the group consisting of sodium sulfite, sodium bisulfite, sodium metabisulfite, sodium thiosulfate, sodium dithionate and a mixture thereof.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="3">
      <claim-text>3. The method of claim 1, wherein the oxo sulfur acid is sodium metabisulfite.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="4">
      <claim-text>4. The method of claim 1, wherein the oxo sulfur acid is sodium bisulfite.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="5">
      <claim-text>5. The method of claim 1, wherein the diphenol is bisphenol A.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="6">
      <claim-text>6. The method of claim 1, wherein a catalytically effective amount of TMAH, TBPH or a mixture thereof is present in step a).</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="7">
      <claim-text>7. A method for the preparation of polycarbonate comprising a) heating, in one or more stages, a mixture comprising a diphenol and a diarylcarbonate;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and b) introducing into the mixture of a), in the same stage or different stages 1) a catalytically effective amount of one or more alkali metal salts of oxoacids of sulfur and 2) a catalytically effective amount of a base selected from the group consisting of TMAH, TBPH and a mixture thereof.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="8">
      <claim-text>8. The method of claim 7, wherein the alkali metal salt of the oxoacid of sulfur is selected from the group from the group consisting of sodium sulfite, sodium bisulfite, sodium metabisulfite, sodium thiosulfite, sodium dithionate and a mixture thereof.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="9">
      <claim-text>9. The method of claim 7, wherein the diphenol is bisphenol A.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="10">
      <claim-text>10. The method of claim 7, wherein the oxo sulfur acid is sodium metabisulfite.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="11">
      <claim-text>11. The method of claim 7, wherein the oxoacids of sulfur is sodium bisulfite.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="12">
      <claim-text>12. The method of claim 7, wherein the catalytically effective amount of TMAH, TBPH or a mixture thereof is present in step a).</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="13">
      <claim-text>13. A method of reducing the Fries content of a polycarbonate comprising a) heating, in one or more stages, a mixture comprising a diphenol and a diarylcarbonate;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and b) introducing into the mixture of a), in the same stage or different stages a catalytically effective amount of one or more alkali metal salts of oxoacids of sulfur.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="14">
      <claim-text>14. The method of claim 13, wherein the alkali metal salt of the oxoacid of sulfur is selected from the group consisting of sodium sulfite, sodium bisulfite, sodium metabisulfite, sodium thiosulfite, sodium dithionate and a mixture thereof.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="15">
      <claim-text>15. The method of claim 13, wherein a catalytically effective amount of TMAH, TBPH or a mixture thereof is present in step a).</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="16">
      <claim-text>16. A polycarbonate prepared by the method of claim 13.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="17">
      <claim-text>17. A polycarbonate prepared by the method of claim 1.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="18">
      <claim-text>18. A polycarbonate prepared by the method of claim 7.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="19">
      <claim-text>19. The method of claim 13, wherein the diphenol is bisphenol A.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="20">
      <claim-text>20. The method of claim 13, wherein the Fries content of the polycarbonate is less than 1000 ppm.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="21">
      <claim-text>21. The method of claim 13, wherein the Fries content of the polycarbonate is less than 500 ppm.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="22">
      <claim-text>22. A method for the preparation of polycarbonate comprising a) heating, in one or more stages, a mixture comprising BPA and diphenylcarbonate;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and b) introducing into the mixture of a), in the same stage or different stages a catalytically effective amount of sodium metabisulfite.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>