<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06195226B1.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as first publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06195226</doc-number>
        <kind>B1</kind>
        <date>20010227</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6195226</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B1</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference family-id="7825181" extended-family-id="13365889">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>09053456</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19980401</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>1998US-09053456</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>13648642</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>DE</country>
        <doc-number>19713528</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19970401</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>1997DE-1013528</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010227</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>G11B  19/20        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>11</class>
        <subclass>B</subclass>
        <main-group>19</main-group>
        <subgroup>20</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="2">
        <text>H02K  21/24        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>H</section>
        <class>02</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>21</main-group>
        <subgroup>24</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="3">
        <text>H02K  29/00        20060101A N20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>H</section>
        <class>02</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>29</main-group>
        <subgroup>00</subgroup>
        <classification-value>N</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>360099080</text>
        <class>360</class>
        <subclass>099080</subclass>
      </main-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="1">
        <text>G9B019028</text>
        <class>G9B</class>
        <subclass>019028</subclass>
      </further-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <classifications-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="1">
        <text>G11B-019/20A</text>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>11</class>
        <subclass>B</subclass>
        <main-group>019</main-group>
        <subgroup>20A</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="2">
        <text>H02K-021/24</text>
        <section>H</section>
        <class>02</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>21</main-group>
        <subgroup>24</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
    </classifications-ecla>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>H02K-021/24</classification-symbol>
        <section>H</section>
        <class>02</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>21</main-group>
        <subgroup>24</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
      <patent-classification sequence="2">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>G11B-019/2009</classification-symbol>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>11</class>
        <subclass>B</subclass>
        <main-group>19</main-group>
        <subgroup>2009</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6195226</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Disk storage device</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="1">
          <text>SCHUH BERNHARD</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5424887</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5424887</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="2">
          <text>ELSAESSER DIETER, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5446610</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5446610</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="3">
          <text>ELSAESSER DIETER, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5774302</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5774302</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="4">
          <text>ELSAESSER DIETER, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>RE34412</doc-number>
            <kind>E</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>USRE34412</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="5">
          <text>HEINZMANN W, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>3845339</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US3845339</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="6">
          <text>ELSAESSER DIETER, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>4519010</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US4519010</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="7">
          <text>PAPST MINEBEA DISC MOTOR GMBH</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>DE</country>
            <doc-number>4238886</doc-number>
            <kind>A1</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>DE4238886</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant data-format="original" app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>Papst Licensing GmbH &amp; Co., KG</orgname>
            <address>
              <address-1>DE</address-1>
              <country>DE</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>DE</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
        <applicant data-format="questel" app-type="applicant" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>EBM PAPST</orgname>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>DE</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Papst, Hans Dieter</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Spaichingen, DE</address-1>
              <city>Spaichingen</city>
              <country>DE</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>DE</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
      <agents>
        <agent sequence="1" rep-type="agent">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>Welsh &amp; Katz, Ltd.</orgname>
          </addressbook>
        </agent>
      </agents>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>Letscher, George J.</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>EXPIRED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      The invention relates to a disk storage device having a direct-driving motor for a hub, which has one or two plane air gaps, whereby information storage disks fixed to a hub and located in an operation chamber rotate so as to store data and whereby optical and/or magnetic write/read heads are provided for reading or writing the data on the information carrier disks, whereby the hub of the information carrier disks and the write/read heads are supported together with their driving units on a device chassis or on a device cover plate and whereby the motor driving the hub is a collectorless DC motor having the permanent magnets at the part of the rotor and an ironless disk winding adjacent to the air gap or air gaps, whereby the soft magnetic yoke parts are provided with collar-like stiffening projections (FIG. 1).
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <p num="1">
      The present invention relates to a disk storage device according to the characteristic clause of claim 1 and a process for production of such a disk storage device.
      <br/>
      The invention relates especially to disk storage devices with one or several disk-like information carriers that are fixed or fixable to a rotatable hub and housed in an operation chamber of a device chassis, which is enclosed from the surroundings so as to write or read data by means of optical or magnetic write/read heads that can be moved across the information carriers.
    </p>
    <p num="2">
      Disk storage devices have an operation chamber with a reduced contamination, where at least one disk rotates.
      <br/>
      This invention relates especially to hard disk drives with a spotlessly clean operation chamber, as there the silence in operation of the motor is especially sensitive to the function of the device.
    </p>
    <p num="3">
      Because of the compactness that is required to an extreme extent, driving motors with flat air gaps would be desired for such a type of device.
      <br/>
      However, a "Pan-Cake-Motor" with a flat air gap and with a given small axial size and a large diameter in a way has a mechanical softness in the axial direction, through which it is very susceptible for vibrations in this region.
      <br/>
      That particularly disturbes, in combination with magnetic motor forces, the operation of the write/read heads.
      <br/>
      This is the main reason, why direct drive motors with a flat air gap have not got a chance in hard disk storage devices, yet.
      <br/>
      The cylindric air gap motor has a natural precedence because of the extreme requirements of compactness, accuracy, silence in operation and noise.
    </p>
    <p num="4">
      A corrective measure is not given yet, when the magnetic yoke is allowed to co-rotate.
      <br/>
      This is better, of course, than when the magnetic yoke disk would be stationary.
      <br/>
      In this case, the axial forces that act between the fixed and the rotating magnetic yoke would also be added.
      <br/>
      Moreover, a stationary magnetic yoke means eddy current losses (that are considerable, when the number of revolutions is up to 10.000 rpm for hard disk drives), and these eddy current losses cause braking.
      <br/>
      To suppress these eddy current losses one could use for instance a core of coiled up layers that is configured as a stationary magnetic yoke, but that would be extravagant An alternative to the suppression of the eddy current would be ferritic magnetic yoke portions.
      <br/>
      A ferritic magnetic yoke means also reduced eddy current losses.
      <br/>
      By this, on the contrary, the losses due to the hysteresis cannot be avoided, however, they may be relatively low in case of materials that are suitable to ferritic sintered components.
    </p>
    <p num="5">
      There is a force action between the winding and the rotor, which has an effect on the winding or the winding support (stator side) and the rotating permanent magnet, respectively, the magnetic yoke--but in a reduced manner also in that case, when the latter co-rotates on both sides of the air gap, and these forces go into the bearing in any case.
      <br/>
      The bearing seat of a disk storage device is disadvantageously loaded against these partly considerable axial forces.
      <br/>
      A main source of these forces are the pulse-like commutation currents in the winding coils.
    </p>
    <p num="6">
      Therefore, according to the invention, it is proposed to design the stator /rotor symmetrically in relation to a plane perpendicular to the rotation axis.
      <br/>
      Then, these forces cancel each other and do not load the bearing.
    </p>
    <p num="7">By further embodying this invention, variants are proposed that are suitable to product engineering, i.e. at a relatively reasonable price, which have, together with a symmetric construction as far as possible in the above mentioned sense, respectively, together with a cheaper asymmetric construction, possibilities to avoid or substantially reduce these pulse-like axial forces, which generally originate from the current pulses in the windings and which are transmitted to the bearing.</p>
    <p num="8">For this purpose it is planned to make the magnetic yoke portions stiff against axial deformations in such a manner, that the ocurring, disturbing exciting forces will be damped, also, if it is possible, compensated, respectively, prevented.</p>
    <p num="9">The following measures serve for this purpose alternatively or cumulatively:</p>
    <p num="10">
      a) to provide an edge that is bent up in the axial direction into the hub radially at the inner edge of the upper rotating magnetic yoke (steel) plate, so that the upper magnetic yoke of the rotor, if it is formed as a deep-drawn portion with an outer edge directing to the bottom, has preferably an S-shaped cross section between the rotation center and the outer circumferential edge.
      <br/>
      This would be the rotor portion of the permanent magnet, Oil whose flat ring shaped disk middle part at its bottom the axially magnetized rotor magnet is provided;
    </p>
    <p num="11">b) if the lower flat disk shaped magnetic yoke is allowed to co-rotate, it should be supported on the bent down outer edge of this rotor pot, however the disk shaped winding should be supported radially on the inner edge;</p>
    <p num="12">c) on the lower magnetic yoke radially at the inner edge also a bent up collar should be provided;</p>
    <p num="13">d) the inner collar at the lower magnetic yoke is bent up into the region of the stator disk winding, perhaps over and above it.</p>
    <p num="14">e) If the lower magnetic yoke rotates according d), then it is supported on the inner edge of the collar and the disk winding is mounted on its outer edge.</p>
    <p num="15">
      FIGS. 1-4 show embodiments of this invention.
      <br/>
      FIG. 1 shows a construction with an arrangement that is completely symmetric to the heavy broken middle plane M. On both sides of the disk-shaped stator winding permanent magnetic disks rotate together with a soft magnetic yoke.
      <br/>
      (In order to balance the disturbing forces completely symmetrically, however, only one arrangement would be suitable, where the broken middle line plane M is in addition substituted by a yoke plate of a soft magnetic type, which runs in this plane and has identical, mirror inverted windings arranged on both of its sides and that must additionally be fed synchronously with the current, as there are, in spite of the otherwise existing symmetry of the construction, different current forces acting on the conductors at the same time in case of for instance a single layer winding with several for instance air-core disk coils, as illustrated here in FIG. 1, as for instance the magnetic field, as shown in FIG. 1, coming from a permanent magnet goes through one of the air gaps, penetrates the disk shaped winding and then goes through the other air gap in the same direction in the other permanent magnet.
      <br/>
      In case of the just mentioned complete symmetry, these axially opposing permanent magnets must have oppositely directed magnetic fields somewhere in the plane, and then the magnetic field, coming from the permanent magnets, goes, symmetrically mirrored to the middle plane M, in the there proposed magnetic yoke plate. Such a complete symmetric balancing of a disk motor drive would be desired for a disk storage device, but, obviously, there would be a lot of extravagance.)
      <br/>
      Therefore, the illustrated FIG. 1 is already a first economic compromise.
      <br/>
      FIG. 2 shows a further simplification, whereby the lower rotating magnetic yoke without a permanent magnet is supported at the upper magnetic yoke, respectively, at its collar, whereas the stator disk is mounted on the inner side.
      <br/>
      FIG. 3 shows a mounting device for the disk-shaped stator at the outer edge together with a rotating lower magnetic yoke that has no permanent magnet on it, whereby both of the magnetic yoke disks have bent up collars at their inner circumferential edge that are joined with the hub.
      <br/>
      FIG. 4 shows a further step of an economic compromise with a stationary magnetic yoke.
      <br/>
      The disk-shaped windings, which are fixed at their inner--or outer edge, may also be integrated in a continous, flat, enclosed printed circuit board that is made preferably of plastics, whereby a certain self-stiffness gives a considerable advantage. This flat stator may also be realized with a printed winding embedded in plastics or, of course, with one or several layer windings together with disk-shaped coils, as already disclosed (DE-PS 25 33 187).
    </p>
    <p num="16">The FIGS. 1-4 show for one of the possible embodiments the construction of the disk storage drive with a hub rotating in a spotlessly clean room, whereby always a stationary shaft is employed in such a so called under-hub-design, i.e. the hub portion that supports the storage disks is arranged anally above the air gap of the driving motor.</p>
    <p num="17">
      Of course, the invention is not confined to this kind of disk storage device, however, it is certainly an advantageous variant.
      <br/>
      The invention can also be employed for disk storage devices according to DE-PS 29 44 212 or DE-OS 35 19 824.
    </p>
    <p num="18">When such a collar-like bending is provided at the circumferential edge, then the result is a greater silence in operation, as these edges that are bent up to some extent towards the inside of the motor, may cause a symmetric force balancing or relieving of the bearings by stiffening up this element.</p>
    <p num="19">
      When the stator side magnetic yoke is subdivided as coiled up layers or when it is made of ferrite so as to prevent eddy currents and braking, then the heat generating is reduced and/or the above mentioned currents1.
      <br/>
      Because of that, the pure magnetic hysteresis losses cannot be prevented, however, they can be impeded by means of a suitable selection of the material.
    </p>
    <p num="20">1 Translator: the German version reads Stromungen=currents, but it should read Storungen=disturbations.</p>
    <p num="21">If in case of a stationary magnetic yoke one manages to compensate the asymmetric unbalanced forces in the inside of the motor, then one could additionally manage or reduce this asymmetric unbalance by bent up edges or lobes of the stator iron.</p>
    <p num="22">
      However, independently of that, there are the axial exciting forces, which originate from the electromotoric action.
      <br/>
      Against that the formation of the magnetic yoke iron in the axial direction has to be made stiff, respectively, the magnetic yoke iron has to be provided with additional damping means through layer arrangement, for instance one has to employ a sandwich magnetic yoke sheet.
      <br/>
      Such additional damping measures combined with maximum axial stiffening are advantageous to several problem cases.
    </p>
    <p num="23">
      In case of a rotating or stationary magnetic yoke, the high axial stiffness serves also for the magnetic balancing, and at the same time and furthermore, that results in a favorable shielding.
      <br/>
      Additionally, in case of a disk motor, a labyrinth seal is provided at the lower edge of the bearing system, especially in case of a stationary shaft in the center.
      <br/>
      This labyrinth seal can be designed very effectively, as there is enough space.
      <br/>
      Especially the cylindric collar surfaces are effective labyrinth seal elements due to a minimum distance.
    </p>
    <p num="24">
      A drastic further advantage may be the possibility to increase the axial compactness substantially.
      <br/>
      For instance the labyrinth seal elements can extend in axial direction into the hub and therefore into the region of the lower ball bearing, where there is a sufficient cross section of the hub material.
      <br/>
      That complements very advantageously with a bent up collar radially at the inner edge of the rotor pot.
    </p>
    <p num="25">
      FIG. 1 shows a section of a hard disk storage device, where its upper cover (1) and chassis (2) is outlined.
      <br/>
      The chassis (2) or frame sits on an encircling edge of a tank flange (3) and in its center a stationary shaft (13) is pressed in a thickening of this tank (3).
    </p>
    <p num="26">
      At the upper end of this stationary shaft (13) there are two ball bearings (11/12), on which a hub rotates.
      <br/>
      At the supporting surfaces (9 and 10) of the hub information disks (5) are clamped via adapters by means of a holding shell (6) by screw means.
      <br/>
      The stator disk that is substantially made of plastics sits together with the integrated winding (22) on the shoulder (23) of the flange shell (3) by means of an inner holding device and extends symmetrically into a space between two permanent magnetic disks (24 and 26) that rotate on both sides of it, so that plane air gaps are formed.
      <br/>
      These permanent magnetic disks close the magnetic circuit via the magnetic yokes (25 and 27).
    </p>
    <p num="27">
      The upper magnetic yoke portion2 (25) is formed as a deep drawn portion in a bell-shaped or cup-shaped manner and has on its lower edge a groove, on which the lower flat magnetic yoke disk (27) is centrally supported.
      <br/>
      The plane M is magnetically symmetric to the latter and this plane extends, in case of this embodiment, through the center of the stator disk winding (21).
    </p>
    <p num="28">2 Translator: the German version reads RuckschluBkeil, but obviously, this is a spelling mistake and makes no sense; it should read RuckschluBteil as it is translated.</p>
    <p num="29">
      In the other figures, the drive element is integrated together with the flange in a disk storage device in the same manner, as shown in Fig. 1.
      <br/>
      There, nothing but a disk is outlined by a broken line.
    </p>
    <p num="30">In FIG. 2 as well as in the FIGS. 3 and 4 the portions with the same function have got the same numbers.</p>
    <p num="31">
      FIG. 2 shows radially directed reinforcing corrugations 33 that increase the stability of the relatively thinwalled die casting housing shell 3, which forms the tank flange.
      <br/>
      In FIG. 2 the lower rotating magnet 26 is omitted, so that the deep drawn shell 25 is shortened to some extent at its radial outer edge in the axial direction.
      <br/>
      Radially at its inner edge, however, an edge is bent up like a collar as far as in the hub 28.
      <br/>
      This hub and the punched and bent portion 25 are rigidly joined.
      <br/>
      The lower flat rotating magnetic yoke 27 has no permanent magnet and is supported on the outer edge of the deep drawn shell 25.
      <br/>
      On both sides of the stator disk there is a plane air gap, analogue to FIG. 1.
    </p>
    <p num="32">
      FIG. 3 shows an alternative embodiment with a punched and bent portion of a S-shaped cross section.
      <br/>
      This portion is the upper magnetic yoke, whereas the lower L-shaped soft iron magnetic yoke cap is supported on the inner side of the hub, whereby the collar that is bent up in the axial direction is supported on a flat stopping face.
      <br/>
      The stator ring disk 31 is with its outer edge supported on a shoulder 39 of the tank flange 3, and extends radially to the inner side and forms on both of its sides also flat air gaps analogue to FIGS. 1 and 2.
    </p>
    <p num="33">
      FIG. 4 shows a stationary magnetic yoke also with a L-shaped cross section and formed as a turned or punched and bent portion and having a radially at the inner edge located leg that extends in the axial direction so as to form an additional labyrinth seal with the hub portions 35, 38 that rotate around both sides of it.
      <br/>
      The coils 22 are supported on the lower magnetic yoke plate 27 and are rigidly fixed to it.
      <br/>
      The plate in turn is supported on the bottom of the tank flange 3, which is thickened in its center and supports a stationary shaft by means of press fit.
    </p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>What is claimed is:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1.</claim-text>
      <claim-text>A brushless DC motor in combination with a load member, the combination comprising:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>a generally flat stator defining an axis and having a plurality of windings disposed thereon which are concentric with said axis and a rotor mounted for rotation about said axis, said rotor having at least one magnetically conducting member spaced from said windings, said at least one magnetically conducting member having a first planar portions and inner and outer leg portion generally transverse to said planar portion forming inner and outer opposingly oriented axially projecting rim portions and defining a generally cup-shaped configuration, said rotor including a permanent magnetic member disposed on said at least one magnetically conducting member at said planar portion radially off-set of said leg portions, said motor defining at least one radially extending planar air gap between adjacent surfaces of said permanent magnetic member and said stator;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and a load member other than a rigid magneto storage disk, said load member being operatively engaged with said rotor by a hub.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="2">
      <claim-text>2. The brushless DC motor in combination with a load member in accordance with claim 1, wherein said at least one magnetically conducting member is a first magnetically conducting member and wherein said rotor includes a second magnetically conducting member generally parallel to said first magnetically conducting member.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="3">
      <claim-text>3. The brushless DC motor in combination with a load member in accordance with claim 2 wherein said second magnetically conducting member is spaced from said first magnetically conducting member.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="4">
      <claim-text>4. The brushless DC motor in combination with a load member in accordance with claim 3 wherein said permanent magnetic member is disposed between said first and second magnetically conducting members.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="5">
      <claim-text>5. The brushless DC motor in combination with a load member in accordance with claim 3 wherein at least a portion of said stator is disposed between said first and second magnetically conducting members.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="6">
      <claim-text>6. A brushless DC motor in combination with a load member, the combination comprising: a generally flat stator defining an axis and having a plurality of windings disposed thereon which are concentric with said axis and a rotor mounted for rotation about said axis, said rotor having at least one magnetically conducting member spaced from said windings, said at least one magnetically conducting member having a first planar portion and inner and outer leg portions generally transverse to said planar portion forming inner and outer opposingly oriented axially projecting rim portions and defining a generally cup-shaped configuration, said rotor including a permanent magnetic member disposed on said at least one magnetically conducting member at said planar portion disposed between said inner and outer leg portions, said motor defining at least one radially extending planar air gap between adjacent surfaces of said permanent magnetic member and said stator;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and a load member other than a rigid magnetic storage disk, said load member being operatively engaged with said rotor.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="7">
      <claim-text>7. The brushless DC motor in combination with a load member in accordance with claim 6, wherein said at least one magnetically conducting member is a first magnetically conducting member and wherein said rotor includes a second magnetically conducting member generally parallel to said first magnetically conducting member.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="8">
      <claim-text>8. The brushless DC motor in combination with a load member in accordance with claim 7 wherein said second magnetically conducting member is spaced from said first magnetically conducting member.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="9">
      <claim-text>9. The brushless DC motor in combination with a load member in accordance with claim 8 wherein said permanent magnetic member is disposed between said first and second magnetically conducting members.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="10">
      <claim-text>10. The brushless DC motor in combination with a load member in accordance with claim 8 wherein at least a portion of said stator is disposed between said first and second magnetically conducting members.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="11">
      <claim-text>11. A brushless DC motor in combination with a load member, the combination comprising: a generally flat stator defining an axis and having a plurality of windings disposed thereon which are concentric with said axis and a rotor mounted for rotation about said axis, said rotor having first and second magnetically conducting members spaced from said windings, said first magnetically conducting member having a first planar portion and inner and outer leg portions generally transverse to said planar portion forming inner and outer opposingly oriented axially projecting rim portions and defining a generally cup-shaped configuration, said second magnetically conducting member having a planar portion spaced from said planar portion of said first magnetically conducting member, said rotor including a permanent magnetic member disposed on said first magnetically conducting member at said planar portion between said inner and outer leg portions, said motor defining at least one radially extending planar air gap between adjacent surfaces of said permanent magnetic member and said stator;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and a load member other than a rigid magnetic storage disk, said load member being operatively engaged with said rotor.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="12">
      <claim-text>12. The brushless DC motor in combination with a load member in accordance with claim 11 wherein said second magnetically conducting member planar portion is generally parallel to said first magnetically conducting member planar portion.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="13">
      <claim-text>13. The brushless DC motor in combination with a load member in accordance with claim 11 wherein said permanent magnetic member is disposed between said first and second magnetically conducting members.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="14">
      <claim-text>14. The brushless DC motor in combination with a load member in accordance with claim 12 wherein at least a portion of said stator is disposed between said first and second magnetically conducting members.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>