<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06181630B2.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as second publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06181630</doc-number>
        <kind>B2</kind>
        <date>20010130</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6181630</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B2</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference is-representative="YES" family-id="26819332" extended-family-id="42108228">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>09499702</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>20000207</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>2000US-09499702</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>43164639</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>49970200</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>20000207</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>2000US-09499702</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="2">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>12130699</doc-number>
        <kind>P</kind>
        <date>19990223</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="2">
        <doc-number>1999US-60121306</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010130</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>G11C   7/00        20060101A I20051110RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>11</class>
        <subclass>C</subclass>
        <main-group>7</main-group>
        <subgroup>00</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051110</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="2">
        <text>G06F  11/14        20060101A I20080531RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>06</class>
        <subclass>F</subclass>
        <main-group>11</main-group>
        <subgroup>14</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20080531</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="3">
        <text>G06F  11/20        20060101A N20080531RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>06</class>
        <subclass>F</subclass>
        <main-group>11</main-group>
        <subgroup>20</subgroup>
        <classification-value>N</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20080531</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>365228000</text>
        <class>365</class>
        <subclass>228000</subclass>
      </main-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="1">
        <text>365183000</text>
        <class>365</class>
        <subclass>183000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="2">
        <text>365185080</text>
        <class>365</class>
        <subclass>185080</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="3">
        <text>714E11138</text>
        <class>714</class>
        <subclass>E11138</subclass>
      </further-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <classifications-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="1">
        <text>G06F-011/14A8P</text>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>06</class>
        <subclass>F</subclass>
        <main-group>011</main-group>
        <subgroup>14A8P</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
    </classifications-ecla>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>G06F-011/1441</classification-symbol>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>06</class>
        <subclass>F</subclass>
        <main-group>11</main-group>
        <subgroup>1441</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
      <patent-classification sequence="2">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>G06F-011/2015</classification-symbol>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>06</class>
        <subclass>F</subclass>
        <main-group>11</main-group>
        <subgroup>2015</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>A</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
      <patent-classification sequence="3">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="ICO"/>
        <classification-symbol>S06F-011/20K</classification-symbol>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>1</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6181630</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Method of stabilizing data stored in volatile memory</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="1">
          <text>CHANG JOSEPH JUIFU, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>3916390</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US3916390</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="2">
          <text>PATEL RAMESHCHANDRA S, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>4327410</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US4327410</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="3">
          <text>HAMERLA DONALD R</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>4525800</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US4525800</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <related-documents>
      <related-publication>
        <document-id>
          <country>US</country>
          <doc-number>60/121,306</doc-number>
          <date>19990223</date>
        </document-id>
        <document-id>
          <country>US</country>
          <doc-number>60/121306</doc-number>
          <date>19990223</date>
        </document-id>
      </related-publication>
    </related-documents>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant data-format="original" app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>Genatek, Inc.</orgname>
            <address>
              <address-1>Redding, CA, US</address-1>
              <city>Redding</city>
              <state>CA</state>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
        <applicant data-format="questel" app-type="applicant" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>GENATEK</orgname>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Caulkins, Jason Robert</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Redding, CA, US</address-1>
              <city>Redding</city>
              <state>CA</state>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>Nelms, David</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>GRANTED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      A system for preventing data loss when volatile memory is used to store data either internal or external to a host computer.
      <br/>
      In the preferred embodiment, the system provides uninterrupted power to the volatile memory and to a non-volatile storage device such as a magnetic disk drive or other non-volatile memory.
      <br/>
      Upon loss of commercial power, host computer shut down, or manual initiation, the data stored in the volatile memory will be automatically backed-up to the non-volatile storage device via a high bandwidth data path.
      <br/>
      Under normal conditions, data stored in volatile memory are accessible by the host computer using a high bandwidth data path.
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <p num="1">This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional No. 60/121,306 filed Feb. 23, 1999.</p>
    <heading>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="2">
      There are two basic classifications of the media on which digital data are stored: Volatile and non-volatile.
      <br/>
      Data stored in volatile memory are lost when power is removed, where data stored in non-volatile memory are retained when power is removed.
      <br/>
      Data intended for high-speed short-term access is typically stored in volatile memory (cache or random access memory).
      <br/>
      Data intended for long term future access is typically stored in non-volatile memory (magnetic disks, or other storage media).
    </p>
    <p num="3">
      Volatile memory currently has faster access times and higher data transfer rates than non-volatile memory.
      <br/>
      This makes it an appealing alternative for systems requiring very high-speed access to data typically stored in long term, non-volatile storage devices.
    </p>
    <p num="4">
      Using volatile memory for long-term data storage has inherent risks, due to the loss of data when the power to the system is removed.
      <br/>
      The methods and systems described herein greatly reduce the risk of data loss, by providing a redundant power supply and back-up process, which ensure the data remain even more stable than data stored on the common magnetic disk drive.
    </p>
    <p num="5">
      In order to take advantage of the higher bandwidth of volatile memory, a high-speed data path is required between the host computer and the volatile memory storage device.
      <br/>
      For volatile memory storage devices located internal to the host computer, the computer expansion bus may be used to transfer data.
      <br/>
      For volatile memory storage devices located external to the host computer, a standard high-speed peripheral bus may be used to transfer data.
    </p>
    <heading>BRIEF SUMMARY</heading>
    <p num="6">The proposed system allows volatile memory to be reliably used for long-term, high-speed data storage by the following four methods:</p>
    <p num="7">
      1.
      <br/>
      Provide external commercial power to the volatile memory storage device to maintain the data.
      <br/>
      2. Provide a battery backup system with switching logic to supply uninterrupted power to the volatile memory and to a local or remote non-volatile storage device in the event of commercial power loss.
      <br/>
      3. Provide long-term data retention by supporting a back-up and restore process to a local or remote non-volatile storage device.
      <br/>
      4. Provide high-speed data paths for moving information between the host computer, the volatile memory, and the non-volatile data storage device.
    </p>
    <heading>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
    <p num="8">
      FIG. 1 is a block diagram of a volatile memory storage expansion card internally mounted to the host computer. It shows the power and data paths described in the Claims.
      <br/>
      FIG. 2 is a block diagram of a volatile memory storage device external to the host computer. It shows the power and data paths described in the Claims.
    </p>
    <heading>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
    <p num="9">
      For volatile memory storage expansion cards located in the host computer (FIG. 1), continuous dc power from an AC/DC converter 2 is provided to the rechargeable battery system 8.
      <br/>
      The rechargeable battery system then provides power to the card, including volatile memory 1, and optionally to the host mounted or local non-volatile storage device 5, 6.
    </p>
    <p num="10">
      An expansion slot cover 3 contains dc connections and discrete user input/output for status indication and manual backup initiation.
      <br/>
      In addition, dc power from the host computer 4 is supplied to the rechargeable battery system, providing a second dc power source for the card.
    </p>
    <p num="11">An automatic and/or manual means to back-up and restore the data stored in the volatile memory to a locally 5 or remotely 6 mounted non-volatile storage device is provided in the firmware of the control logic 7.</p>
    <p num="12">
      In the preferred embodiment the volatile memory storage device is used to store data and is provided with continuous power, even when the host computer is off.
      <br/>
      When the host computer is turned on, the data stored in the volatile memory storage device are normally immediately available.
    </p>
    <p num="13">
      Data are then read and written to the volatile memory storage device during the normal use of the host computer.
      <br/>
      At any time, the user may manually initialize a back-up procedure, which then transfers the entire contents of the volatile memory to a non-volatile storage device 5,6.
      <br/>
      When this process is finished, the data in volatile memory are again available for normal use, and the back-up data are unchanged.
    </p>
    <p num="14">
      The loss of commercial power will initiate an automatic back-up from the volatile memory to the non-volatile storage device.
      <br/>
      After the back-up, the non-volatile memory will continue to be available for normal operation (running on host computer supplied dc), while an alarm condition is indicated.
      <br/>
      The alarm condition will be automatically cleared upon restoration of commercial power.
    </p>
    <p num="15">
      The loss of host computer dc will initiate an automatic back-up from the volatile memory to the non-volatile storage device.
      <br/>
      After the back-up, the non-volatile memory will continue to be available for normal operation, with no alarm condition.
    </p>
    <p num="16">
      Upon the loss of commercial power and host computer supplied dc, power will be provided seamlessly from the rechargeable battery system to the volatile memory and the non-volatile storage device.
      <br/>
      In addition, an automatic back-up from the volatile memory to the non-volatile storage device will be initiated, an alarm condition will be indicated, and the device will be orderly shut down.
    </p>
    <p num="17">
      When commercial power or host computer supplied dc is restored to the volatile memory storage expansion card, it will then automatically restore the data previously saved from the non-volatile storage device to the volatile memory.
      <br/>
      The data will then be available for normal access.
    </p>
    <p num="18">
      For volatile memory storage devices located external to the host computer (FIG. 2), continuous dc power from an AC/DC converter 2 is provided to the rechargeable battery system 8.
      <br/>
      The rechargeable battery system then provides power to the device, including volatile memory 1, and the local non-volatile storage device 5.
    </p>
    <p num="19">An automatic and/or manual means to back-up and restore the data stored in the volatile memory to a locally mounted non-volatile storage device 5 is provided in the firmware of the control logic 7.</p>
    <p num="20">
      In the preferred embodiment the volatile memory storage device is used to store data and is provided with continuous power, even when the host computer is off.
      <br/>
      When the host computer is turned on, the data stored in the volatile memory are normally immediately available.
    </p>
    <p num="21">
      Data are then read and written to the volatile memory storage device during the normal use of the host computer.
      <br/>
      At any time, the user may manually initiate a back-up procedure, which then transfers the entire contents of the volatile memory to the non-volatile storage device 5.
      <br/>
      When this process is finished, the data in volatile memory are again available for normal use, and the back-up data are unchanged.
    </p>
    <p num="22">
      In the event of a loss of commercial power, dc power will be provided seamlessly from the rechargeable battery system to the volatile memory and the non-volatile storage device.
      <br/>
      In addition, an automatic back-up from the volatile memory to the non-volatile storage device will be initiated, an alarm condition will be indicated, and the device will be orderly shut down (regardless of the condition of the host computer).
    </p>
    <p num="23">
      When commercial power is restored to the volatile memory storage device, it will then automatically restore the data previously saved from the non-volatile storage device to the volatile memory.
      <br/>
      The data will then be available for normal access.
    </p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>What is claimed is:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1.</claim-text>
      <claim-text>A method of stabilizing data stored in volatile memory comprising of:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>means for providing direct dc input to the volatile memory; means for providing a battery back-up to the volatile memory; means for providing a battery back-up to a local or remotely mounted non-volatile storage device; means for providing a high bandwidth data path between the volatile memory, the host computer, and a non-volatile storage device; means for providing long-term data retention upon power loss, by transferring the data stored in the volatile memory to a non-volatile storage device.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>