<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06183620B2.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as second publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06183620</doc-number>
        <kind>B2</kind>
        <date>20010206</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6183620</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B2</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference family-id="7857426" extended-family-id="1321883">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>09416327</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19991012</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>1999US-09416327</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>1371919</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>DE</country>
        <doc-number>19805619</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19980212</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>1998DE-1005619</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim kind="international" sequence="2">
        <country>WO</country>
        <doc-number>EP9900846</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19990210</date>
        <priority-linkage-type>W</priority-linkage-type>
        <priority-active-indicator>N</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="2">
        <doc-number>1999WO-EP00846</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010206</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>C25C   3/20        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>C</section>
        <class>25</class>
        <subclass>C</subclass>
        <main-group>3</main-group>
        <subgroup>20</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>205336000</text>
        <class>205</class>
        <subclass>336000</subclass>
      </main-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="1">
        <text>205389000</text>
        <class>205</class>
        <subclass>389000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <classifications-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="1">
        <text>C25C-003/20</text>
        <section>C</section>
        <class>25</class>
        <subclass>C</subclass>
        <main-group>3</main-group>
        <subgroup>20</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
    </classifications-ecla>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>C25C-003/20</classification-symbol>
        <section>C</section>
        <class>25</class>
        <subclass>C</subclass>
        <main-group>3</main-group>
        <subgroup>20</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>2</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>0</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>0</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6183620</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Process for controlling the A1F3 content in cryolite melts</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="1">
          <text>ANDERSEN JENS ARVID</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>4045309</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US4045309</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="2">
          <text>DESCLAUX PAUL, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>4668350</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US4668350</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="3">
          <text>BASQUIN JEAN-LUC, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>4867851</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US4867851</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="4">
          <text>ENTNER PETER</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5094728</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5094728</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="5">
          <text>ALCAN INT LTD</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>EP</country>
            <doc-number>0195142</doc-number>
            <kind>A1</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>EP-195142</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="6">
          <text>ALUSUISSE LONZA SERVICES AG</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>EP</country>
            <doc-number>0455590</doc-number>
            <kind>A1</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>EP-455590</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="7">
          <text>HERAEUS ELECTRO NITE INT</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>EP</country>
            <doc-number>0703026</doc-number>
            <kind>A1</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>EP-703026</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <related-documents>
      <continuation>
        <relation>
          <parent-doc>
            <document-id>
              <country>WO</country>
              <doc-number>PCT/EP99/00846</doc-number>
              <date>19990210</date>
            </document-id>
          </parent-doc>
        </relation>
      </continuation>
    </related-documents>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant data-format="original" app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>Heraeus Electro-Nite International N.V.</orgname>
            <address>
              <address-1>Houthalen, BE</address-1>
              <city>Houthalen</city>
              <country>BE</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>BE</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
        <applicant data-format="questel" app-type="applicant" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>HERAEUS ELECTRO NITE INTERNATIONAL</orgname>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>BE</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Verstreken, Paul Clement</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Hasselt, BE</address-1>
              <city>Hasselt</city>
              <country>BE</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>BE</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
      <agents>
        <agent sequence="1" rep-type="agent">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>Akin, Gump, Strauss, Hauer &amp; Feld, L.L.P.</orgname>
          </addressbook>
        </agent>
      </agents>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>Valentine, Donald R.</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>LAPSED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      A process is provided for controlling the AlF3 content in cryolite melts for aluminum reduction, wherein the temperature of the melt is measured.
      <br/>
      In order to produce a very precise process which makes it possible to perform the aluminum reduction at the lowest posssible temperature, and thus as energy-saving as possible, the liquidus temperature of the cryolite melt is measured and compared with a first target value.
      <br/>
      AlF3 is added to the bath if the measured liquidus temperature is higher than the first target value.
      <br/>
      If the measured liquidus temperature is lower than the first target value, the measured liquidus temperature is compared with a second target value which is lower than the first target value.
      <br/>
      NaF or Na2CO3 is added to the bath if the measured liquidus temperature is lower than the second target value.
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <heading>CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
    <p num="1">This application-is a continuation of International Application PCT/EP99/00846 Filed Feb. 10, 1999.</p>
    <heading>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="2">The invention relates to a process for controlling the AlF3 content in cryolite melts for aluminum reduction, wherein the temperature of the melt is measured.</p>
    <p num="3">
      A process of this type is known from U.S. Pat. 4,668,350. In the process disclosed therein, a known relation between the bath temperature and the bath composition (NaF:AlF3) is used.
      <br/>
      From this relation a target temperature of the bath is calculated as a function of a target composition (NaF:AlF3).
      <br/>
      The temperature of the bath is measured and AlF3 is added, if the bath temperature is higher than the target temperature.
      <br/>
      Of course, the bath temperature is also influenced by a series of other factors.
    </p>
    <heading>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="4">An object of the invention is to provide a very exact process that makes it possible to operate the aluminum reduction at as low a temperature as possible, and therefore as energy-saving as possible.</p>
    <p num="5">
      This object is achieved according to the invention in that the liquidus temperature of the cryolite melt is measured, the measured liquidus temperature is compared to a first target value, and AlF3 is added to the bath if the measured liquidus temperature is higher than the first target value.
      <br/>
      If the measured liquidus temperature is lower than the first target value, the measured liquidus temperature is compared with a second target value that is lower than the first target value, and NaF or Na2 CO3 is added to the bath if the measured liquidus temperature is lower than the second target value.
    </p>
    <p num="6">
      Since the liquidus temperature of a melt allows very exact conclusions about the proportion of individual components of the melt, the process according to the invention offers the possibility of caring out the aluminum reduction process in as energy-favorable a manner as possible and thus as economically as possible.
      <br/>
      The invention also explicitly includes the reverse comparison between a target value and the measured value of the liquidus temperature, namely that the measured liquidus temperature is first compared with the second target value, and NaF or Na2 CO3 is added to the bath if the measured liquidus temperature is lower than this second target value.
      <br/>
      If the measured liquidus temperature is higher than the second target value, the measured liquidus temperature is compared to the first target value, which is greater than the second target value, and AlF3 is added to the bath if the measured liquidus temperature is higher than this first target value.
      <br/>
      If, for example, the measured liquidus temperature is lower than the second target value, a comparison with the first, higher target value is of course superfluous.
      <br/>
      If the measured liquidus temperature lies between the two target values, no addition of a component influencing the liquidus temperature occurs.
    </p>
    <heading>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="7">Two different target values are necessary in order to create a buffer zone and to prevent overreactions, which can occur due to constant compensation additions.</p>
    <p num="8">
      The temperature difference between the two target values depends, among other things, on the stability of the aluminum reduction process.
      <br/>
      If the process is stable, a smaller temperature difference can be selected.
      <br/>
      The liquidus temperature of the bath is dependent on all components, in particular on Al2 O3 and AlF3.
      <br/>
      The difference between two target values is thus also a function of the way in which and the quantity and precision with which AlF3 (or other components, such as Al2 O3) is added.
      <br/>
      For example, the difference can be correspondingly smaller, the smaller the respectively supplied quantity.
      <br/>
      With a point dosing (point feeder), less but more precise dosing is used than with a middle feeder (center bar breaker) or a side feeder (sideworked cell).
      <br/>
      The difference between the first and the second target value is also dependent, among other things, on the experience of the operator who is controlling the melt, wherein it fundamentally applies that the difference can become smaller with increasing experience of the operator.
    </p>
    <p num="9">
      Fundamentally, the liquidus temperature of the melt can be lowered by the addition of AlF3 and increased by the addition of NaF.
      <br/>
      For an increase, however, the addition of Na2 CO3 is also possible, since Na2 CO3 contributes to the formation of NaF in the melt and thus to the increase of the NaF portion and to the reduction of the AlF3 portion.
      <br/>
      A liquidus temperature that is too high indicates an AlF3 concentration that is too low, while a liquidus temperature that is too low indicates an AlF3 concentration that is too high.
      <br/>
      By addition of NaF or Na2 CO3, cryolite is formed together with AlF3, and thus the ATF3 concentration is lowered.
      <br/>
      Initially, a target value can be determined for a liquidus temperature from the known phase diagrams, taking into account the initial composition of the bath.
      <br/>
      The second target value is established for an assumed bath composition.
      <br/>
      The concrete relationships between the bath composition and the bath temperature are themselves described in detail in U.S.Pat. No. 4,668,350. In this regard, reference is made explicitly to this disclosure, and the patent is incorporated herein by reference.
    </p>
    <p num="10">
      According to the invention, it is advantageous that the cooling curve of a sample of the melt outside of the molten bath itself be measured, and the liquidus temperature thereby be determined.
      <br/>
      In principle, it is also of course possible to measure the liquidus temperature by other suitable processes that are sufficiently known to the artisan.
    </p>
    <p num="11">In the following, an embodiment of the process according to the invention is described.</p>
    <p num="12">
      The first target value can be calculated from the average or the current bath composition.
      <br/>
      For example, a bath with a proportion of 5% CaF2 , 3% Al2 O3, and with an excess of 12% AlF3 (Halvor Kvande, Journal of Metallurg, pp. 22ff (November 1994)) has a liquidus temperature of 955 (degree)  C. With an AlF3 excess of 11% the liquidus temperature amounts to 960 (degree)  -C, and with an AlF3 excess of 13% the liquidus temperature amounts to 950 (degree)  C. That is, a variation of the AlF3 excess of 2% causes a change of the liquidus temperature by 10 (degree)  C. Calculations of this type are described, for example, in Solheim et al., Light Metals 1995, The Minerals, Metals &amp; Materials Society, pp. 451ff (1995).
      <br/>
      If the first target value amounts to 960 (degree)  C., for example, and a liquidus temperature of 970 (degree)  C. is measured, the AlF3 excess is to be increased by about 2%.
    </p>
    <p num="13">
      With a stable bath the target temperature (target value) can be lowered.
      <br/>
      The AlF3 concentration thereby increases, which leads to a higher current efficiency.
      <br/>
      If the bath cell becomes unstable, the liquidus temperature (target value) is to be increased.
      <br/>
      The cell stability can be monitored in a conventional manner by regular checks with a suitable sensor.
    </p>
    <p num="14">
      The second target value depends, among other things, on the type of the addition of Al2 O3 to the bath.
      <br/>
      With an automatic or a point feeding the second target value can lie approximately 10 (degree)  C. below the first target value, whereas with a center bar breaker and without automation of the addition the second target value can lie approximately 20 (degree)  C. below the first target value.
      <br/>
      If the measured value of the liquidus temperature lies above the first target value, AlF3 is added according to the aforementioned model composition.
      <br/>
      If the measured value of the liquidus temperature lies below the second target value, NaF (or Na2 CO3) is added, such that an addition of 3% NaF (relative to the entire bath) leads to an increase of the liquidus temperature by approximately 10 (degree)  C. If the second target value amounts to 950 (degree)  C., and a liquidus temperature of 940 (degree)  C. is measured, an addition of 3% NaF (or a corresponding quantity of Na2 CO3), relative to the entire bath, is necessary.
    </p>
    <p num="15">The measurements can be performed, for example, every two days or daily.</p>
    <p num="16">
      It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that changes could be made to the embodiment(s) described above without departing from the broad inventive concept thereof.
      <br/>
      It is understood, therefore, that this invention is not limited to the particular embodiment(s) disclosed, but is intended to cover modifications within the spirit and scope of the present invention as defined by the appended claims.
    </p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>I claim:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1. A process for controlling the AlF3 content in cryolite melts for aluminum reduction, comprising measuring the liquidus temperature of a cryolite melt, comparing the measured liquidus temperature with a first target value, adding AlF3 to a molten bath of the cryolite melt if the measured liquidus temperature is higher than the first target value, comparing the measured liquidus temperature with a second target value which is lower than the first target value, and adding NaF or Na2 CO3 to the molten bath of the cryolite melt if the measured liquidus temperature is lower than the second target value.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="2">
      <claim-text>2. The process according to claim 1, wherein the liquidus temperature is determined by measuring the cooling curve of a sample of the cryolite melt outside of the molten bath of the cryolite melt.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>