<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06181236B2.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as second publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06181236</doc-number>
        <kind>B2</kind>
        <date>20010130</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6181236</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B2</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference is-representative="YES" family-id="23805826" extended-family-id="42107586">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>09454728</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19991204</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>1999US-09454728</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>43163845</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>45472899</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19991204</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>1999US-09454728</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010130</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>G08B   1/08        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>08</class>
        <subclass>B</subclass>
        <main-group>1</main-group>
        <subgroup>08</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="2">
        <text>G10K   5/00        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>10</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>5</main-group>
        <subgroup>00</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>340326000</text>
        <class>340</class>
        <subclass>326000</subclass>
      </main-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="1">
        <text>340323000R</text>
        <class>340</class>
        <subclass>323000R</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="2">
        <text>340332000</text>
        <class>340</class>
        <subclass>332000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="3">
        <text>340539100</text>
        <class>340</class>
        <subclass>539100</subclass>
      </further-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <classifications-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="1">
        <text>G08B-001/08</text>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>08</class>
        <subclass>B</subclass>
        <main-group>1</main-group>
        <subgroup>08</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="2">
        <text>G10K-005/00</text>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>10</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>5</main-group>
        <subgroup>00</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
    </classifications-ecla>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>G08B-001/08</classification-symbol>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>08</class>
        <subclass>B</subclass>
        <main-group>1</main-group>
        <subgroup>08</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
      <patent-classification sequence="2">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>G10K-005/00</classification-symbol>
        <section>G</section>
        <class>10</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>5</main-group>
        <subgroup>00</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6181236</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Sports whistle with audible and visual output signals</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="1">
          <text>PEJIC NENAD</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>6067013</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US6067013</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="2">
          <text>GERTLER LEONA, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>4314316</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US4314316</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="3">
          <text>COSTABILE MICHAEL J</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5293354</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5293354</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="4">
          <text>RAND JR DAVID</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5507246</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5507246</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="5">
          <text>YAMAMOTO DAVID TAKAO</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5847652</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5847652</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>SCHNEIDER, JR. ARNOLD C.</name>
          </addressbook>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Schneider, Jr., Arnold C.</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Devon, PA, 19333, US</address-1>
              <city>Devon</city>
              <state>PA</state>
              <postcode>19333</postcode>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>Pope, Daryl</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>GRANTED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      A sports whistle having a sensor (12) which is responsive to the operation of a present art whistle (14).
      <br/>
      Said sensor activates a conventional wireless transmitter (18) simultaneously with the audible output signal.
      <br/>
      Said wireless signals are acquired by a conventional receiver (28).
      <br/>
      Said receiver initiates a variety of visual indicators to overcome crowd noise.
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <heading>BACKGROUND--FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="1">
      This invention relates to whistles used by officials at sporting events to indicate the occurrence of some event.
      <br/>
      In particular, it provides the improvement of simultaneous audible and visual signals to overcome noise.
    </p>
    <heading>BACKGROUND--DESCRIPTION OF INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="2">
      In many sports such as football, soccer, basketball, ice hockey, wrestling, etc., an official blows a whistle to notify players and spectators of the occurrence of some event.
      <br/>
      Due to increased crowd noise, it is often impossible for live spectators at a stadium and television viewers at home to discern the audible signal and to know when the event occurred.
      <br/>
      It is, therefore, proposed that these officials use a conventional whistle to initiate a wireless signal simultaneous with, and in the same manner as, the present art, audible signal.
      <br/>
      By means of a receiver, this wireless signal is then used to initiate a variety of visual signals that can easily be discerned by both live spectators and television viewers.
      <br/>
      If desired for security, the wireless signal can be comprised of several frequencies.
    </p>
    <p num="3">
      Football is an excellent example for the usage of this improvement.
      <br/>
      When a referee signals that a play has ended, the audible signal usually can not be heard by the crowd in attendance or by the television audience.
      <br/>
      If the ball is subsequently fumbled, it is difficult to know whether the whistle was blown before or after the fumble.
      <br/>
      With this improvement, when the whistle is blown, a simultaneous wireless signal initiates a variety of lights or other visual indications on the playing field and also on the television screen.
      <br/>
      By use of video replay, it is then possible to determine exactly when the referee's signal was made.
    </p>
    <heading>PRIOR ART</heading>
    <p num="4">
      There have been toy and party whistles with extension elements that give a visual indication as long as they are blown, e.g. U.S. Pat. Nos. 530,909 and 532,642.
      <br/>
      There is a sports whistle which maintains an element in the extended position after it has been blown, e.g. see U.S. Pat. No. 5,507,246. There is an illuminating whistle which has a lamp bulb within the whistle, e.g. see U.S. Pat. No. 4,314,316. There is an electronic whistle device which provides an electrically activated audible signal when a hand-held button is depressed, e.g. see U.S. Pat. No. 5,847,652.
    </p>
    <p num="5">
      None of the above-mentioned, prior art whistles emit a wireless signal and none of them meet the need for visual observation from a great distance or iva the television screen.
      <br/>
      In addition, the electronic whistle device does not maintain the advantages of the present art, mouth blown whistle.
    </p>
    <heading>OBJECTS AND ADVANTAGES</heading>
    <p num="6">Accordingly, several objects and advantages of my invention are:</p>
    <p num="7">
      (a) to enable a sports official to give a signal which overcomes crowd noise;
      <br/>
      (b) to maintain the present art referee whistle and its audible signal;
      <br/>
      (c) to improve such whistles so they can provide simultaneous wireless signals;
      <br/>
      (d) to provide a flash of light or movement of an object in the sport arena visible to entire audience that is triggered by a wireless signal from the whistle; and
      <br/>
      (e) to provide an indication on television screens that is triggered by a wireless signal from the whistle.
    </p>
    <heading>DRAWING FIGURE</heading>
    <p num="8">
      In the drawings:
      <br/>
      FIG. 1 depicts the preferred embodiment of the invention
      <br/>
      FIG. 2 is a partly diagrammatic representation of a referee using the invention to trigger remote visual signals.
      <br/>
      FIG. 3 depicts
      <br/>
      (a) details of the preferred embodiment of the sensor
      <br/>
      (b) details of a modification that provides a closure over the whistle opening to permit wireless signals without an audible signal
      <br/>
      (c) details of a modification wherein the transmitter is combined with the sensor and whistle in a unitary assembly
      <br/>
      FIG. 4 depicts a modification wherein the audible sensor is combined with the transmitter separate from the whistle
      <br/>
      --
      <br/>
      -- REFERENCE NUMERALS IN DRAWINGS
      <br/>
      --        10   apparatus of invention  28   receiver
      <br/>
      --        12   sensor                  30   wires (electrical)
      <br/>
      --        14   whistle                 32   lighting indication
      <br/>
      --        16   lanyard                 34   mech. indication
      <br/>
      --        18   transmitter             36   T.V.
      <br/>
      indication
      <br/>
      --        20   ON/OFF switch           40   diaphragm
      <br/>
      --        22   mouthpiece              42   switch
      <br/>
      --        24   sound chamber           44   audio sensor
      <br/>
      --        26   opening                 46   closure
    </p>
    <heading>SUMMARY</heading>
    <p num="9">
      In accordance with the present invention, a device produces a plurality of official signals at a sporting event wherein one of these signals is audible and at least one other signal is visual.
      <br/>
      In combination with a conventional whistle are a sensor, a transmitter, and a receiver.
    </p>
    <p num="10">The preferred embodiment of the invention utilizes an air-actuated sensor responsive to the whistle's operation.</p>
    <p num="11">An alternative embodiment of the invention utilizes an audio-actuated sensor responsive to the whistle's operation.</p>
    <p num="12">DESCRIPTION--FIGS. 1 TO 4</p>
    <p num="13">
      The preferred embodiment of the whistle is illustrated in FIG. 1 with details of sensor 12 shown in FIG. 3.
      <br/>
      The hand-held portion of the whistle 10 is a modification of a present art referee whistle 14 by the addition of said sensor 12.
      <br/>
      The sensor 12 is connected to the pneumatics of the whistle and senses that the whistle has been blown (illustrated in FIG. 3).
      <br/>
      The sensor 12 is also electrically connected to wires 30 that go with the lanyard 16 that hangs from the referee's neck (illustrated in FIG. 1).
      <br/>
      The wires 30 connect to a conventional transmitter 18.
      <br/>
      An ON/OFF switch 20 permits audible signals with or without wireless signals.
    </p>
    <p num="14">
      The entire invention is depicted in FIG. 2.
      <br/>
      A referee is shown using the hand-held portion of the whistle 10.
      <br/>
      The transmitter 18 is attached to his waist.
      <br/>
      The two main portions are interconnected by said wires 30 that go with the lanyard 16.
    </p>
    <p num="15">
      FIG. 3 depicts an additional embodiment of the invention wherein the transmitter 18 is combined with the whistle 14 and sensor 12 in a unitary assembly.
      <br/>
      FIG. 3 also depicts an embodiment wherein a closure 46 can be slid over the whistle opening 26 to permit wireless signals without audible signal.
    </p>
    <p num="16">FIG. 4 depicts an additional embodiment of the invention wherein an audio sensor 44 is combined with the transmitter 18 in a unitary assembly separate from the whistle 14.</p>
    <p num="17">OPERATION--FIGS. 2 &amp; 3</p>
    <p num="18">
      As shown in the figures, the operation of the audible output portion of the whistle is identical to a present art whistle.
      <br/>
      Air is blown into the mouthpiece 22 which is connected to the sound chamber 24 and emits an audible signal as it departs through the opening 26.
    </p>
    <p num="19">
      Initiation of the wireless output signal is by means of a sensor 12 which is responsive to the influx of said air.
      <br/>
      Said influx of air causes the diaphragm 40 to deflect, thereby actuating the switch 42.
      <br/>
      Said switch is electrically connected to the transmitter 18.
    </p>
    <p num="20">
      For the sake of brevity, a disclosure of the transmitter is omitted since that is a well-developed art with components readily available from suppliers of garage door openers, etc.
      <br/>
      A receiver 28, also well-developed, responsive to said wireless signal remotely initiates a variety of visual indicators such as a flash of light 32, the movement of an object 34, or an indication on a television screen 36.
    </p>
    <p num="21">CONCLUSION, RAMIFICATIONS, AND SCOPE</p>
    <p num="22">
      The objects are achieved by a modification to the present art referee whistle and the addition of a transmitter.
      <br/>
      The modification consists of a sensor that is integrally connected to the pneumatics of the whistle and senses that the whistle has been blown.
      <br/>
      The sensor is also electrically connected to a transmitter through wires that go with the lanyard that hangs from the referee's neck.
      <br/>
      By means of this connection, the sensor triggers circuitry within the transmitter to emit a wireless signal.
      <br/>
      An ON/OFF switch on the transmitter allows the referee to control whether or not a wireless signal should be generated.
    </p>
    <p num="23">A receiver responsive to the wireless isngal initiates a variety of visual indicators such as a flash of light, the movement of an object, or an indication on a television screen.</p>
    <p num="24">
      At a football game the flash of light could be located at the top of the goal posts, at the top of the first down markers, or on the scoreboard.
      <br/>
      At an indoor event, the flash could be located at the scorer's table or scoreboard.
      <br/>
      The movement of and object could be a flag that is released by the signal.
      <br/>
      It will now be possible for both the live audience and the television audience to know the precise instant that a referee's signal has been sounded.
    </p>
    <p num="25">
      The whistle can also be used as a starting signal for races.
      <br/>
      By triggering the flash of light, the hearing impaired will be able to readily sense the starting signal.
    </p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>I claim:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1. A device for producing a plurality of official signals at a sporting event, wherein one of said official signals is an audio signal and at least one other official signal is a visual signal, comprising a conventional whistle that is responsive to the influx of air to produce said audio signal and the following:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>a) a transmitter operatively associated with said whistle and responsive to an electrical impulse for transmitting a wireless output signal; b) a sensor responsive to said whistle for generating said electrical impulse to said transmitter;</claim-text>
      <claim-text>and c) a receiver responsive to said wireless signal for generating a visual signal to spectators at a sporting event and to television viewers; wherein said receiver controls generation of said visual signal located at the sporting event, and as well automatically controls generation of an said visual signal that is displayed on a televisions viewer's television screen, thereby indicating when the whistle is blown.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="2">
      <claim-text>2. The device of claim 1 when the sensor is responsive to the audio output of the whistle and is attached to said whistle.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="3">
      <claim-text>3. The device of claim 2 wherein the sensor is responsive to the influx of air into the whistle and is attached to said whistle.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="4">
      <claim-text>4. The device of claim 2 wherein the sensor responsive to the audio output is separately located from said whistle.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="5">
      <claim-text>5. The device of claim 1 wherein said receiver responds by causing indications to appear on scoreboards.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="6">
      <claim-text>6. The device of claim 1 wherein said receiver responds by causing indications to appear on television screens.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>