<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06178853B2.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as second publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06178853</doc-number>
        <kind>B2</kind>
        <date>20010130</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6178853</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B2</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference is-representative="YES" family-id="46256950" extended-family-id="42098431">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>09510591</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>20000222</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>2000US-09510591</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>43151277</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>51059100</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>20000222</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>2000US-09510591</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="2">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>39839799</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19990917</date>
        <priority-linkage-type>2</priority-linkage-type>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="2">
        <doc-number>1999US-09398397</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010130</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <term-of-grant>
      <disclaimer/>
    </term-of-grant>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>B25B  21/02        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>B</section>
        <class>25</class>
        <subclass>B</subclass>
        <main-group>21</main-group>
        <subgroup>02</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>081054000</text>
        <class>081</class>
        <subclass>054000</subclass>
      </main-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="1">
        <text>081057420</text>
        <class>081</class>
        <subclass>057420</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="2">
        <text>081429000</text>
        <class>081</class>
        <subclass>429000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="3">
        <text>081480000</text>
        <class>081</class>
        <subclass>480000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="4">
        <text>173093500</text>
        <class>173</class>
        <subclass>093500</subclass>
      </further-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <classifications-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="1">
        <text>B25B-021/02</text>
        <section>B</section>
        <class>25</class>
        <subclass>B</subclass>
        <main-group>21</main-group>
        <subgroup>02</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="2">
        <text>B25B-021/02C</text>
        <section>B</section>
        <class>25</class>
        <subclass>B</subclass>
        <main-group>021</main-group>
        <subgroup>02C</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
    </classifications-ecla>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>B25B-021/02</classification-symbol>
        <section>B</section>
        <class>25</class>
        <subclass>B</subclass>
        <main-group>21</main-group>
        <subgroup>02</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
      <patent-classification sequence="2">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>B25B-021/026</classification-symbol>
        <section>B</section>
        <class>25</class>
        <subclass>B</subclass>
        <main-group>21</main-group>
        <subgroup>026</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>9</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6178853</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Actuating device for an electrical power wrench</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="1">
          <text>GIARDINO DAVID A, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5083619</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5083619</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="2">
          <text>HUANG CHEN S</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5412546</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5412546</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="3">
          <text>SETSUKO SHIBATA</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5839518</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5839518</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="4">
          <text>BUCK DAVID A</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5890403</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5890403</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="5">
          <text>HSIEH AN-FU</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5915484</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5915484</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="6">
          <text>JUAN CHIH-CHEN</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5941319</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5941319</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <patcit num="7">
          <text>LI FEN-LIEN, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>5954141</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US5954141</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <related-documents>
      <continuation-in-part>
        <relation>
          <parent-doc>
            <document-id>
              <country>US</country>
              <doc-number>39839799</doc-number>
              <kind>A</kind>
              <date>19990917</date>
            </document-id>
          </parent-doc>
        </relation>
      </continuation-in-part>
    </related-documents>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant data-format="original" app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>You Jin Industrial Co., Ltd.</orgname>
            <address>
              <address-1>Taipei Hsien, TW</address-1>
              <city>Taipei Hsien</city>
              <country>TW</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>TW</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
        <applicant data-format="questel" app-type="applicant" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>YOU JIN INDUSTRIAL</orgname>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>TW</country>
          </nationality>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Huang, Wan-Chang</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Taipei Hsien, TW</address-1>
              <city>Taipei Hsien</city>
              <country>TW</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>TW</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>Smith, James G.</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>LAPSED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      An actuating device for an electrical power wrench includes a base member connected to a motor and an output shaft is rotatably connected to the base member.
      <br/>
      A pin biased by a spring movably extends through the base member.
      <br/>
      A ball biased by a spring is received in the base member and engaged with a groove defined in an outside of the pin.
      <br/>
      A movable frame with a weight movably retained between two blocks on the base member and two springs connected between the two ends of the movable frame and the two blocks.
      <br/>
      An L-shaped actuating member is rotatably connected between the two blocks and pivotably connected to two lugs of the movable frame.
      <br/>
      When the base member is rotated by the motor, the movable frame radially moves due to the eccentric force to pivot the actuating member.
      <br/>
      When the force being put on to the pin by the actuating member overcomes the froce of the two springs, the pin extends to impact a plate extending radially outward from the output shaft to output a sudden and large torque.
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <p num="1">
      This is a continuation-in-part of application Ser.
      <br/>
      No. 09/398,397, filed Sep. 17, 1999.
    </p>
    <heading>FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="2">The present invention relates to an actuating device for an electrical power wrench and includes a pin which radially impacts a plate mounted to the output shaft by a pivotal movement of a pushing member which is actuated by a movable frame when an eccentric force is applied to the frame.</p>
    <heading>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="3">
      The present invention intends to provide an actuating device for an electrical power wrench wherein the output shaft has a plate mounted thereto which is radially impacted by a pin controlled by the eccentric force of the power wrench.
      <br/>
      The pin extends and radially impacts the plate when the desired eccentric force of the base member driven by a motor is reached.
      <br/>
      The present invention has arisen to mitigate and/or obviate the disadvantages of the conventional power wrenches.
    </p>
    <heading>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="4">
      In accordance with one aspect of the present invention, there is provided an actuating device for an electrical power wrench which comprises a base member having a tubular member extending from centrally a first side thereof so as to be connected to a motor.
      <br/>
      A passage is defined through the base member for receiving a pin therein which is biased by a spring.
      <br/>
      A side recess is defined in the base member and a ball is received in the side recess and biased by a spring.
      <br/>
      Two blocks extend from the first side of the base member.
      <br/>
      A movable frame is movably connected to the first side of the base member with a weight connected to a first end of the movable frame.
      <br/>
      Two lugs extend from the movable frame which is retained by a guide plate connected to the first side of the base member.
      <br/>
      Two springs are respectively connected between the rods and the movable frame.
    </p>
    <p num="5">
      An actuating member has a first part engaged with the two lugs of the movable frame, and a second part of the actuating member extending from the first part at an angle relative to the first part.
      <br/>
      The actuating member is pivotally connected between the two blocks and the second part of the actuating member located adjacent the pin.
      <br/>
      An output shaft is rotatably and centrally connected to the second side of the base member, and a plate extends radially outward from the output shaft.
    </p>
    <p num="6">The primary object of the present invention is to provide an actuating device which impacts the plate on the output shaft when the motor rotates at a desired high speed so as to output a sudden and large torque on the object.</p>
    <p num="7">Another object of the present invention is to provide an actuating device wherein the movement of the pin to impact the plate of the output shaft is resulted in the eccentric force caused from the rotation of the base member driven by the motor.</p>
    <p num="8">These and further objects, features and advantages of the present invention will become more obvious from the following description when taken in connection with the accompanying drawings which show, for purposes of illustration only, several embodiments in accordance with the present invention.</p>
    <heading>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
    <p num="9">
      FIG. 1 is a perspective view of the actuating device in accordance with the present invention;
      <br/>
      FIG. 2 is an exploded view of the actuating device in accordance with the present invention;
      <br/>
      FIG. 3 is a side elevational view, partly in section, of the actuating device in accordance with the present invention, wherein the pin is received in the passage and the base member is not yet rotated;
      <br/>
      FIG. 4 is a top cross sectional view to show a ball biased by a spring is engaged with a groove defined in the pin;
      <br/>
      FIG. 5 is an illustrative view to show the position relationship between the plate on the output shaft and the pin when the base member is not yet rotated;
      <br/>
      FIG. 6 is a side elevational view, partly in section, of the actuating device in accordance with the present invention, wherein the pin extends from the second end of the base member by a second part of the actuating member when the base member is rotated by the motor;
      <br/>
      FIG. 7 shows that the force pushing the pin overcomes the force of the spring biasing the ball and the pin extends through the second side of the base member;
      <br/>
      FIG. 8 is an illustrative view to show the rotational pin impacts the plate on the output shaft to let the output shaft rotate, and
      <br/>
      FIG. 9 is an illustrative view to show the output shaft of the actuating device may engage with a socket to loosen bolts of vehicle wheels.
    </p>
    <heading>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
    <p num="10">
      Referring to FIGS. 1 to 4, the actuating device for an electrical power wrench in accordance with the present invention comprises a base member 1 having a tubular member 2 extending from centrally a first side of the base member 1.
      <br/>
      The tubular member 2 has a polygonal hole 21 for receiving a driving shaft 71 of a motor 7 as shown in FIG. 9.
      <br/>
      A passage 11 is defined through the base member 1 and located above the tubular member 2.
      <br/>
      Two blocks 12 extend from the first side of the base member 1 and each block 12 has a notch 122 defined in the inside thereof.
      <br/>
      A rod 123 extends from each distal end of the block 12 and a threaded hole 121 is defined in the distal end of each block 12.
      <br/>
      A side recess 17 is defined laterally through the base member 1 and communicates with the passage 11 so as to receive a spring 34 and a ball 33 in a closed end defining the side recess 17.
    </p>
    <p num="11">
      A pin 3 is movably inserted in the passage 11 and has a head 31 on one of two ends thereof.
      <br/>
      A spring 4 is mounted to the pin 3 and biased between the first side of the base member 1 and the head 31 of the pin 3.
      <br/>
      The spring 4 maintains the pin 3 not to extend from the second side of the base member 1 when the motor is not operated.
      <br/>
      A groove 32 is defined in an outside of the pin 3 and when the pin 3 is inserted into the passage 11, the ball 33 is engaged with the groove 32.
    </p>
    <p num="12">
      A clutch device 6 is connected to the first side of the base member 1 and includes a movable frame 61 which has a U-shaped chamber 610 defined in a side of a first end thereof so as to receive a weight 63 therein.
      <br/>
      Two lugs 612 extend from the movable frame 61 and each lug 612 has an engaging recess 6121 defined in a side thereof.
      <br/>
      Two side plates 611 respectively extend from two ends of the movable member 61 and each side plate 611 further has a dent 6110 so that the movable frame 61 is movably connected to the first side of the base member 1 by two springs 15.
      <br/>
      One end of the spring 15 is engaged with the dent 6110 and the other end of the spring 15 is engaged with the rod 123.
    </p>
    <p num="13">
      An actuating member 62 has a first part 623 engaged with the engaging recesses 6121 in the two lugs 612 of the movable frame 61, and a second part 622 of the actuating member 62 extends from a top of the first part 623 at an angle relative to the first part 622.
      <br/>
      The actuating member 62 has two protrusions 621 extending from two ends thereof and each protrusion 621 has a bearing 64 mounted thereto which is received in the notch 122 of each block 12 so that the actuating member 62 is rotatably engaged between the two blocks 12.
      <br/>
      A retaining plate 16 is connected to the two blocks 12 by two bolts 162 extending through two holes 161 in two ends of the retaining plate 16 and engaged with the threaded holes 121 in the two blocks 12 so as to prevent the actuating member 62 from disengaging from the two notches 122 of the two blocks 12.
    </p>
    <p num="14">
      A U-shaped guide plate 14 is connected to the first side of the base member 1 by extending bolts 142 through two holes 141 in the two ends of the guide plate 14 and engaged with two threaded holes 13 defined in the first side of the base member 1.
      <br/>
      The two sides of the U-shaped guide plate 4 guides the two lugs 612 to be moved along the two sides of the guide plate 14.
    </p>
    <p num="15">
      An output shaft 5 is rotatably and centrally connected to the second side of the base member 1 by mounting a bearing 52 to an end 53 of the output shaft 5.
      <br/>
      The output shaft 5 has a rectangular engaging end 54 so as to be connected to a socket 8 as shown in FIG. 9.
      <br/>
      A plate 51 extends radially outward from the output shaft 5 and has two semi-circular recesses 511 defined in two opposite sides thereof.
    </p>
    <p num="16">
      Referring to FIG. 5, the pin 3 is received in the passage 11 in the base member 1 when the motor 7 does not rotate, the plate 51 does not exert a force to the head 31 of the pin 3.
      <br/>
      Referring to FIGS. 6 to 8, when the motor 7 rotates, the base member 1 together with the movable frame 61 are rotated, the eccentric force will let the movable frame 61 move radially relative to the tubular member 2.
      <br/>
      When the movable frame 61 moves due to the eccentric force, the first part 623 engaged with the two lugs 612 of the movable frame 61 is pulled and the second part 622 is pivoted about the protrusions 621 so as to push the pin 3 extend from the second side of the base member 1 to impact the plate 51 at the position of one of the recesses 511.
      <br/>
      During the rotation of the actuating member 62, the force has to overcome the force of the spring 34 so that once the force is large enough to push the pin 3 to extend from the second side of the base member 1, The output shaft 5 outputs a sudden and large torque.
      <br/>
      The rotation of the base member 1 produces intermittent torque to the object such as bolt so that the bolt is loosened easily.
    </p>
    <p num="17">
      The structure is simple and the torque is generated due to the eccentric force applied to the weight 63 in the movable frame 61 so that no complicated transmission mechanism required.
      <br/>
      The spring 34 and the ball 33 engaged with the groove 32 ensure that only a force large enough to overcome the force of the two springs 4 and 34 can push the pin 3 out from the second side of the base member 1.
      <br/>
      In other words, the pin 3 extends only when the base member 1 is rotated at a high speed so that the pin 3 will not extend from the base member 1 at a lower speed.
      <br/>
      This may avoid useless contact between the pin 3 and the plate 51 on the output shaft 5.
    </p>
    <p num="18">While we have shown and described various embodiments in accordance with the present invention, it should be clear to those skilled in the art that further embodiments may be made without departing from the scope and spirit of the present invention.</p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>What is claimed is:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1.</claim-text>
      <claim-text>An actuating device for an electrical power wrench, comprising:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>a base member having a tubular member extending from centrally a first side of said base member and said tubular member adapted to be connected to a motor, a passage defined through said base member and two blocks extending from said first side of said base member, a side recess defined in said base member and communicating with said passage, a ball received in said side recess and biased by a spring; a movable frame movably connected to said first side of said base member, a weight connected to a first end of said movable frame and two lugs extending from said movable frame, two springs respectively connected between said blocks and said movable frame, a guide plate connected to said first side of said base member and guiding said two lugs; an actuating member having a first part engaged with said two lugs of said movable frame, and a second part of said actuating member extending from said first part at an angle relative to said first part, said actuating member pivotally connected between said two blocks; a pin movably inserted in said passage and biased by a spring mounted to said pin, a groove defined in an outside of said pin, said ball in said side recess being engaged with said groove of said pin; an output shaft rotatably and centrally connected to said second side of said base member, a plate extending radially outward from said output shaft, said movable frame moving radially relative to said tubular member due to a rotation of said base member, and said actuating member pivoted and said pin pushed by said second part to extend from said second side of said base member to impact said plate.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="2">
      <claim-text>2. The device as claimed in claim 1, wherein said plate has two recesses defined in two opposite sides thereof so that said pin engages with one of said recesses when said pin extends from said second side of said base member.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="3">
      <claim-text>3. The device as claimed in claim 1, wherein said two blocks each have a notch and said actuating member has two protrusions extending from two ends thereof so as to be rotatably engaged with said two notches.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="4">
      <claim-text>4. The device as claimed in claim 3 further comprising a retaining plate connected to said two blocks so as to prevent said actuating member from disengaging from said two notches of said two blocks.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="5">
      <claim-text>5. The device as claimed in claim 3, wherein said movable frame has two side plates extending from two ends thereof and each side plate of said movable frame has a bearing mounted thereto which is received in said notch in said block.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="6">
      <claim-text>6. The device as claimed in claim 1, wherein said guide plate is a U-shaped member with two sides, said two lugs of said movable frame located between said two sides of said U-shaped guide plate.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="7">
      <claim-text>7. The device as claimed in claim 1, wherein said two lugs each have an engaging recess defined in a side thereof and said first part of said actuating member is engaged with said two engaging recesses.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="8">
      <claim-text>8. The device as claimed in claim 1, wherein said movable frame has a U-shaped chamber defined therein for receiving said weight therein.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="9">
      <claim-text>9. The device as claimed in claim 1, wherein said movable frame has two side plates extending from two ends thereof and each side plate has a dent, each block having a rod extending therefrom so that one end of said spring is engaged with said dent and the other end of said spring is engaged with said rod.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="10">
      <claim-text>10. The device as claimed in claim 1, wherein said pin has a head so that said spring is biased between said first side of said base member and said head.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>