<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06193289B1.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as first publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06193289</doc-number>
        <kind>B1</kind>
        <date>20010227</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6193289</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B1</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference is-representative="YES" family-id="24230797" extended-family-id="42113009">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>09558744</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>20000421</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>2000US-09558744</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>43171038</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>55874400</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>20000421</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>2000US-09558744</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010227</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>A47J  43/28        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>A</section>
        <class>47</class>
        <subclass>J</subclass>
        <main-group>43</main-group>
        <subgroup>28</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>294008000</text>
        <class>294</class>
        <subclass>008000</subclass>
      </main-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <classifications-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="1">
        <text>A47J-043/28D</text>
        <section>A</section>
        <class>47</class>
        <subclass>J</subclass>
        <main-group>043</main-group>
        <subgroup>28D</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
    </classifications-ecla>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>A47J-043/283</classification-symbol>
        <section>A</section>
        <class>47</class>
        <subclass>J</subclass>
        <main-group>43</main-group>
        <subgroup>283</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>3</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6193289</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Barbeque turner</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="1">
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>450536</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US-450536</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="2">
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>557092</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US-557092</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="3">
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>614016</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US-614016</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="4">
          <text>TOMASKOFF WILLIAM</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>681662</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US-681662</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="5">
          <text>BANKS CHARLES</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>815781</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US-815781</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="6">
          <text>ECKERT FRANK</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>1214522</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US1214522</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="7">
          <text>ANTHONY GIANNICO</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>1553289</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US1553289</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="8">
          <text>PEARSON BENJAMIN F</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>1575275</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US1575275</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="9">
          <text>BROKVIST ERIC R, et al</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>1897999</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US1897999</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="applicant">
        <patcit num="10">
          <text>JOHN IMSCHWEILER</text>
          <document-id>
            <country>US</country>
            <doc-number>2033635</doc-number>
            <kind>A</kind>
          </document-id>
          <document-id data-format="questel">
            <doc-number>US2033635</doc-number>
          </document-id>
        </patcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>BROWN SEAN</name>
          </addressbook>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Brown, Sean</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Euless, TX, 76039, US</address-1>
              <city>Euless</city>
              <state>TX</state>
              <postcode>76039</postcode>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
      <agents>
        <agent sequence="1" rep-type="agent">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Fleishman, Lawrence I.</name>
          </addressbook>
        </agent>
      </agents>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>Cherry, Johnny D.</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>LAPSED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      Disclosed is a Barbeque Turner with a plate, an armature and a handle.
      <br/>
      Food, which is engaged by the plate, is turned by the pull of a trigger which actuates gears within the handle which, in turn, rotate that armature and the plate which is attached thereto.
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <heading>CROSS REFERENCES TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
    <p num="1">None</p>
    <heading>STATEMENTS AS TO RIGHTS TO INVENTIONS MADE UNDER FEDERALLY SPONSORED</heading>
    <heading>RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT</heading>
    <p num="2">None</p>
    <heading>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="3">
      1.
      <br/>
      Field of the Invention
    </p>
    <p num="4">
      This invention relates generally to a device for turning over items that are being cooked.
      <br/>
      More particularly, this invention comprises a device that turns over items that are being barbequed or grilled.
    </p>
    <p num="5">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
    <p num="6">
      People who grill or barbeque food use manual devices, such as spatulas and forks, to turn the food that is being cooked.
      <br/>
      This is especially inconvenient when cooking with the newer barbeque ovens which have multiple, closely spaced cooking grids because there is not enough room to turn the food by hand.
      <br/>
      Around the turn of the century, there were several inventions that allowed food to be turned with a mechanical device.
      <br/>
      However, these inventions have their mechanisms open to the outside and are not well suited to modern safety standards, manufacturing or fabrication techniques.
      <br/>
      Therefore, it is desirable to have a simple, closed device that turns over the food being cooked that can easily be manufactured by modern techniques with modern materials.
    </p>
    <heading>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="7">
      The object of the current invention is to provide a device that can be used to turn over items that are being barbequed or cooked.
      <br/>
      The current invention provides such a device with a mechanically activated rotation mechanism.
    </p>
    <p num="8">
      The invention comprises a handle, an armature and a plate.
      <br/>
      The handle contains a set of three gears, an external trigger and most of the armature.
      <br/>
      The user places the plate under the object to be turned and presses the trigger.
      <br/>
      The action of the trigger, through the gears, rotates the plate through 180 degrees and flips the object.
      <br/>
      A spring flips the plate back to the original position.
      <br/>
      The plate is removably fixed to the armature outside of the handle to facilitate changes in plates for different applications.
      <br/>
      The advantages of the invention are that the mechanism is closed and the user can flip the food in a narrow space because he need not turn his wrist when actuating the devise.
    </p>
    <heading>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
    <p num="9">
      FIG. 1 is an isometric view of the invention.
      <br/>
      FIG. 2 is a top view of the invention.
      <br/>
      FIG. 3 is a side cross section of the handle of the invention.
      <br/>
      FIG. 4 is a front cross sectional view of the gears for an alternate preferred embodiment.
    </p>
    <heading>DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
    <p num="10">
      The preferred embodiment of the invention is best understood by referring to the drawings.
      <br/>
      As shown in FIG. 1 the present invention is comprised of a plate 1, an armature 2, and a handle 3.
    </p>
    <p num="11">
      Referring further to FIG. 2, the plate 1 consists of a plate 4 and a rod 5.
      <br/>
      The forward portion 6 of the plate 4 is horizontal when in use and the rearward portion 7 of the plate is bent upward from the horizontal.
      <br/>
      Although the plate as illustrated is in the form of a spatula, other forms, such as a fork, may be used.
      <br/>
      The rod 5 has a front portion 8 that extends from and in the same plane as the rearward portion 7 of the plate 4 and a rear portion 9 that bends back toward the horizontal and lies in the same plane as the forward portion 6 of the plate 4.
      <br/>
      The rod 5 is typically attached to the plate 1 with rivets 10.
      <br/>
      The rear portion 9 of the rod 5 is threaded 11 to allow other plates, such as a fork, to be attached to the armature 2.
      <br/>
      The armature 2 passes through a front bearing 14 and a rear bearing 15 that are disposed in opposite ends of the handle 3.
    </p>
    <p num="12">
      Referring further to FIG. 3, the handle 3 is comprised of an inner sleeve 25 and an outer sleeve 26.
      <br/>
      The inner sleeve can be metal, plastic or any other material that is convenient to fabricate, sufficiently strong and can withstand the heat.
      <br/>
      In the preferred embodiment of the invention, metal is used.
      <br/>
      The outer sleeve must be thermally insulating and able to withstand heat.
      <br/>
      Wood is used in the preferred invention.
    </p>
    <p num="13">
      The front portion of the armature 2 has a sleeve 12 which is threaded 13 to engage the rear portion 9 of the rod 5.
      <br/>
      The armature is further stabilized by a mounting bracket 27 within the handle 3.
      <br/>
      A crown pinion gear 15 is attached to the portion of the armature 2 that is within the handle 3.
    </p>
    <p num="14">
      A trigger 16 is attached to a trigger shaft 17 which is disposed in the handle 3 so as to be perpendicular to the armature 2.
      <br/>
      The trigger 16, which is attached to the trigger shaft 17, extends through an opening 18 in the handle 3.
      <br/>
      A trigger guard 21 is mechanically attached with bolts 28 to the handle 3 in the vicinity of the trigger 16 and the opening 18 in the handle 3.
    </p>
    <p num="15">
      A trigger spur gear 19 is also attached to the trigger shaft 17.
      <br/>
      A transfer spur gear 29 is attached to a transfer shaft 20 that is disposed in the handle 3 so as to be parallel to the trigger shaft 17.
      <br/>
      The trigger shaft 17, trigger spur gear 19, transfer shaft 20, and transfer spur gear 29 are all positioned relative to one another and the armature 2 and crown pinion gear 15 so the gears mesh as shown in FIG. 3.
      <br/>
      The number of teeth in each gear and the respective gear ratios are such that a squeeze of the trigger rotates the plate through approximately 180 degrees.
    </p>
    <p num="16">
      While there are many trigger displacements, gear ratios and gear sizes that will accomplish this, the preferred embodiment uses a trigger displacement of 52 degrees, a 11/16" diameter pinion gear with 34 teeth, a 3/8" diameter spur gear with 20 teeth and a 5/16" diameter crown gear with 10 teeth.
      <br/>
      The gears can be made of plastic, nylon, metal or any other convenient material that will withstand the heat.
    </p>
    <p num="17">When the trigger 16 is released, the plate 4, is returned to its original position by a rotary spring 30 that is fixed between the armature 2 and the handle 3.</p>
    <p num="18">
      In a second embodiment of the invention, as shown in FIGS. 1, 2 and 3 as modified by FIG. 4, a trigger bevel gear 22 is attached to a trigger shaft 17, a transfer bevel gear 23 is attached to the transfer shaft 20 and a bevel pinion gear 24 is attached to the armature 2.
      <br/>
      In this embodiment, the shafts may be oblique to one another if the bevel gears are hypoid.
      <br/>
      The trigger shaft 17, trigger bevel gear 22, transfer shaft 20, and transfer bevel gear 23 are all positioned relative to one another and the armature 2 and bevel pinion gear 24 so the gears mesh as shown in FIG. 4.
      <br/>
      While there are many trigger displacements, gear ratios and gear sizes that will accomplish this, the preferred embodiment uses a trigger displacement of 52 degrees, a 11/16" diameter pinion gear with 34 teeth, a 3/8" diameter spur gear with 20 teeth and a 5/16" diameter crown gear with 10 teeth.
    </p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>What is claimed is:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1.</claim-text>
      <claim-text>A Barbeque Turner comprising:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>a. an armature rotatably disposed through a handle, b. a trigger shaft disposed within said handle, c. a trigger attached to said trigger shaft and extending through an opening in said handle, d. a trigger bevel gear disposed on said trigger shaft, e. a transfer shaft disposed in said handle, f. a transfer bevel gear attached to said transfer shaft, g. a bevel pinion gear attached to said armature, h. said shafts being disposed within said handle and said gears being attached to said shafts so a displacement of said trigger causes the rotation of said trigger bevel gear which causes a rotation of said transfer bevel gear which causes a rotation of said bevel pinion gear and said armature, and i. a plate attached to a portion of said armature that extends outside of said handle.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="2">
      <claim-text>2. The Barbeque Turner in claim 1 wherein a. said trigger shaft is perpendicular to said armature, and b. said transfer shaft is parallel to said trigger shaft.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="3">
      <claim-text>3. The Barbeque Turner in claim 2 wherein a. said bevel pinion gear is a crown pinion gear, b. said transfer bevel gear is a transfer spur gear, and c. said trigger bevel gear is a trigger spur gear.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>