<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questel-patent-document lang="en" date-produced="20180805" produced-by="Questel" schema-version="3.23" file="US06184343B2.xml">
  <bibliographic-data lang="en">
    <publication-reference publ-desc="Granted patent as second publication">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>06184343</doc-number>
        <kind>B2</kind>
        <date>20010206</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>US6184343</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </publication-reference>
    <original-publication-kind>B2</original-publication-kind>
    <application-reference is-representative="YES" family-id="26709463" extended-family-id="42112103">
      <document-id>
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>08986304</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19971205</date>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel">
        <doc-number>1997US-08986304</doc-number>
      </document-id>
      <document-id data-format="questel_Uid">
        <doc-number>43169772</doc-number>
      </document-id>
    </application-reference>
    <language-of-filing>en</language-of-filing>
    <language-of-publication>en</language-of-publication>
    <priority-claims>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="1">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>98630497</doc-number>
        <kind>A</kind>
        <date>19971205</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="1">
        <doc-number>1997US-08986304</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim kind="national" sequence="2">
        <country>US</country>
        <doc-number>3324796</doc-number>
        <kind>P</kind>
        <date>19961206</date>
        <priority-active-indicator>Y</priority-active-indicator>
      </priority-claim>
      <priority-claim data-format="questel" sequence="2">
        <doc-number>1996US-60033247</doc-number>
      </priority-claim>
    </priority-claims>
    <dates-of-public-availability>
      <publication-of-grant-date>
        <date>20010206</date>
      </publication-of-grant-date>
    </dates-of-public-availability>
    <classifications-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="1">
        <text>C07K  14/47        20060101A I20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>C</section>
        <class>07</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>14</main-group>
        <subgroup>47</subgroup>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
      <classification-ipcr sequence="2">
        <text>A61K  38/00        20060101A N20051008RMEP</text>
        <ipc-version-indicator>
          <date>20060101</date>
        </ipc-version-indicator>
        <classification-level>A</classification-level>
        <section>A</section>
        <class>61</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>38</main-group>
        <subgroup>00</subgroup>
        <classification-value>N</classification-value>
        <generating-office>
          <country>EP</country>
        </generating-office>
        <classification-status>R</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>M</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20051008</date>
        </action-date>
      </classification-ipcr>
    </classifications-ipcr>
    <classification-national>
      <country>US</country>
      <main-classification>
        <text>530300000</text>
        <class>530</class>
        <subclass>300000</subclass>
      </main-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="1">
        <text>530324000</text>
        <class>530</class>
        <subclass>324000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
      <further-classification sequence="2">
        <text>530350000</text>
        <class>530</class>
        <subclass>350000</subclass>
      </further-classification>
    </classification-national>
    <classifications-ecla>
      <classification-ecla sequence="1">
        <text>C07K-014/47A1B</text>
        <section>C</section>
        <class>07</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>014</main-group>
        <subgroup>47A1B</subgroup>
      </classification-ecla>
    </classifications-ecla>
    <patent-classifications>
      <patent-classification sequence="1">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>C07K-014/4705</classification-symbol>
        <section>C</section>
        <class>07</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>14</main-group>
        <subgroup>4705</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>I</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
      <patent-classification sequence="2">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="CPC">
          <date>20130101</date>
        </classification-scheme>
        <classification-symbol>A61K-038/00</classification-symbol>
        <section>A</section>
        <class>61</class>
        <subclass>K</subclass>
        <main-group>38</main-group>
        <subgroup>00</subgroup>
        <symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
        <classification-value>A</classification-value>
        <classification-status>B</classification-status>
        <classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
        <action-date>
          <date>20130101</date>
        </action-date>
      </patent-classification>
      <patent-classification sequence="3">
        <classification-scheme office="EP" scheme="ICO"/>
        <classification-symbol>K61K-038/00</classification-symbol>
      </patent-classification>
    </patent-classifications>
    <number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
    <exemplary-claim>1</exemplary-claim>
    <figures>
      <number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
      <number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
      <image-key data-format="questel">US6184343</image-key>
    </figures>
    <invention-title format="original" lang="en" id="title_en">Fetal globin inducing factor</invention-title>
    <references-cited>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <nplcit num="1">
          <text>Berendsen, Science, vol. 282, pp. 642-643, Oct. 1998.</text>
        </nplcit>
      </citation>
      <citation srep-phase="examiner">
        <nplcit num="2">
          <text>Caldwell, Yakubutsu Dotai (Xenobiotic Matabolism and Disposition), vol. 11(1), pp. 119-125, 1996.</text>
        </nplcit>
      </citation>
    </references-cited>
    <related-documents>
      <related-publication>
        <document-id>
          <country>US</country>
          <doc-number>60/033,247</doc-number>
          <date>19961206</date>
        </document-id>
        <document-id>
          <country>US</country>
          <doc-number>60/033247</doc-number>
          <date>19961206</date>
        </document-id>
      </related-publication>
    </related-documents>
    <parties>
      <applicants>
        <applicant app-type="applicant" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>STAMATOYANNOPOULOS GEORGE</name>
          </addressbook>
        </applicant>
        <applicant app-type="applicant" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>PAPAYANNOPOULOU THALIA</name>
          </addressbook>
        </applicant>
      </applicants>
      <inventors>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="1">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Stamatoyannopoulos, George</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Seattle, WA, 98122, US</address-1>
              <city>Seattle</city>
              <state>WA</state>
              <postcode>98122</postcode>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
        <inventor data-format="original" sequence="2">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <name>Papayannopoulou, Thalia</name>
            <address>
              <address-1>Seattle, WA, 98122, US</address-1>
              <city>Seattle</city>
              <state>WA</state>
              <postcode>98122</postcode>
              <country>US</country>
            </address>
          </addressbook>
          <nationality>
            <country>US</country>
          </nationality>
        </inventor>
      </inventors>
      <agents>
        <agent sequence="1" rep-type="agent">
          <addressbook lang="en">
            <orgname>Baker Botts, L.L.P.</orgname>
          </addressbook>
        </agent>
      </agents>
    </parties>
    <examiners>
      <primary-examiner>
        <name>McKelvey, Terry</name>
      </primary-examiner>
    </examiners>
    <lgst-data>
      <lgst-status>LAPSED</lgst-status>
    </lgst-data>
  </bibliographic-data>
  <abstract format="original" lang="en" id="abstr_en">
    <p id="P-EN-00001" num="00001">
      <br/>
      The invention is directed to fetal globin inducing factor (FGIF), and to nucleic acids encoding FGIF.
      <br/>
      FGIF controls the expression of fetal globin gene products.
      <br/>
      An FGIF polypeptide is shown in FIG. 3 and nucleotide sequences that encode FGIF polypeptides are shown in FIGS. 1 and 2.
      <br/>
      The invention is also directed to therapeutic methods employing FGIF polypeptides, encoding nucleic acids and functional fragments thereof for the treatment of globin disorders and to methods for screening compounds that modulate fetal globin gene expression as well as compounds identified by these methods.
    </p>
  </abstract>
  <description format="original" lang="en" id="desc_en">
    <heading>CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
    <p num="1">
      This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Patent Application Ser.
      <br/>
      No. 60/033,247, filed Dec. 6, 1996.
    </p>
    <heading>FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="2">
      This invention relates to nucleic acids that encode fetal globin inducing factor and to fetal globin inducing factor.
      <br/>
      The invention also relates to methods for altering globin expression by the regulation of globin transcription.
    </p>
    <heading>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="3">
      Oxygen is transported throughout multicellular animals through the function of hemoglobin.
      <br/>
      The most primitive of these oxygen-carrying molecules, or globins, is a single polypeptide of about 150 amino acid residues and is utilized in worms, insects, and primitive fish.
      <br/>
      In higher adult vertebrates two types of globin chains exist.
      <br/>
      These chains are referred to as the  ALPHA  and  BETA  globins and make up a tetrameric hemoglobin molecule composed of two  ALPHA  and two  BETA  chains, or  ALPHA 2 BETA 2.
      <br/>
      Through a series of gene duplications during evolution, other globin chains also exist and exhibit developmental and stage specific expression.
      <br/>
      These other globins include  GAMMA  globin which is specifically expressed in the fetus to produce an  ALPHA 2 GAMMA 2 hemoglobin.
      <br/>
      This fetal hemoglobin exhibits higher affinity for oxygen than adult  ALPHA 2 BETA 2 hemoglobin.
      <br/>
      Another globin chain arising during evolution is the  DELTA  globin which gives rise to the minor hemoglobin  ALPHA 2 DELTA 2 found in adult primates.
      <br/>
      Finally, an  EPSILON  globin also exists which results in another embryonic form of hemoglobin having the composition  ALPHA 2 EPSILON 2.
    </p>
    <p num="4">Abnormalities in the structure or in the rate of synthesis of the various globin chains result in a variety of different pathological conditions which can be classified into two distinct groups (Stamatoyannopoulos and Nienhuis, Molecular Basis of Blood Diseases, Stamatoyannopoulos et al. (eds.), Philadelphia pp. 108-136, 1994; D. J. Weatherall, Molecular Basis of blood Diseases, Stamatoyannopoulos et al. (eds.), Philadelphia pp. 161-195, 1994; and Bunn, H. F., Molecular Basis of Blood Diseases, Stamatoyannopoulos et al. (eds.), Philadelphia pp. 208-244, 1994).</p>
    <p num="5">
      The first classification is where structural abnormalities of  ALPHA  or  BETA  globin genes exist.
      <br/>
      These abnormalities are called hemoglobinopathies.
      <br/>
      There are over 500 different mutations of  ALPHA  or  BETA  globin genes producing abnormal hemoglobins.
      <br/>
      The most common hemoglobinopathy is the sickle hemoglobin or hemoglobin S (Hb S) which represents the substitution of valine for glutamic acid in position six of the  BETA  globin subunit.
      <br/>
      The sickle cell gene is frequent among Black people; about eight to ten percent of African-Americans carry the Hb S gene while in certain populations of Africa, like in Nigeria, twenty-five percent of the population carries sickle cell trait.
      <br/>
      There are about 120,000 new cases of sickle cell disease born each year.
      <br/>
      It is estimated that the prevalence of homozygous Hb S patients in the United States is between 60,000 and 80,000.
      <br/>
      Sickle cell disease is a severe disease characterized by frequent painful crises, hemolytic anemia and severe organ damage due to intravascular sickling.
      <br/>
      The life span of these patients is significantly decreased.
    </p>
    <p num="6">
      Evidence now indicates that elevated levels of fetal hemoglobins (Hb F) attenuate the severity of sickle cell disease.
      <br/>
      As is well known, Hb S molecules tend to form long, intracellular polymers upon deoxygenation.
      <br/>
      Physiological effects of sickle cell mutations are due, in large part, to abnormalities in the rheological properties of blood.
      <br/>
      The rate of sickle cell hemoglobin polymerization is largely dependent on the concentration of Hb S in the red cell.
      <br/>
      The presence of fetal hemoglobin in sickle red cells affects Hb S polymerization by decreasing the concentration of the abnormal molecule and, most importantly, by failing to participate in polymer formation.
      <br/>
      In addition to this biochemical evidence, genetic evidence similarly indicates that high levels of Hb F have therapeutic effects in sickle cell disease.
      <br/>
      For example, compound heterozygotes inheriting a sickle cell gene and a gene for hereditary persistence of fetal hemoglobin have no clinical manifestations when Hb F exceeds twenty-five percent of total hemoglobin content (75% of hemoglobin in these patients is Hb S).
      <br/>
      Similar observations exist for persons who carry the combination of the sickle cell gene and a condition called  DELTA  BETA  thalassemia which is associated with high levels of Hb F.
    </p>
    <p num="7">
      The levels of Hb F required for therapeutic benefit in sickle cell disease have been investigated in several studies.
      <br/>
      In a prospective study, Hb F levels in excess of ten percent were associated with fewer episodes of aseptic necrosis, while levels greater than twenty percent were associated with fewer painful crises and pulmonary complications.
      <br/>
      In a large prospective study of the natural history of sickle cell disease, the frequency of painful crises was found to be inversely proportional to the square of the Hb F level.
      <br/>
      These results indicate that even modest elevations in Hb F can yield therapeutic benefits.
      <br/>
      It is generally accepted that production of over twenty-five percent fetal hemoglobin in the red cell can cure sickle cell disease.
    </p>
    <p num="8">
      The second classification is where abnormalities in globin chain synthesis exist.
      <br/>
      These abnormalities are called  ALPHA ,  BETA , or  DELTA  BETA  thalassemia syndromes.
      <br/>
      An example of these abnormalities is the  BETA  thalassemia syndromes.
      <br/>
      Beta ( BETA ) thalassemia genes are common among people of Mediterranean and Asian descent.
      <br/>
      About 100,000 patients with homozygous thalassemia, or combinations of  BETA  thalassemia with abnormal hemoglobins, are born each year in this area of the world.
      <br/>
      In  BETA  thalassemia there is either a total absence or a severe deficiency of  BETA  globin gene.
      <br/>
      However,  ALPHA  chain production continues at normal levels.
      <br/>
      These excess  ALPHA  globin chains accumulate and precipitate within erythroblasts resulting in ineffective erythropoiesis and cell death, both of which are characteristic of the thalassemia syndromes.
    </p>
    <p num="9">
      Precipitation of  ALPHA  chains in circulating erythrocytes and consequential membrane damage is responsible for the hemolytic syndrome.
      <br/>
      Patients with homozygous  BETA  thalassemia survive beyond the period of the switch from fetal to adult globin formation because some level of Hb F production continues in the adult stage of development.
      <br/>
      Sufficient  GAMMA  gene expression occurs in only a small proportion of erythroblasts.
      <br/>
      Cells which contain adequate levels of Hb F survive and thereby provide red cells which are released in the periphery.
      <br/>
      The efficiency of  GAMMA  globin production in erythroblasts of patients with  BETA  thalassemia clearly determines the severity of their clinical course.
      <br/>
      It is accepted that any increase of fetal hemoglobin will have therapeutic effects in  BETA  thalassemia syndromes.
      <br/>
      Production of over twenty-five percent of fetal hemoglobin per cell can cure the disease of patients with homozygous  BETA  thalassemia.
    </p>
    <p num="10">
      Attempts have been made to augment the expression of fetal hemoglobin for the therapeutic treatment of sickle cell disease or homozygous  BETA  thalassemia (Blau and Stamatoyannopoulos, Hematology Trends '93, Lechner et al. (eds.), Stuttgart-New York, pp 144-158, 1993).
      <br/>
      For example, 5-azacytidine induces fetal hemoglobin in animals and patients with thalassemia or sickle cell disease.
      <br/>
      However, its use was discontinued because it has been shown that this drug is carcinogenic.
      <br/>
      Hydroxyurea, a cytotoxic drug used in cancer chemotherapy, has also been shown to induce fetal hemoglobin in experimental animals.
      <br/>
      This compound kills mature erythroid cells and induces a fast downstream differentiation of immature cells.
      <br/>
      Treatment of sickle cell patients with hydroxyurea results in induction of fetal hemoglobin which reaches therapeutic levels in a small proportion of patients.
      <br/>
      However, induction of fetal hemoglobin occurs only when blood cytotoxicity appears as measured by decreased white blood cell counts.
      <br/>
      Furthermore, issues related to the wisdom of life long treatment with a cytotoxic drug which may also be carcinogenic remain especially for the treatment of children.
      <br/>
      Further, a large portion of patients respond to the hydroxyurea treatment with only small or moderate elevations of fetal hemoglobin.
      <br/>
      Hydroxyurea does not induce fetal hemoglobin in patients with homozygous  BETA  thalassemia.
    </p>
    <p num="11">
      Another form of treatment involves intravenous administration of arginine butyrate.
      <br/>
      This compound induces fetal hemoglobin synthesis in primates and has been reported to induce fetal hemoglobin in patients with homozygous  BETA  thalassemia receiving continuous IV infusion of butyrate for two to three weeks.
      <br/>
      However, a second study in which patients with homozygous  BETA  thalassemia or Hb S disease were treated with continuous intravenous (IV) infusion of butyrate for up to two or three months did not reproduce these results.
      <br/>
      Most recently intermittent IV treatment with butyrate (two days every 15 days) has been shown to increase fetal hemoglobin in a few patients.
      <br/>
      It is still unclear whether this treatment can increase fetal hemoglobin to the levels required for a cure or a significant clinical improvement.
      <br/>
      Also, the side effects of treating children with IV administration of butyrate have not been determined.
    </p>
    <p num="12">Although it is generally accepted that induction of fetal hemoglobin can cure patients with Hb S disease or  BETA  thalassemia, there is a need for better compositions and methods which augment the regulation of globin gene expression.</p>
    <heading>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="13">The present invention overcomes the problems and disadvantages associated with current strategies and designs and provides new compositions and methods for the regulation of globin gene expression.</p>
    <p num="14">
      One embodiment of the invention is directed to proteins and peptides that encode fetal globin inducing factor (FGIF).
      <br/>
      This factor, and active portions thereof, can function to regulate the expression of globin genes such as fetal globin.
      <br/>
      FGIF, either purified recombinantly produced, can be used in the treatment of globin and associated disorders.
    </p>
    <p num="15">
      Another embodiment of the invention is directed to nucleic acids encoding FGIF and active portions thereof.
      <br/>
      FGIF proteins and polypeptides are encoded in the nucleotide sequences of FIGS. 1 and 2.
      <br/>
      These nucleic acids can be used to produce large quantities of FGIF protein, peptides, fragments or active portions thereof.
      <br/>
      The invention further comprises nucleic acid vectors containing FGIF sequences and cells, which may be eukaryotic or prokaryotic, transformed with FGIF sequences.
    </p>
    <p num="16">
      Another embodiment of the invention is directed to methods for regulating globin transcription.
      <br/>
      Regulation can be effected by administration of FGIF, nucleic acids that express FGIF or agents that alter FGIF expression or activity.
      <br/>
      Regulation of globin transcription can ameliorate disorders such as hemoglobinopathies and associated globin disorders.
      <br/>
      Preferably, regulation involves increasing fetal hemoglobin expression.
    </p>
    <p num="17">
      Another embodiment of the invention is directed to methods for screening compounds that regulate globin gene expression.
      <br/>
      Compounds identified can be used in vitro and in vivo in the treatment of globin disorders.
    </p>
    <p num="18">
      Other embodiments and advantages of the invention are set forth, in part, in the description which follows and, in part, will be obvious from this description or may be learned from the practice of the invention.
      <br/>
      DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS
      <br/>
      FIG. 1 Nucleotide sequence of the human FGIF cDNA (SEQ ID NO: 1).
      <br/>
      FIG. 2 Comparison of the human (top) and murine (bottom) FGIF nucleotide sequence (SEQ ID NO: 2).
      <br/>
      FIG. 3 Amino acid sequence of mature human FGIF comprising 239 amino acid residues that contain three ankyrin sequence motifs (SEQ ID NO: 3).
      <br/>
      FIG. 4 FGIF function as a transcriptional activator.
      <br/>
      FIG. 5 Induction of human fetal globin by FGIF.
    </p>
    <heading>DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
    <p num="19">As embodied and broadly described herein, the present invention is directed to amino acid and nucleic acid sequences that encode proteins and peptides of fetal globin inducing factor and active portions thereof, and to compositions and methods for modifying the expression of globin genes.</p>
    <p num="20">
      Many attempts have been made to augment the expression of hemoglobin in humans and, in particular, fetal hemoglobin, for the therapeutic treatment of sickle cell disease, thalassemia and related disorders.
      <br/>
      Increases in Hb F levels in, for example, sickle cell patients produced fewer episodes of aseptic necrosis.
      <br/>
      Increases of greater than twenty percent were associated with fewer painful crises and pulmonary complications.
      <br/>
      In fact, the frequency of crises was found to be inversely proportional to the square of Hb F level indicating that even modest elevations in Hb F can yield therapeutic benefits.
    </p>
    <p num="21">
      Conventional efforts have been focused on identifying agents that simply increase Hb F levels in patients.
      <br/>
      However, the steps by which such increases can occur have largely been ignored.
      <br/>
      In efforts to analyze these steps, a factor was discovered that regulates transcription of fetal hemoglobin.
      <br/>
      That factor is referred to herein as fetal hemoglobin inducing factor (FGIF) which, as used herein, includes full length FGIF protein as well as active and functional peptides and fragments thereof.
    </p>
    <p num="22">
      FGIF was discovered during a systematic search for mRNAs encoding factors that induce human fetal hemoglobin genes.
      <br/>
      For this search, somatic cell hybrids were formed by fusing human fetal erythroid cells with mouse erythroleukemia cells.
      <br/>
      Initially, hybrids produce human fetal hemoglobin.
      <br/>
      After several months in culture, these hybrids switched from production of fetal hemoglobin to production of human adult hemoglobin (Papayannopoulou et al., Cell 46:469-476, 1986).
      <br/>
      Transcriptional inducers of fetal hemoglobin were sought among mRNA species that were present in both the human fetal erythroid cells and the fetal globin expressing hybrids, but absent in both the adult erythroid cells and the adult globin expressing hybrids.
      <br/>
      One such mRNA species discovered encoded FGIF.
    </p>
    <p num="23">
      One embodiment of the invention is directed to FGIF proteins, peptides and fragments, and active or functional portions thereof.
      <br/>
      These proteins, peptides and fragments are collectively referred to herein as FGIF.
      <br/>
      FGIF further includes amino acid sequences considered by those of ordinary skill in the art as functionally or structurally equivalent to an FGIF sequence.
      <br/>
      Methods for assessing functional and structural equivalency are well known and routine within the art.
      <br/>
      A human FGIF polypeptide comprising 239 amino acids is shown in FIG. 3.
    </p>
    <p num="24">
      Functionally equivalent FGIF amino acid sequences include, for example, sequences that are related in that at least one functional activity of FGIF is present.
      <br/>
      Such related, but different polypeptides include, for example, substitutions of conserved and non-essential amino acids.
      <br/>
      Functionally equivalent FGIF includes modifications of FGIF which may be made without destroying the biological function of the FGIF polypeptide.
      <br/>
      For example, only a portion of the entire primary structure may be required for effective activity.
      <br/>
      Modifications of the FGIF amino acid sequence which does not destroy its activity also fall within the definition of FGIF.
      <br/>
      Structurally equivalent FGIF sequences include genetically engineered fragments of FGIF, either individually, modified or fused to heterologous proteins such as fusion proteins that retain measurable biological activity; these also fall within the definition of the FGIF polypeptides.
    </p>
    <p num="25">
      Structural and functional modification of FGIF may comprise modifications of the primary amino acid sequence of FGIF wherein the resulting polypeptides have substantially equivalent or enhanced function as compared to the sequence set forth in FIG. 3.
      <br/>
      These modifications may be deliberate, for example, through site-directed mutagenesis, or may be accidental such as through mutation in hosts which are FGIF producers.
      <br/>
      All of these modifications are included as long as FGIF biological function is retained.
    </p>
    <p num="26">
      Further, modified FGIF protein may comprise modification of one or more amino acids within the FGIF amino acid sequence.
      <br/>
      For example, the FGIF amino acid sequence may be altered by substituting other natural or non-natural amino acids for those present in the wild-type sequence.
      <br/>
      Natural amino acids are those commonly found in proteins from eukaryotic sources.
      <br/>
      Non-natural amino acids include chemically or biologically altered forms of natural amino acids or amino acids that are chemically synthesized.
      <br/>
      Non-natural amino acids also include unusual and modified amino acids such as, for example, aminoadipic acid, aminobutyric acid, desmosine, hydroxyproline, allo-isoleucine and many others which are well-known in the art.
      <br/>
      Modified FGIF proteins also include fusion proteins containing FGIF sequences.
      <br/>
      For example, various molecules can be attached to FGIF such as other proteins, carbohydrates, lipids, or chemical moieties.
      <br/>
      Such modifications are included within the definition of FGIF proteins and peptides.
    </p>
    <p num="27">
      FGIF has been purified and isolated from both human and murine sources and is present in all mammalian cells including other primate cells.
      <br/>
      Cell types that express FGIF include circulating cells, cells of the bone marrow, cells of the myeloid system.
      <br/>
      Specific cells include, for example, platelets, white blood cells, erythroid cells and their precursors such as stem cells, myeloid stem cells, erythrocyte-colony forming unit cells (E-CFU), erythrocyte-burst forming unit cells (E-BFU), and pro-erythrocytes.
    </p>
    <p num="28">
      FGIF can be prepared as a composition for administration in vivo or in vitro.
      <br/>
      FGIF compositions can be prepared in solution as a dispersion, mixture, liquid, spray, capsule or as a dry solid such as a powder or pill, as appropriate or desired.
      <br/>
      Solid forms may be processed into tablets or capsules or mixed or dissolved with a liquid such as water, alcohol, saline or other salt solutions, glycerol, saccharides or polysaccharide, oil or a relatively inert solid or liquid.
      <br/>
      Liquids administered orally may include flavoring agents such as mint, cherry, guava, citrus, cinnamon, orange, mango, or mixed fruit flavors to increase palatability.
      <br/>
      Pills, capsules or tablets administered orally may also include flavoring agents.
      <br/>
      Additionally, all compositions may further comprise agents to increase shelf-life, such as preservatives, anti-oxidants and other components necessary and suitable for manufacture and distribution of the composition.
      <br/>
      Compositions further comprise a pharmaceutically acceptable carrier.
      <br/>
      Carriers are chemical or multi-chemical compounds that do not significantly alter or effect the active ingredients of the compositions.
      <br/>
      Examples include water, alcohols such as glycerol and polyethylene glycol, glycerin, oils, salts such as sodium, potassium, magnesium and ammonium, fatty acids, saccharides or polysacchaides.
      <br/>
      Carriers may be single substances or chemical or physical combinations of these substances.
    </p>
    <p num="29">
      As FGIF can be easily produced through recombinant technology or purification from cell sources, antibodies to FGIF can also be created.
      <br/>
      Antibodies may be polyclonal or monoclonal as desired.
      <br/>
      Monoclonal antibodies preferably target functionally active portions of the protein, such as the ankyrin site, and can be used in vitro or in vivo as agents that alter FGIF activity.
      <br/>
      Methods for the generation of both polyclonal and monoclonal antibodies from protein samples are well know to those of ordinary skill in the art (e.g. Current Protocols in Immunology, J. E. Coligan et al. (eds.), John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York).
    </p>
    <p num="30">
      Another embodiment of the invention is directed to nucleic acid sequences that encode FGIF proteins, peptides and fragments, and functionally or structurally equivalent portions thereof.
      <br/>
      As before, methods for assessing functional and structural equivalency are well known and routine within the art.
      <br/>
      Functionally equivalent nucleic acid sequences include, for example, sequences that encode different, but equivalent FGIF polypeptides whose differences can be attributed to degeneracy of the genetic code.
      <br/>
      However, these FGIF polypeptides would also exhibit similar functional activity.
      <br/>
      In such cases, the respective nucleic acids encode functionally equivalent gene products.
    </p>
    <p num="31">
      In addition, functional fragments of FGIF encoding nucleic acids such as oligonucleotides, polyoligonucleotides, primers and the like are also within the definition of the term FGIF.
      <br/>
      Functional equivalency is also present with FGIF nucleic acids that do not encode gene products but, for example, are functional elements in and of themselves.
      <br/>
      Specific examples of such functional nucleic acids include promoters, enhancers and other gene expression regulatory elements.
    </p>
    <p num="32">
      Sequences encoding FGIF proteins, peptides and fragments may comprise DNA, RNA or PNA sequences which may be double-stranded or single-stranded.
      <br/>
      These sequences may comprise the nucleotides characteristic of DNA (e.g. A, G, C, T), RNA (e.g. A, G, C, U) or PNA (e.g nucleotide bases covalently connected to a polyamide backbone), or, alternatively, may contain one or more modified nucleotide bases.
      <br/>
      Modified bases include, for example, acetylcytidine, dihydrouridine, inosine, methylated bases, methoxyuridine and many others, all of which are well known to those of ordinary skill in the art.
    </p>
    <p num="33">
      FGIF sequences may also be inserted in prokaryotic or eukaryotic cells to form recombinant cells that express or are capable of expressing FGIF.
      <br/>
      For example, prokaryotic cells such as E. coli can be transformed with FGIF nucleic acid sequences.
      <br/>
      Eukaryotic cells can be transfected with FGIF nucleic acids or FGIF-containing nucleic acid vectors using procedures that are well-known in the art (e.g Current Protocols in Molecular Biology, F. M. Ausubel et al. (eds.), John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York).
      <br/>
      Transfected sequences may be maintained as episomal or integrated into the host cell genome.
      <br/>
      FGIF protein can be continuously or, upon induction, selectively expressed from these cells as desired by incorporating transcriptional or translational control sequences such as promoters, enhancers, operators, termination sites, etc., all of which are well known to those of ordinary skill in the art.
      <br/>
      Recombinant cells containing FGIF sequences can be maintained, expanded to produce large quantities of nucleic acids, or induced to express large quantities of FGIF.
    </p>
    <p num="34">
      Another embodiment of the invention is directed to methods for the treatment of globin disorders by regulation of FGIF activity or expression.
      <br/>
      FGIF and agents that regulate FGIF expression can mediate the severity of globin disorders such as sickle cell anemia and thalassemia, and associated disorders by increasing or decreasing globin gene expression.
      <br/>
      For example, many globin disorders can be mediated by increased fetal globin gene expression.
      <br/>
      FGIF protein and peptides, and functional fragments thereof, or agents that alter FGIF activity can be used to activate fetal globin expression.
      <br/>
      Increased amounts of fetal globin have been shown to alleviate or cure globin disorders including the sickle cell syndromes and the  BETA  thalassemia syndromes.
      <br/>
      FGIF amino acid sequences can also be used to maintain expression of therapeutic quantities of fetal globin for the treatment of various hemoglobinopathies.
      <br/>
      FGIF protein can also be administered to patients to reduce globin expression.
      <br/>
      In many patients, complications arise due to the accumulation of excess alpha chains.
      <br/>
      Administering agents that decrease FGIF activity and thereby decrease alpha chain expression may alleviate such disorders or at least ameliorate symptoms associated with such disorders.
    </p>
    <p num="35">
      Expression of therapeutically effective quantities of FGIF can be achieved, for example, in hematopoietic cells by in vivo or ex vivo modes to augment expression of the endogenous globin genes.
      <br/>
      FGIF can be administered by delivering therapeutically effective quantities of protein or agents that regulate FGIF expression or activity.
      <br/>
      A therapeutical effective quantity is that amount which has a beneficial effect to the patient by alleviating one or more symptoms of the disorder or simply reduce premature mortality.
      <br/>
      For example, a beneficial effect may be a decrease in pain, a decrease in duration, frequency or intensity of crises, an increased hematocrit, an improved erythropoiesis, a reduced or eliminated necessity for chelation therapy, an increased reticulocyte count, an increased peripheral blood flow, a decreased hemolysis, decreased fatigue or an increased strength.
      <br/>
      Preferably, a therapeutic amount is that amount of chemical compound or agent delivered to a patient that stimulates or enhances the expression of non-adult globin such as embryonic or fetal globin, or the proliferation of embryonic, fetal or adult globin expressing cells.
    </p>
    <p num="36">
      The patient may be a domesticated animal, but is preferably a human or another primate.
      <br/>
      Administration may be to an adult, an adolescent, a child, a toddler, a neonate or an infant, or administered in utero.
      <br/>
      Administration of compositions of the invention containing FGIF or agents that affect FGIF expression or activity may be short term, continuous or sporadic as necessary.
      <br/>
      Patients with a suspected or diagnosed with a blood disorder may only require composition treatment for short periods of time or until symptoms have abated or have been effectively eliminated.
      <br/>
      Compositions provided to the patient may include any combination of the proteins or agents of the invention in combination with other substances such as chemical compounds known to those of ordinary skill in the art as useful for the treatment of globin disorders.
    </p>
    <p num="37">
      Compositions of the invention can be directly or indirectly administered to the patient.
      <br/>
      Indirect administration is performed, for example, by administering the composition to cells ex vivo and subsequently introducing the treated cells to the patient.
      <br/>
      The cells may be obtained from the patient to be treated or from a genetically related or unrelated patient.
      <br/>
      Related patients offer some advantage by lowering the immunogenic response to the cells to be introduced.
      <br/>
      For example, using techniques of antigen matching, immunologically compatible donors can be identified and utilized.
    </p>
    <p num="38">
      Direct administration of a composition may be by oral, parenteral, sublingual, rectal such as suppository or enteral administration, or by pulmonary absorption or topical application.
      <br/>
      Parenteral administration may be by intravenous injection, subcutaneous injection, intramuscular injection, intra-arterial injection, intrathecal injection, intra peritoneal injection or direct injection or other administration to one or more specific sites.
      <br/>
      Injectable forms of administration are sometimes preferred for maximal effect in, for example, bone marrow.
      <br/>
      When long term administration by injection is necessary, venous access devices such as medi-ports, in-dwelling catheters, or automatic pumping mechanisms are also preferred wherein direct and immediate access is provided to the arteries in and around the heart and other major organs and organ systems.
    </p>
    <p num="39">
      Another effective method of administering the composition is by direct contact with, for example, bone marrow through an incision or some other artificial opening into the body.
      <br/>
      Compositions may also be administered to the nasal passages as a spray.
      <br/>
      Arteries of the nasal area provide a rapid and efficient access to the bloodstream and immediate access to the pulmonary system.
      <br/>
      Access to the gastrointestinal tract, which can also rapidly introduce substances to the blood stream, can be gained using oral, enema, suppository, or injectable forms of administration.
      <br/>
      Compositions may be administered as a bolus injection or spray as appropriate.
      <br/>
      Compositions may be given sequentially over time (episodically) such as every two, four, six or eight hours, every day (QD) or every other day (QOD), or over longer periods of time such as weeks to months.
      <br/>
      Compositions may also be administered in a timed-release fashion such as by using slow-release resins and other timed or delayed release materials and devices.
      <br/>
      Orally active compositions are more preferred as oral administration is usually the safest, most convenient and economical mode of drug delivery.
      <br/>
      However, direct injection may be preferred when immediate access to the blood system is desired.
    </p>
    <p num="40">
      Treatments to the patient may be therapeutic or prophylactic.
      <br/>
      Therapeutic treatment involves administration of one or more compositions of the invention to a patient suffering from one or more symptoms of the disorder.
      <br/>
      Symptoms typically associated with globin disorders include, for example, anemia, tissue hypoxia, organ dysfunction, abnormal hematocrit values, ineffective erythropoiesis, abnormal reticulocyte count, abnormal iron load, splenomegaly, hepatomegaly, impaired peripheral blood flow, dyspnea, increased hemolysis, jaundice, anemic crises and pain such as angina pectoris.
      <br/>
      Relief and even partial relief from one or more of these symptoms corresponds to an increased life span or simply an increased quality of life.
      <br/>
      Further, treatments that alleviate a pathological symptom can allow for other treatments to be administered.
    </p>
    <p num="41">
      Prophylactic treatments involve pulsed administration of a composition to a patient having a confirmed or suspected blood disorder without having any overt symptoms.
      <br/>
      For example, otherwise healthy patients who have been genetically screened and determined to be at high risk for the future development of a blood disorder may be administered compositions of the invention prophylactically.
      <br/>
      Administration can begin at birth and continue, if necessary, for life.
      <br/>
      Both prophylactic and therapeutic uses are readily acceptable because these compounds are generally safe and non-toxic.
    </p>
    <p num="42">
      Another embodiment of the invention is directed to a method for regulating the expression of a globin gene in a mammalian cell comprising exposing the cell to an effective amount of a composition of the invention.
      <br/>
      Upon exposure, a poorly expressed or quiescent globin gene of the cell is stimulated to increase the expression of its protein product.
      <br/>
      An effective amount of the composition is that amount which increases the extent or magnitude of hematopoiesis, increases the proliferation of hemoglobin expressing cells, increases, decreases or balances expression from one or more globin genes, or increases or stimulates the specific expression of one or more globin genes such as an alpha ( ALPHA ) globin gene, a zeta ( ZETA ) globin gene, an epsilon ( EPSILON ) globin gene, a beta ( BETA ) globin gene, a delta ( DELTA ) globin gene, a gamma (G- GAMMA or A- GAMMA ) globin gene, or an, at least, partly functional pseudo-globin gene.
      <br/>
      Cells can be treated in culture or in vivo.
      <br/>
      Cultures of treated cells will produce increased amounts of hemoglobin and preferably embryonic or fetal globin.
      <br/>
      This hemoglobin can be harvested for introduction to a patient or the stimulated cells themselves can be administered to the patient.
      <br/>
      Alternatively, recombinant cells containing a globin gene which can be stimulated by compositions of the invention can be utilized.
      <br/>
      These recombinant cells may be heterologous or homologous natural cells, or synthetically created cells such as a lipid vesicles.
    </p>
    <p num="43">
      Alternatively administration may comprise the administration of quantities of nucleic acids that encode FGIF.
      <br/>
      Such nucleic acids can be administered in vivo in vector systems capable of expressing FGIF.
      <br/>
      Many such systems are well known to those of ordinary skill in the art and include, for example, adenovirus and adeno-associated virus vectors, retroviral vectors, liposomes and direct injection of expressible nucleic acids into cells.
      <br/>
      Such methods and vectors are described in, for example, Wolff et al. (Science 247:1465-1468, 1990; Ali et al., Gene Therapy, 1:367-384, 1994; Walsh et al., Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A., 91:7257-7261, 1994; Miller, Nature, 357:455-460, 1992; Michael and Curiel, Gene Therapy, 1:223-232, 1994; Budker et al., Gene Therapy, 3:593-598, 1996; Kay et al., Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A., 91:2353-2357, 1994; Hengge et al., Nat. Genet., 10: 161-166, 1995; Mann et al., Cell, 33:153-159, 1983; Nicolau et al., Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A., 80:1068-1072, 1983; and U.S. Pat. No. 5,399,346).
      <br/>
      These vector systems and many others also well known in the art can be used to express FGIF in hematopoietic target cells to augment fetal globin expression.
    </p>
    <p num="44">
      The expression of FGIF provides advantages for the treatment of globin disorders such as hemoglobinopathies over current therapies involving globin gene expression.
      <br/>
      For example, conventional vectors carrying either human fetal ( GAMMA ) of human adult ( BETA ) globin genes for expression of therapeutic polypeptides.
      <br/>
      This approach requires a consistent production of high levels of globin mRNA in the target cell population which is difficult and often impractical to achieve with any degree of confidence.
      <br/>
      Expression of FGIF encoding nucleic acids overcomes these disadvantages as a relatively small numbers FGIF molecules transactivates expression of endogenous fetal globin genes.
    </p>
    <p num="45">
      Another embodiment of the invention is directed to methods of screening for agents that modulate FGIF function.
      <br/>
      Methods consist of contacting FGIF with a sample containing an agent to be tested and determining whether the agent enhances or inhibits the transactivation function of FGIF.
      <br/>
      Transactivation can be measured by determining the change in expression levels of fetal globin.
      <br/>
      Agents that enhance FGIF function can be used to treat hemoglobinopathies and  BETA  thalassemia syndromes.
    </p>
    <p num="46">
      Methods for screening can be performed using a variety of methods known in the art.
      <br/>
      Such assays include, for example, the use stable or transient expression or in vivo, expression assays.
      <br/>
      Other assays known in the art, including in vitro screening procedures are similarly applicable for identifying modulators of FGIF.
      <br/>
      Any or all of such assays can be automated or modified for high throughput procedures.
      <br/>
      Agents to be screened for presence of inducers of fetal globin gene expression include, for example, libraries of chemicals, pharmaceutical products or naturally existing substances.
    </p>
    <p num="47">
      Another embodiment of the invention is directed to agents identified by the above methods which induce globin gene expression and preferably fetal globin expression.
      <br/>
      Induction can be by either direct or indirect modes of action.
      <br/>
      Agents that directly induce fetal globin expression are agents that increase fetal globin transcription.
      <br/>
      Agents that indirectly induce expression are agents that regulate FGIF activity which thereby increases fetal hemoglobin expression.
      <br/>
      Agents that indirectly affect FGIF activity include butyric acid and butyric acid compounds.
    </p>
    <p num="48">The following examples illustrate embodiments of the invention, but should not be viewed as limiting the scope of the invention.</p>
    <heading>EXAMPLES</heading>
    <p num="49">
      Hybrids formed by fusing human fetal erythroblasts (HFE) with mouse erythroleukemia (MEL) cells initially produce human  GAMMA -globin and subsequently switch to  BETA -globin expression.
      <br/>
      Gamma ( GAMMA ) gene expression in these hybrids can be explained by presence of fetal erythroid-origin trans acting factors that activate  GAMMA  globin gene transcription.
      <br/>
      Factors present in fetal erythroid cells were cloned using differential mRNA display.
      <br/>
      With this method, mRNA species can be distinguished by the size of amplified cDNA fragments.
      <br/>
      By comparing cDNA species amplified from mRNA of  GAMMA -hybrids,  BETA -hybrids, human fetal liver erythroblasts and adult erythroblasts, cDNAs present only in  GAMMA -hybrids and fetal liver erythroblasts and to functionally recognize those inducing  GAMMA  gene transcription using transactivation assays were identified.
    </p>
    <p num="50">
      RNA was prepared from a single hybrid when it was at the stage of exclusive  GAMMA -globin expression or exclusively  BETA -globin expression. mRNA was amplified using 5'-arbitrary primers and 3'-T12VN primers.
      <br/>
      Fifty pairs of cDNA fragments which were present both in human fetal liver erythroblasts and in the  GAMMA -hybrid, but absent in human adult erythroblasts and the  BETA -hybrid, were cloned and sequenced.
      <br/>
      The sequences of 48 pairs differed between the fetal liver erythroblasts and the  GAMMA -hybrid, in spite of the identical sizes of amplified products.
      <br/>
      Two pairs had identical sequences in the fetal liver erythroblasts and the  GAMMA -hybrid.
      <br/>
      The mRNA of one of these pairs codes for human proteasome subunit X. The sequence of the second pair, designated as FL/H6, belongs to a previously unidentified human gene.
      <br/>
      Northern Blots using FL/H6 as a probe revealed two hybridization signals in human fetal liver cells, but only one in human adult bone marrow cells or MEL cells.
      <br/>
      A second hybridization signal with higher molecular weight was also found in a  ALPHA -ABA-treated  GAMMA -hybrid, where the switching from human  GAMMA  to  BETA  globin was strikingly delayed.
      <br/>
      Full-length cDNA (FGIF) of FL/H6 was cloned from a human fetal liver cDNA library as well as the  ALPHA -ABA-treated  GAMMA -hybrids cDNA library.
    </p>
    <p num="51">
      The two cDNAs have over 80% homology at the nucleic acids level and over 85% homology in predicted open reading frame.
      <br/>
      In view of this data, FGIF sequences from other mammalian sources is expected to have corresponding degrees of homology.
      <br/>
      Protein translated from the cDNAs has three ankyrin motifs and limited homology with transcriptional factor Notch.
      <br/>
      The nucleotide sequences of FGIF is shown in FIGS. 1 and 2, and the amino acid sequence, in FIG. 3.
    </p>
    <p num="52">
      Transcriptional activation activity of FGIF was determined using a yeast transactivation assay.
      <br/>
      Briefly, yeast stably integrated with the LacZ reporter gene controlled by yeast Ga14 UAS and minimal promoter was transformed with either a control construct containing only the Ga14 DNA binding domain (pBD) or a construct containing a fusion of FGIF with a Ga14 DNA binding domain.
      <br/>
      Following transformation, and an initial expression period, transcriptional activation activity of FGIF was determined by measuring activation of the LacZ reporter gene.
      <br/>
      LacZ activities were determined in lysates of yeast colonies transformed with either pBD or pBD-FGIF.
      <br/>
      Relative luminescent units (RLU) were expressed per microgram of protein.
    </p>
    <p num="53">
      A total of six pairs of control and pBD-FGIF transformed yeast colonies were examined.
      <br/>
      Relative luminescent units of these colonies is shown in FIG. 4.
      <br/>
      In all cases, significant transcription of between about 14-30 fold in the LacZ reporter gene was observed in the pBD-FGIF expressing colonies compared to controls.
      <br/>
      These results indicate that FGIF is a transcriptional transactivator.
    </p>
    <p num="54">
      Additional functional studies were performed to assess the induction of human  GAMMA  globin gene expression by FGIF.
      <br/>
      Briefly, somatic cell hybrids which contained human chromosome 11 (the chromosome on which the human  BETA  globin locus resides) and which displayed low level of human fetal globin gene expression (about 5% of total human globin were  GAMMA ), were stably transfected with an FGIF expression construct.
      <br/>
      Hybrids comprised human fetal erythroid * MEL cell hybrids.
      <br/>
      The FGIF construct, termed  MU LCR- BETA -FGIF-pA-SV40p-Neo-pA, was comprised of:  MU LCR which corresponds to a 2.5 kb cassette of the  BETA  globin locus control region;  BETA  which corresponds to the  BETA  globin gene promoter; pA which corresponds to a polyadenylation site, and Neo which corresponds to a neomycin resistance gene that confers resistance to the mammalian selectable agent G418.
      <br/>
      The  MU LCR- BETA  promoter was used to allow erythroid lineage specific expression of FGIF.
    </p>
    <p num="55">
      Stably transfected hybrids were selected with G418 and induced with hemin and HMBA.
      <br/>
      FGIF dependent expression of fetal globin was determined by RNASE protection assay.
      <br/>
      The results of these studies are shown in FIG. 5 and are expressed as the ratio of  GAMMA  globin to  GAMMA + BETA  globin expression.
      <br/>
      Hybrids expressing induced FGIF resulted in an about 8-fold higher  GAMMA / GAMMA + BETA  ratio than untransfected hybrids.
      <br/>
      Studies using anti- GAMMA  globin chain antibodies showed similar increase in  GAMMA  globin positive cells indicating that the  GAMMA  globin was also increased.
      <br/>
      These results indicate that FGIF functions in vivo as an inducer of  UPSILON  globin.
      <br/>
      Untransfected hybrids were used as the control.
    </p>
    <p num="56">
      Other embodiments and uses of the invention will be apparent to those skilled in the art from consideration of the specification and practice of the invention disclosed herein.
      <br/>
      All U.S. patents and patent applications, including provisional application Ser.
      <br/>
      No. 60/033,247, entitled Fetal Globin Inducing Factor filed Dec. 5, 1996, and all other documents referenced herein, for whatever reason, are specifically incorporated by reference.
      <br/>
      It is intended that the specification and examples be considered exemplary only, with the true scope and spirit of the invention indicated by the following claims.
    </p>
  </description>
  <claims format="original" lang="en" id="claim_en">
    <claim num="1">
      <claim-text>What is claimed is:</claim-text>
      <claim-text>1.</claim-text>
      <claim-text>An isolated amino acid sequence or an active fragment of said sequence that functions to regulate expression of a globin gene wherein said sequence comprises SEQ ID NO:3 or SEQ ID NO:3 with one or more conservative amino acid substitutions.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="2">
      <claim-text>2. The amino acid sequence of claim 1 which is a human sequence.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="3">
      <claim-text>3. A composition comprising the amino acid sequence of claim 1 and a carrier.</claim-text>
    </claim>
    <claim num="4">
      <claim-text>4. The composition of claim 3 wherein the carrier is selected from the group consisting of water, oils, alcohols, salts, fatty acids, saccharides, polysaccharides and combinations thereof.</claim-text>
    </claim>
  </claims>
</questel-patent-document>